<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition.atom"/>
  <title>Neuherbs - Diet Nutrition</title>
  <updated>2022-02-25T16:39:09+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Neuherbs</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/love-oats-and-oatmeal-9-benefits-they-are-providing-your-body</id>
    <published>2022-02-25T16:39:09+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-03-21T15:43:30+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/love-oats-and-oatmeal-9-benefits-they-are-providing-your-body"/>
    <title>Love Oats and Oatmeal? 9 Benefits They Are Providing Your Body</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to the perfect breakfast, there is one grain that everyone loves. And that grain is oats. <span style="color: #167860;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/omega-steel-cut-oats" style="color: #167860;"><strong>Omega steel-cut oats</strong></a></span> are a perfect nutritious grain that can help you make tons of dishes, and one of the most popular ones is oatmeal. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Oatmeal is a comforting breakfast option, full of fiber, protein, and other nutrients. It is fulfilling, and the best part is that you don’t have to limit oatmeal to breakfast. There are tons of benefits of eating oatmeal at night or as a midday snack. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A tip here is to use omega steel cut oats to prepare your oatmeal instead of buying the packaged one. The packaged oatmeal has nothing but sugar and salt.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other meals that you can make using omega instant oats include-oats cookies, oats flour which you can use to make chapati by mixing it with other grains.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">But why should you? What benefits of eating oatmeal at night or oats give you? Thus, in this blog, we will discuss its benefits.</span></p>
<h2><strong>10 Benefits of oats and oatmeal</strong></h2>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>1. Oats are naturally gluten-free</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Oats are gluten-free grains. Thus, for people allergic to gluten or avoid gluten-comprising food, this is a perfect grain. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The only thing to remember here is to buy oats that have gluten-free written on them. It is because the processing procedure with other grains is processed may taint them.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>2. Oats and oatmeal can help ease constipation</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Oats are rich in fiber and beta-glucan, which helps your digestive system. There is research showing that oats can increase gut microbiota diversity. Thus, it can help you provide relief from IBS, diarrhoea, and constipation.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, it can help ease acute constipation as it is rich in fiber which can make you pass stool easily as it adds bulk and water to stools.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>3. Oats ease sleep issues</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The benefit of eating oatmeal at night is better to sleep. If you cannot sleep and are a bit hungry, try oatmeal. A simple oatmeal dish can increase the production of tryptophan in your body. It happens due to the melatonin and complex carbs that oats have. It helps induce better sleep.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It also has vitamin B6, which can increase the production of serotonin in your body, which again can help you sleep. So, the benefits of eating oatmeal at night are there, and you should try having oats at dinner.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>4. Oats can help you lose weight</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">We know oats have fiber and a bit of protein. However, <span style="color: #168066;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/rolled-oats" style="color: #168066;"><strong>omega-3 rolled oats</strong></a></span> have another compound, known as glucan. This compound helps decrease the desire to eat by increasing the function of the hunger-fighting hormone-cholecystokinin. Thus, it helps you feel full, and you do not end up snacking, which helps keep your calories in check.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>5. Oats and oatmeal can improve insulin levels</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you suffer from type-2 diabetes, including oatmeal and oats in your diet can help regulate insulin level. High blood sugar levels are the reason why people get diabetes. Oats have compounds that can help reduce or balance your insulin levels. If you are overweight and have diabetes, oats should be part of your diet.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">They can also help you lose weight and have a better digestion system, necessary for regulating diabetes.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>6. Oats is good for skin</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you want to use oats tropically, you should because it can treat dry skin and inflammation. Some creams and lotions have oats in them, as their starch can help dry skin. If you want to treat dry, acne-prone, and itchy skin, try an oats mask, which you can prepare at home. It is soothing, and there are no side effects.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Note: Always do a patch test to ensure you do not end up aggravating your skin issues, as some products might not suit your skin.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>7. Oats are good for babies</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Babies are fussy eaters, and their digestion system is still developing. Thus, the benefits of oatmeal at night for babies are many. It is light and mushy, so they can eat it with ease. Also, it promotes good gut health and eases constipation. You can make them oats cookies or oats pancakes if they refuse to eat oatmeal.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>8. Oats and oatmeal can improve your immune system</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our immune system is what keeps us healthy and infections at bay. Oats have beta-glucan and soluble fiber. Both of these help WBCs thrive and fight off infections in our bodies.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Oats and oatmeal are also rich in zinc &amp; selenium, which again helps fight infection. There is research stating that oats’ compound beta-glucan can help antibiotics work better in our body, healing wounds fast. Thus, it is advisable to include <span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/omega-instant-oats" style="color: #167a62;"><strong>omega-instant oats</strong></a></span> in your diet somehow,</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>9. Oats help boost heart health</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your heart is a vital organ, and you need to work on keeping it healthy. Eating oatmeal is one way you can do this, as it can reduce the amount of LDL in our body, which is necessary for keeping the heart-healthy.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Toppings for oatmeal to make it more delicious</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Oatmeal is nutritious. However, it is bland as oats and water does not provide much taste. So, what can you add to your oatmeal to make it delicious without compromising its taste? Let's see”</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Milk</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are making oatmeal in water, try adding a bit of milk to your bowl. It can dairy or non-dairy as per your choice.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Fruits, nuts, and seeds</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can add slices of fresh fruits, nuts, and seeds to your bowl of oatmeal. It adds more nutrients to your oatmeal and makes it delicious.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Veggies</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Savoury oats are incredible too. Add cut vegetables and spices to your oatmeal and enjoy.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Oats are a holy grail when it comes to grain. It is versatile and naturally gluten-free. Try switching your other grain with oats and reap all the benefits it provides. Also, oatmeal is one of the best breakfast meals or evening snacks. Also, it can be a great dinner if you are looking to eat something light yet fulfilling. If you're to love oats and oatmeal, tell us in the comments some of your favourite recipes.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/are-your-kids-hungry-11-snacks-ideas-which-are-healthy-and-delicious</id>
    <published>2022-02-25T16:12:11+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-03-21T16:13:46+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/are-your-kids-hungry-11-snacks-ideas-which-are-healthy-and-delicious"/>
    <title>Are Your Kids Hungry? 11 Snacks Ideas Which Are Healthy and Delicious</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Have you noticed that when kids stay at home, they are hungry every 10 minutes? Sometimes they genuinely crave food, and other times, they are bored and confuse it with hunger. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In any case, kids should eat something every few hours to help their developing body and brain. The only problem that most parents face with their kids is that often their kids eat snacks that are unhealthy or not nutritious enough. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes it is okay to let them have a treat. However, as a parent, we will like it if our kids have healthy snacks in the evening. Isn’t it?</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How do you go about it? By encouraging them slowly to eat or try a portion of new food. Mixing and matching their favorite food with a healthy item, like baking muffins and sprinkling <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/protein-mix"><span style="color: #167a62;"><strong>protein mix seeds</strong></span></a> on it. If you are looking for such quirky ideas, we have a list of healthy snacks for evening or mid-morning snacks, which your kids will love.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Smoothies with a dash of antioxidant mix</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kids can be prickly when it comes to fruits. However, try making them smoothies, and they will love it and ask you for more. Also, smoothies are better and healthier than milkshakes, which every kid loves. All you have to do is blend some fruits with yogurt or water and serve them. Also, sprinkle some <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/antioxidant-mix"><span style="color: #167a62;"><strong>antioxidant mix seeds</strong></span></a> on top of the smoothie to make it more nourishing and fulfilling.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Yogurt with a hint of honey and superfood mix</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yogurt has many qualities. It is a healthy treat with tons of protein, calcium, and live bacteria, helping boost the digestive system. It makes for a perfect healthy snack for evenings or mid-morning. Just remember to buy plain yogurt, as kids-yogurt available in the market are full of added sugar. Instead of buying that, get plain yogurt and add fruits or drizzle honey to make it sweet and nourishing. Also, you can add more nutrients to it by adding a spoonful of <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/super-food-mix"><span style="color: #167a62;"><strong>superfood mix seeds</strong></span></a>. It contains multiple seeds, berries, and nuts which makes the snack fulfilling.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Popcorn with a bit of salt</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Which kid doesn’t love popcorn? And fortunately, it is a whole grain full of nutrition and goodness. Yes, the ones we get at the theatre aren’t healthy as they are full of toppings that take away the nutritional value. However, if you make popcorn at home and only add a bit of salt to it, popcorn is an incredible snack for kids.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Snack tray of veggies and dip</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Want your kids to have veggies as a healthy snack for the evening? Then try veggies and dip. Cut up some carrot, celery, cucumber, and bell peppers. Set up a tray and place these vegetables on them and serve it a dip of your choice. Also, when you go to the market, take help from the kids to buy the veggies or help them grow them at home. This way, they will be more interested in eating veggies.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Home-made Popsicles</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kids love their Popsicles, and you can make them home to ensure they are nutritious and healthy. How? There are many ways to make them, which makes for a perfect healthy snack for the evening or as a dessert. Try this:</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Get some Popsicle maker and fill it with 100% real juice of a fruit. Add a stick and freeze it.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Get some plain yogurt, make it thin and add fresh fruits slices. Fill the Popsicle maker with this blend. Freeze it and enjoy a healthy treat.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Protein mix</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If your kids like nuts, protein mix is a great snack for them. It has nuts, whole grain, and other things full of protein. It is fun to eat, and your kids get a good amount of protein, which is good for their developing bodies.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Cottage cheese with whole toast</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cottage cheese is a soft cheese that you can eat in multiple ways. It is full of protein and vitamin B-12. Your kids can eat them by shallow frying them with some salt or pepper. Or you can make a whole wheat toast using cottage cheese.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Frozen banana chocolate bites</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kids love to eat dessert, and you should not deprive them of the same. Be smart and make a healthy dessert like frozen banana chocolate bites. All you need is some bananas. Now, cut them into slices and freeze them overnight.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a bowl, mix some natural peanut butter with cacao powder and vanilla essence. Microwave it to make a paste. Now, dip half part of the frozen banana using a fork into this paste. Freeze it again overnight, and your delicious dessert is ready.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Boiled eggs</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eggs are a perfect breakfast, but they also make for a healthy snack for the evening. Just boil one egg and give it to your kid when they scream bloody murder because they are hungry. Cut them into slices and sprinkle some salt &amp; pepper.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Oats and banana cookies</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Banana is so versatile that you can use it to make tons of desserts that are healthy and perfect for kids. When you use bananas, you don’t even need sugar, which is not great for kids. All you need is some banana, rolled oats, coconut oil vanilla essence, and choco chips. Mix them well and spread them on a baking tray, and your healthy cookies are ready.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Baked chips with salt and pepper</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kids love chips, and as parents, we do not want our kids to eat something full of fat and salt. The alternative? Kale and sweet potato baked chips. Sprinkle some salt and pepper, and this healthy snack for the evening will blow your kids away.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every kid is different. However, all kids are picky-eater. Also, if you encourage a kid to eat something telling them it is healthy, like broccoli, they might not eat it ever. Thus, you have to get creative to ensure they have healthy snacks in the evening, or anytime they feel hungry. Furthermore, let your kids eat every few hours, they need the fuel for activities as their bodies are developing every second.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/best-post-workout-diet-meal-ideas</id>
    <published>2022-02-05T18:14:02+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-02-05T18:14:03+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/best-post-workout-diet-meal-ideas"/>
    <title>10 Best Post-workout Diet Meal Ideas</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">2022 is finally here, and we all want this year to be incredible, healthy, and happy for us. One of the ways we can be healthy and happy is to get regular exercise. Surely, many of us have decided to start working out in the new year. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">But before you start a routine, there is something else related to the workout that you need to consider. And that is a post-workout diet. Yes, your workout routine does not end with that last lap at the gym. It includes workout nutrition too. When it comes to pre-workout meals, people know what to eat and avoid. However, when it comes to a post-workout diet, people either do not pay much attention to it or don't have enough idea about it.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yet, knowing the best post-workout meal for muscle gain is essential. Why? Let us explain it to you.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>What happens when we work out…</strong></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you exercise, the muscles use all the glycogen. It is the fuel resource that our body uses during workouts. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It burns up, especially high when we do HIIT. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thus, your muscles run on a partial amount of glycogen, and even some proteins break down during </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once your last-lap finishes, the body works on rebuilding the glycogen levels and repairing/regrowing the muscle's protein. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are not eating the right food, your body will not get the correct nutrients. Thus, it will not help your body heal after a workout.</span></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thus, eating the best post-workout diet is necessary for:</span></p>
<ol style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Muscle gain</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fat loss</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Body &amp; muscle repair</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Muscle regrowth</span></li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The right food is always a combination of protein, fat, and carbs. Now, we know why post-workout nutrition is imperative for our bodies. Let us learn about the best post-workout meal for muscle gain.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>10. Best post-workout meals for muscle gain</strong></h2>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>1. Fish</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fish are rich in protein, omega-3 fatty acids, and other healthy fats. Also, they have carbs, which are an essential part of the post-workout diet. They can provide your body with a balanced meal that your body craves after an intense workout. Fishes like tuna or salmon are rich in <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/deep-sea-fish-oil"><strong>omega 3 fish oil capsules</strong></a>, which your body does not make but is necessary for heart health. Thus, a post-workout diet containing fish is an ideal choice. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you do not eat fish, try adding fish oil to your post-workout diet to get a healthy dose of omega-3 fatty acids.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>2. Egg or paneer scramble</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">An egg is rich in protein, carbs, and other minerals. It is the perfect post-workout diet and an ideal breakfast. It is also easy to make as it is a one-pot dish. Furthermore, add several vegetables to it to make it more fulfilling and nutritious. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you don't eat eggs, try paneer (cottage cheese) or tofu scramble with tons of vegetables to get post-workout nutrition. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>3. Peanut butter sandwich</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another best post-workout meal for muscle gain is a <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/collections/peanut-butter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>peanut butter</strong></a> sandwich. Two tablespoons of peanut butter contain 8 grams of protein. Also, it has fiber, carbs, and healthy fats, which will help you lose fat and build muscle. Ditch the sugary jams and get a bottle of natural-unsweetened peanut butter. It is delicious and full of energy. To make it richer in protein, add greek yogurt to your meal.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>4. Quinoa</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If your post-workout diet is lunch, try replacing your white rice with <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/quinoa-seeds" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>quinoa</strong></a>. They pack in a healthy amount of carbs, fiber, and protein. It will help you lose weight and build muscles while helping your body repair itself after an intense workout.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Quinoa with chicken or lentils or a vegetable quinoa scramble works as perfect post-workout nutrition.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>5. Rice with chicken breast</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the best post-workout meals for muscle gain is boneless chicken breast with rice. It can be brown rice, white rice, or even quinoa. That is up to you. Use spices and herbs to make it delicious, but on the lighter side and enjoy an appetizing dish that will fuel your body.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>6. Smoothies</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The best post-workout diet is smoothies. Whether it is lunchtime or breakfast, smoothies can give you immediate energy and give your body some fuel as you work on making a fulfilling lunch meal. Make sure your smoothie has enough protein and nutrients. Add greek yogurt, some fresh fruits, oats, protein powder, peanut butter, or any other nut butter to make it fulfilling. You can also have a veggie smoothie. Do not forget to sprinkle some seed mix into it for more crunchy and nutritious.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>7. Avocado toast</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Avocado is rich in healthy fats, which many people do not get from other sources of food. Thus, it can be a great meal with all the post-workout nutrition your body needs. Get some whole wheat bread and toast it. Now, add avocado, onion, tomato, tuna for protein and enjoy this delicious toast. Also, do not forget your true vitamin supplement to give your body that extra dose of vitamins it needs.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>8. Protein shake</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Want to just grab a snack after your workout? Then a protein shake is perfect for you. You can make a peanut butter shake or get a dietitian recommended protein shake and use it to make a powerful shake that can keep you going for a while or till you make something substantial to eat.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>9. Wraps</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wraps are a protein and fiber-rich meal that you can consume post-workout. Make a whole-grain wrap and use green veggies, some fish or sliced boiled egg for protein, and avocado for fat. Use some delicious dip and enjoy this nutritional and delicious dish.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>10. Oatmeal</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Oatmeal is also a great post-workout diet. Make it rich in protein by adding nut butter and some <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/healthy-seeds-mix" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>seed mix</strong></a>.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wrapping up, focusing on your post-workout diet is highly necessary. The timing also matters, and you should wait up to an hour after exercise training to eat. However, that can vary according to the type of workout you do. Thus, focussing on the best post-workout meals for muscle gain is essential and hydrating yourself. Drinking enough water is as necessary as eating the correct nutrients.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/try-these-12-delicious-snacks-under-100-calories-now</id>
    <published>2022-01-11T15:30:41+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-03-21T16:51:51+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/try-these-12-delicious-snacks-under-100-calories-now"/>
    <title>Try These 12 Delicious Snacks Under 100 Calories Now</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No matter how much we try, feeling hungry at night or between meals is imperative. Who amongst you wakes up at 2 am and has a snack? Most of us are guilty of doing this at least once in our life. Aren't we?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The only problem with this is picking up unhealthy food when snacking. Everyone craves something tasty, but such items are usually junk or high in calories. Finding <span style="color: #167a62;"><a title="guilt-free healthy snacks" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/looking-for-energy-boosting-snacks-for-work-try-these-8-healthy-munchies" style="color: #167a62;"><strong>guilt-free healthy snacks</strong></a></span> under 100 calories isn’t easy, but not impossible. There are tons of guilt-free snacks under 100 calories, which are even full of flavours. If you are looking for such guilt-free snacks to binge on between meals.</span></p>
<h2><strong> Here are 12 guilt-free healthy snacks you should try.</strong></h2>
<h3><strong>1. Popcorns- quick &amp; healthy</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Who does not like to gauge on popcorns while the opening credits are rolling on in theatres? Though the popcorns you get in theatres are high in calories and sodium, the ones you make at home are under 100 calories. They are a guilt-free snack when you air-pop them at home and use only little seasoning. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These are great for midnight snacking as they are whole-grain and full of fiber. So, the next time you want to snack mindfully, make some delicious &amp; simple popcorn at home.</span></p>
<h3><strong>2. Greek yogurt or curd (½ cup)- For yummy prebiotic fill</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Homemade Dahi or curd is another healthy guilt-free snack option for everyone to try out. You can also eat a half cup of non-fat Greek yogurt. Both have about 59 calories (half cup)!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It makes for a yummy, fulfilling, and healthy snack. Also, it is full of proteins, prebiotics, and calcium. So it is fulfilling and good for the gut &amp; bones. Try adding 2-3 pieces of strawberries and 1 tbsp of sunflower seeds. It will still be under 100 calories, but the nutrient value will increase ten times.</span></p>
<h3><strong>3. Boiled egg-To load up on protein</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One boiled egg roughly has 40-50 calories. Thus, it is a guilt-free healthy snack that you can eat between meals to keep yourself full. It is high in fiber and protein, so you will not crave anything else for a while.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sprinkling some salt or pepper on it is the perfect way to eat this yummy and fulfilling snack.</span></p>
<h3><strong>4. 10-12 pieces of almonds-Healthiest snack</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Almonds are a great snack if looking for guilt-free snacks for weight loss. When you are feeling peckish, try eating 10-12 pieces of almonds, and you will free great. It has many nutrients which will keep you full for some time. You can even slightly roast them and add salt &amp; pepper.</span></p>
<h3><strong>5. Grapes-for sweet cravings</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Want to snack on something sweet? Then try grapes. They are a guilt-free healthy snack under 100 calories, which also extinguish your cravings for something sweet. They are rich in fiber, so you will not crave anything for a while. Grapes are also rich in antioxidants and make for a quick and healthy snack.</span></p>
<h3><strong>6. Vegetable toast-for a crunchy delight</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Craving for something spicy and low in calories? Then get one piece of your favorite bread. Toast it and lightly spread homemade dip. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Add some cucumber or tomatoes or onions, or all three. Sprinkle some spices like pepper, chat masala, and salt. Enjoy this delicious guilt-free snack with about 99-98 calories.</span></p>
<h3><strong>7. Oranges-delicious fruit to your rescue</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another guilt-free healthy snack under 100 calories is an orange. You can even enjoy two oranges because it is low in calories and high in nutrients. It is also a rich source of vitamin C. Thus, enjoying them gives you protection against cold and flu.</span></p>
<h3><strong>8. 1 cup of corn chaat- a perfect savory snack</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another savory snack to enjoy anytime is a corn chaat. Get a cup of sweet or normal corn. Boil the corns, add lots of vegetables and spices, and squeeze in a lemon. It is so crispy to eat, and you can even roast corn in 1 tsp of ghee or olive oil. All this has around 90 calories, so you can enjoy them without feeling guilty.</span></p>
<h3><strong>9. Simple oatmeal-fulfilling and nutrient-dense</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Want to eat something more fulfilling than fruit? Then try oatmeal. Just do not make the fancy one if you want to have a guilt-free snack under 100 calories. In a pan, add water, ½ cup oats, and some cinnamon or vanilla extract for flavor. You can cut up a ¼ banana in it for sweetness and creamy texture. Do add 1 tbsp of pumpkin seeds on top and enjoy. All this for around 80-85 calories.</span></p>
<h3><strong>10. Almond latte-for the caffeine fix</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes our hunger pangs are all about coffee. We want to drink a good cup of latte or cappuccino, but the usual ones with whole-fat milk and sugar are above 100 calories. But no worries! We have the perfect solution. Try almond milk latte or soy-mil latte without sugar or only add 1 tsp of sugar in it. Or you can have stevia in your vegan coffee. It tastes delicious, and the calories do not cross the mark of 100. </span></p>
<h3><strong>11. Roasted chickpeas-for a chatpata taste</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chickpeas are something that Indians make a lot. However, they can be a delicious option for a guilt-free healthy snack under 100 calories. All you have to do is roast some chickpeas in the oven. Add spices to your liking and store in an air-tight container. When you feel like snacking, go and grab a handful and enjoy with a cup of warm espresso.</span></p>
<h3><strong>12. Khakra- simple and light</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A whole-wheat chakra has around 40-50 calories, depending on the brand. It also comes in multiple flavors, so you can enjoy them without feeling any guilt.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Try these guilt-free snacks for weight loss or for snacking without regret. They are full of taste, and with so few calories, they do not affect your overall calorie intake. Picking the right snacks is better than not eating and overeating during meals. So, pick these guilt-free snacks and stay fit.</span></p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/10-fiber-rich-foods-include-in-your-diet</id>
    <published>2022-01-10T18:26:52+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-03-21T17:23:39+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/10-fiber-rich-foods-include-in-your-diet"/>
    <title>10 Fiber Rich Foods to Include in Your Diet</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every nutritionist, doctor, and even the internet these days will tell you to include foods rich in fiber in your diet. Why is everyone insisting on increasing your fiber intake? Is it imperative for your body? The short answer-yes!</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fiber is an essential nutrient, keeping our digestive system healthy. It helps you have regular bowel movements and softer stools. That can help keep inflammation &amp; diabetes at bay. Fiber can also help you achieve your weight loss goals, as our body takes time to digest dietary fiber. Thus, it keeps you full for a long time. Fiber-rich foods for constipation or diarrhea can help resolve these issues. (If there are no underlying issues). That is why it is so essential to have fiber-rich foods every day.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, what are fiber-rich foods that you should include in your diet? And what types of fiber are there? Let's read about these two things below.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Fiber and its type</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fiber is a complex carb that is indigestible, thus making it imperative for our body. It is of two types:</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Soluble fiber: It is a fiber that dissolves in water and creates a gel-like substance. That helps lower blood sugar and cholesterol levels in your body. Chia seeds are a rich source of soluble fiber.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Insoluble fiber: It passes through your body undigested, which helps create bulk, adding to stool. It makes your bowel movement softer and more regular. Wholegrain foods are rich in insoluble fibers, like wheat pasta or bread or ragi pasta and more.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>10 Fiber Rich Foods include in your daily diet</strong></h3>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>1. Pears</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a medium-sized pear, you get 5.5 grams of fiber. Including this in your diet does increase your intake of fiber, and since it is a relatively sweet and nutritious fruit, most people enjoy it. It’s best to eat it raw. However, if you don’t like it that way, try taking it with oatmeal or yogurt.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do not mix it with refined flour, as that defeats the purpose of including pears- a fiber-rich food in your diet. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>2. Chia seeds</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/chia-seeds" style="color: #167a62;"><strong>Chia seeds</strong></a></span> are tiny black seeds that are full of nutrients. When you start including natural chia seeds in your diet, it can make a massive difference. One of the readily available fiber-rich foods in India, chia seeds have 34.4 grams/100 grams of fiber in them. Also, chia seeds are a rich source of calcium, protein, &amp; antioxidants.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are many ways to include chia seeds in your diet:</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Add them to water and drink</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use them to make laddu</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Make chia seeds pudding or use them to make protein bars at home</span></li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>3. Broccoli</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Broccoli is a great vegetable to add to your diet. It is a cruciferous vegetable, which serves around 5 grams of fiber in one cup. The fiber in it is good and helps the healthy gut bacteria thrive. It is also a versatile vegetable that you can, either, eat after boiling with pepper &amp; salt. Or cook with other dishes like pasta or vegetable spread.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>4. Flax seeds</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/flax-seeds" style="color: #167a62;"><strong>Flax seeds</strong></a></span> are an old-school remedy that people use in India. For years, many people take flax seeds either whole or ground with lukewarm water early in the morning. It is not only a fiber-rich food in India, but also has other properties like keeping your skin healthy and glowing.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 100 grams of flax seeds, you get 27 grams of fiber. That means daily, eating one tbsp of ground flax seeds gives you 1.9 grams of fiber. That is a good number, and you should eat it daily, either with water. Or by adding it to your oatmeal, smoothie, or making laddus out of it. However, don’t consume more than 1 tbsp a day as it is hot for the digestive system.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>5. Dark chocolate</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dark chocolate is full of nutrients, and it does have 3.1 grams of fiber per one bar. The important thing here is to find <span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/dark-chocolate-peanut-butter" style="color: #167a62;"><strong>dark chocolate peanut butter</strong></a></span> that has less sugar. Also, the amount of cacao should be between 75% to 95%.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>6. Oats</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the healthiest foods rich in fiber is oats. It has 10.1 grams of fiber per cup. It is a grain that you cook in multiple ways, providing you with essential nutrients, minerals, and antioxidants. The beta-glucan (fiber) in it helps lower blood pressure levels too. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Make sure you buy natural rolled or instant oats and not processed ones. Oatmeal with fruits or overnight oats or making oats pancakes is a great way to include this grain in your diet.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>7. Black beans</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">All beans are super-rich in fiber. Beans are the best fiber-rich for constipation, and you should include them in your meals. Make tacos or use cooked beans in your salad to get 8.3 grams of fiber per half-cup. They are also rich in protein, making them great for weight loss and building muscles.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>8. Raspberries</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Who doesn’t love raspberries? They are a great addition to your morning smoothie or oatmeal bowl. Another reason to include them in your diet is due to their high content of fiber. It has 8 grams of fiber in one cup, which will undoubtedly help you reach your daily intake of fiber.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>9. Chickpeas</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chickpea is a legume, and like most legumes, it is a food rich in fiber. It has around 7 grams of fiber per 100 grams. If you eat it cooked, per cup has 12.5 grams of fiber. It also has protein and other nutrients which keep you full. You can make hummus using chickpea or make a chickpea salad. It is also a great snack where you can roast it in the oven, mix spices to it, and enjoy in-between meals.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>10. Lentils</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">All lentils are high in protein and fiber. When eating fiber-rich foods in India, people rely on lentils. If you cook them, you get 13 grams of fiber per cup.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Research says that every day, women need 24 grams of fiber and men 38 grams. However, studies show that most people eat only 16-18 grams of fiber. That is not sufficient for having a healthy gut. Modern diet culture and stress also do not help this situation. Thus, include foods rich in fiber in your diet as it is a natural way to eat more fiber. Fiber-rich foods for weight loss or constipation can be the remedy you were looking for all this time.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/looking-for-energy-boosting-snacks-for-work-try-these-8-healthy-munchies</id>
    <published>2022-01-07T16:27:58+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-01-07T16:36:49+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/looking-for-energy-boosting-snacks-for-work-try-these-8-healthy-munchies"/>
    <title>Looking for Energy Boosting Snacks for Work? Try These 8 Healthy Munchies.</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>It's 4 pm, and you are halfway through your work or daily chores. You are feeling pretty good about yourself. You ate a healthy lunch, your work is going smoothly, and you did a few exercises. But as you continue to work, you feel lethargic. Your energy levels are dripping, and you want to have a nap or slouch on your couch (which is not an option).</p>
<p>Why is this happening? Well, short answer-you need <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/rolled-oats"><strong>energy-boosting snacks</strong></a> for work. Yes, snacks! Just like dinner or lunch, snacks are essential for your body. In-between your meals, you feel hungry or low in energy, and during such times, eating snacks for energy is good instead of grabbing coffee all the time. Sure, coffee is healthy (if you don’t drink the whipped cream version), but exceeding more cups of Joe can have adverse effects. Thus, it is best to grab a snack that is healthy and convenient to carry.</p>
<p>If you are at home, you can grab any healthy snack you like. However, at your office or when working, snacks for energy not only need to be healthy but easy to carry. In this blog, we are sharing energy-boosting snacks for work that are healthy, satisfying, and easy to find or carry.</p>
<h2>Try These 8 Healthy Snacks for Energy Boosting</h2>
<h3><strong>1. Pumpkin seeds</strong></h3>
<p>These small seeds are rich in multiple nutrients. Not only are they high in zinc, magnesium, and healthy omega-3 fats. <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/pumpkin-seeds"><strong>Pumpkin seeds</strong></a> are also super-rich in other nutrients. They also provide you with instant energy, satiating you, thus, making for a perfect snack.</p>
<ul>
<li>They have a high number of antioxidants, which help our body fight free radicals.</li>
<li>It can enhance the health of the bladder and prostate.</li>
<li>They are high in fibre.</li>
<li>They make for a perfect snack.</li>
</ul>
<p>To enjoy this, munch on it raw or roast it or add it to a smoothie.</p>
<h3><strong>2. Bananas and apples</strong></h3>
<p>Any fruit is a great snacking option. Every fruit gives you an energy boost along with the nutrients that your body needs. However, when it comes to energy-boosting snacks for work, then bananas and apples top the chart. They are easy to carry or find near your office. Also, to give it an extra dose of energy, eat them with unsweetened peanut butter. It makes for a yummy and fulfilling snack.</p>
<ul>
<li>Bananas have magnesium and carbohydrates, which can give you an energy boost.</li>
<li>Bananas are a bit sweet. Thus, they are a perfect snack for when you crave something sweet.</li>
<li>Apples are good for digestion and the immune system. A perfect mid-morning snack!</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>3. Almonds </strong></h3>
<p>They are a superfood when it comes to snacks for energy-boosting. They are rich in healthy fats, which makes them a great snacking option.</p>
<ul>
<li>Almonds are rich in antioxidants and calcium, and magnesium</li>
<li>They provide a quick energy boost, and you only need a handful of them for this.</li>
<li>Roast the almonds and add a bit of black pepper &amp; salt. They taste incredible, or you can pack them raw in your office bag.</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>4. Dark chocolate</strong></h3>
<p>Ooh! Who doesn’t love chocolate? Now, you have a reason to eat it, but only pure dark chocolate. They are rich in antioxidants due to the high content of pure cocoa. Thus, they help the heart pump more blood throughout the body. It, in turn, gives you tons of energy and enhances your focus.</p>
<h3><strong>5. Nut butter</strong></h3>
<p>A high-energy boosting snack for work is nut butter. Almond or <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/collections/peanut-butter"><strong>peanut butter</strong></a> or hazelnut nut butter is now available in small pouches for single-time use. Get them and ensure that they do not have added sugar. When you eat a spoonful of these nut butter, you feel energetic and satiated. Also, you can eat them with apples or bananas to balance protein and carbs and feel full for a long time.</p>
<h3><strong>6. Popcorns</strong></h3>
<p>They are low in calories and yummy. So, when feeling a little snacky, get some popcorn. You can pop some in the office microwave and enjoy a treat. Cut back on oil or flavours to keep it low-calorie and healthy.</p>
<h3><strong>7. Smoothies</strong></h3>
<p>Vegetable or fruit smoothies are a perfect energy-boosting snack for work. You can carry them in your tumbler or go have one during your little break. They rejuvenate you and give you an energy kick as well.</p>
<h3><strong>8. Roasted chickpea</strong></h3>
<p>Chickpea is highly nutritious and makes for a great snacking option. They are rich in protein and fibre, which is perfect for boosting energy. Just roast some or buy roasted chickpea, which comes in tons of flavours. Pop them when you are feeling low on energy, and you will not regret it.</p>
<p>Most people avoid snacking, thinking it will increase their weight. That can be true if you munch on unhealthy items or binge-eat healthy snacks. But if you watch what snacks for the energy you eat, they will not lead to any weight-gain issues. Besides, it is best to munch on pumpkin seeds or almonds when you feel slow on energy. Otherwise, your productivity will suffer, and you will also feel cranky and irritated.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/want-to-get-better-health-include-these-10-nuts-and-seeds-in-your-diet-then</id>
    <published>2022-01-06T18:06:24+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-01-07T16:44:53+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/want-to-get-better-health-include-these-10-nuts-and-seeds-in-your-diet-then"/>
    <title>Want to Get Better Health? Include These 10 Nuts and Seeds in Your Diet Then!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Everyone wants a healthy body and ensures that their heart is working in optimal condition. And thus, we worry about every food we consume to ensure that we do not eat something that worsens our physical and mental health. While there is doubt around most foods in our mind, we all have faith in our trusty little trail mix or <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/protein-mix" title="Protein Mix"><strong>protein-mix seeds</strong></a></span>. Right? These are made of <strong><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/super-food-mix"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">nuts and seeds</span></a></strong>, which are healthy. Also, they make for a great &amp; tasty snacking option.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Many scientific studies have proven that nuts are rich in protein, which helps you feel full, eat healthily, and lower the risk of developing diabetes and other heart diseases. It also makes for a yummy snack when you feel hungry or low on energy. Also, adding <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/antioxidant-mix"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>nuts for weight loss</strong></span></a> to your diet is a perfect way to keep your daily calorie intake in control.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">When it comes to seeds, they are light and rich in nutrients, which also helps in weight loss. <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/flax-seeds"><strong>Seeds for weight loss</strong></a> are another diet tip for all looking to lose a few pounds.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you want to become healthier, lose weight, or include healthy snacks in your diet, try these 10 nuts and seeds.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Include these nuts for weight loss in your diet.</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Almonds</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It is a healthy nut that is becoming popular amongst people due to being one of the best nuts for weight loss. Also, it is rich in multi-nutrients making it a healthy snack option. Another fact about almonds that makes them great is the fact that it is available easily.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you usually grab potato chips when hungry, replace them with almonds-raw or roasted. Almonds are rich in proteins, healthy fat, fiber, iron, potassium, Vitamin-E, calcium, and phosphorus. Try unsweetened almond butter to increase your intake of this nut.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Peanuts</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Fun fact, a peanut is a legume, yet in the culinary sense, people consider it a nut. Peanuts are high in protein, which makes them a great addition to your diet. Readily available, it is a perfect nut for weight loss with the presence of an abundance of other nutrients.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Though they are nutritious, you need to limit your consumption per day. It is because peanuts roughly have 567 calories per 100 grams. So, eat them daily but within a limit. Also, they are rich in iron, antioxidants, amino acids, calcium, and flavonoids.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Walnuts</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Walnuts are low in carbohydrates, but high in fat which makes them high-calorie nuts. However, the fat in it is PUFs which are quite beneficial for your body. Also, they are super-rich in proteins, making them a perfect nut for weight loss. You can munch on them or soak them overnight and eat them in the morning. Do eat only a few pieces for better health. You can even add walnuts in your cakes or muffins to add a distinctive flavor to them when it's time for a treat.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Hazelnuts</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Hazelnut is an ideal sweet-tasting nut. You can add to usually people add to sweets. However, adding them to coffee without extra sugar gives your cup of joe a distinct taste. Hazelnuts are not high in proteins, but they do reduce cholesterol. That is a plus for anyone looking to be healthier.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Eat hazelnut by adding them to your milk or as a snack after roasting them. You can even get unsweetened hazelnut butter to enjoy the benefits this nut provides.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Include these Seeds for weight loss in your diet.</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Seeds for weight loss are an excellent idea as they are light in calories and high in nutrients. They have antioxidants, protein, and lots of minerals &amp; vitamins. Thus, making them a perfect snack. You can include them in your smoothie bowl. Eat it raw or add it to your trail mix or oatmeal. Seeds for weight loss to include in your diet are:</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Pumpkin seeds</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">One of the best seeds for weight loss is <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/pumpkin-seeds"><strong>pumpkin seeds</strong></a> because it is high in iron and fiber. It is also rich in protein, amino acids, and omega-3 fatty acids, which are essential for good heart health. Use it on your whole wheat bread or homemade granola and oats.</p>
<h4><strong>Chia Seeds</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/chia-seeds"><strong>Chia seeds</strong></a> are incredible little seeds. They are high in antioxidants, fiber, and omega-3 fatty acids. All of these nutrients help your gut and heart health. You can eat chia seeds by soaking in water and drinking that water. Or sprinkle them on smoothies or oatmeal.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Wild rice</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Wild rice is a grass seed that is extremely high in proteins. Also, it is richer in antioxidants than white rice. Also, add wild rice to your salads. Or substitute it for white rice allows you to absorb zinc, niacin, and Vitamin B6.</p>
<h4><strong>Quinoa</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">An excellent substitute for rice, <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/quinoa-seeds"><strong>quinoa seeds</strong></a> are rich in protein (it has 15% protein per 8 grams cup). It also has vitamin E and quercetin, which are quite healthy for your body. Try eating it as a substitute for rice or as a breakfast option.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Flax seeds</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">An ideal <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/flax-seeds"><strong>Flax seeds</strong></a> for weight loss, it is high in nutrients, especially in fiber &amp; proteins. It is high in omega-3 fatty and linoleic acid too. Due to this, it helps enhance cardiovascular disease. It is rich in lignans too, which helps reduce your chances of cancer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">There are multiple ways to include seeds and nuts for weight loss in your diet. By adding them to your breakfast or smoothies or more, you can absorb the goodness they provide while losing weight the right way.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/10-vegetarian-foods-that-are-loaded-with-iron</id>
    <published>2021-11-01T11:10:35+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-03-21T16:42:34+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/10-vegetarian-foods-that-are-loaded-with-iron"/>
    <title>10 Vegetarian Foods That Are Loaded With Iron</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Iron is one of the essential nutrients that our body requires. It is one nutrient whose deficiency can lead to anemia. Also, it leads to shortness of breath, dizziness, and headaches, amongst other things. Iron-rich foods are the best source for every human to ensure their iron level never dwindles. However, vegetarians or vegans can find it challenging to eat the required amount of iron every day. It is because heme-iron, which the body absorbs the best, is only found in animal products like meat. Non-heme, which is only available in plants, has iron, but the body takes time to absorb it.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thus, vegetarians must eat a wide variety of fruits and veggies high in iron. Don’t worry! With the number of options available, you can ensure that your body doesn’t get iron deficiency. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;"><strong>Here are the 10 food items to include in your diet for iron.</strong></h2>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong>1. Chanterelle mushrooms-6.4 gm iron per 200 servings </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">High in iron, this fungal delicacy can be an incredible addition to your meals. You can make a main course out of it (which can be pricey) or enjoy a salad or sandwich with little chunks of this mushroom. It makes for a delicious dish that you need to try out.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong>2. Soybean- 8.8 mg iron per one cup  </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Soybeans are a great source of iron, and they are delicious too. Products that are derived from soybeans, like tofu or tempeh, also have a high quantity of iron. Tofu is particularly easy to use in meals, like a salad or burger Pattie.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another reason to increase your intake of soybean is that they are rich in other nutrients. It has phosphorus, calcium, and magnesium.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong>3. Cashews- 6.7 mg in 100 grams  </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cashews and other nuts like almonds or pine nuts have a good amount of iron. Even macadamia has 1-1.6 mg of iron in it. Nuts are a great piece of food that can curb hunger and make for great midday or late-night snacks. However, two things to remember here is to consume them raw. Roasting them decreases their nutrients. Also, do not binge on them, as that can be too much for your body to handle. Even nut butter has a high amount of iron, but only if you choose 100% natural butter. If you are not careful, you can end up eating loads of sugar. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Also Read:</strong> <span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/want-to-get-better-health-include-these-10-nuts-and-seeds-in-your-diet-then" style="color: #167a62;">Want to Get Better Health? Include These 10 Nuts and Seeds in Your Diet Then!</a></span></span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong>4. Spinach-4 mg per 150 g </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spinach is one of the best leafy vegetables to have. It is high in iron, along with other nutrients. Use it in salad or sandwiches, or make a curry pout of it. Adding other green leafy vegetables increases its nutritional value.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong>5. Canned tomatoes-1.57 mg per ½ cup </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Canned tomatoes are a simple way to add iron to your meals. Use it in vegetables or sandwiches to enjoy some iron boost.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong>6. Boiled green peas-2.46 mg per cup </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">They are high in iron and are something you can pair with tons of vegetables. You can even eat them raw, and they will not taste funny.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong>7. Patotoes-3.2 mg in one potato </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Contrary to popular belief, potatoes are a great source of many nutrients. And amongst which iron and fiber are significant. If you eat with the skin, the nutritional value is even more. Sweet potato is also rich in iron, but slightly less than the regular ones. Eat them boiled and not fried.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong>8. Palm hearts-4.6 mg per cup</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Palm hearts are one of the best and delicious tropical vegetables. Along with iron, it is rich in fiber, vitamin C, folate, magnesium, and potassium. Try it in stir-fry or salad, and you will not complain.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong>9. Olives- 3.3 mg per 100 grams</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Technically a fruit, olives are a rich source of iron. It also has fat, fiber, and soluble vitamin E &amp; A.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It also helps you promote good heart health, and eating them raw or juicing them is easy.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong>10. Oats-3.4 mg per one cup</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you eat a bowl of cooked oats, your meal has a massive amount of oats and fiber. It also has some protein, which helps you stay full and subdue the urge to eat junk.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">To conclude, iron is important! Period! So, include these items in your meals and ensure you are eating enough to supplement your body. Otherwise, you can get sick often, and no one wants that.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/5-proven-home-remedies-for-indigestion-and-gas</id>
    <published>2021-11-01T11:02:14+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-02-04T15:08:00+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/5-proven-home-remedies-for-indigestion-and-gas"/>
    <title>5 Proven Home Remedies for Indigestion and Gas</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is the season of festivals, meaning the season of eating fried &amp; spicy food. As far as taste is concerned, this season will surely be a favorite for every foodie. But as far as health and healthy eating habits are concerned, this season is heavy for those who suffer from weak digestive systems. People whose digestion is not good, whenever they eat something spicy or fried, they face problems. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stomach issues</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> like indigestion, acidity, or stomach gas are</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> common for them.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gas is particularly problematic. It can come with stomach cramps and lead to flatulence, which is quite embarrassing for all.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you want, you can solve the stomach gas problem by adopting some home remedies. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The heavy food items that we consume</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> during the festive season produce a lot of gas. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thus, adopting home remedies is better than eating too many pills. Isn't it? Here are the home remedies that you can try.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;"><strong>5 Proven Home Remedies For Indigestion and Gas </strong></h2>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong>1. Ginger </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Among the substances used for digestion, ginger comes first.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> It </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">helps in digestion and prevents inflammation and heartburn. After a meal, a sip of a mixture of ginger and some lemon juice can keep you away from stomach troubles. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong>2. Aloe Vera Juice </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If facing the problem of indigestion or gas, then consuming <span style="color: #3bbf4a;"><a title="Aloe Vera Juice" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/aloe-vera-juice" style="color: #3bbf4a;">Aloe Vera Juice</a></span> is beneficial for you. It soothes your digestive system and helps you get rid of gas and indigestion. On facing any digestive problem, you are advised to take 15-20 ml fresh Aloe Vera Juice daily, and you will see the difference.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong>3. Fenugreek Seeds (methi) </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you have severe belching for several days, you can use fenugreek. Soak fenugreek in water overnight. Then after that, drink this fenugreek water on an empty stomach i</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">n the morning.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Consumption of this will relieve the problem of sour belching. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong>4. Ajwain </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ajwain will work as an easy way to remove gas. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Take a teaspoon</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of Ajwain with little black salt. Chew it and eat it for </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">instant relief</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It will get rid of the gas in the stomach.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong>5. Probiotic Curd </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">most milk products causing</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> digestive problems, yogurt or curd has the opposite effect. The probiotics present in it helps in relieving stomach disorders. It provides relief in digestive and gas-related problems. </span></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Enjoy the festive season without worrying about gas by adopting these home-remedies. They are safe, have no side effects, and are readily available.</span></p>
</blockquote>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
