<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/immunity-detox.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/immunity-detox"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/immunity-detox.atom"/>
  <title>Neuherbs - Immunity &amp; Detox</title>
  <updated>2022-01-10T18:22:10+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Neuherbs</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/immunity-detox/7-ways-to-boost-your-energy-levels-naturally</id>
    <published>2022-01-10T18:22:10+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-03-21T18:10:38+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/immunity-detox/7-ways-to-boost-your-energy-levels-naturally"/>
    <title>7 Ways to Boost Your Energy Levels Naturally</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are times when we feel tired or low on energy. The fatigue we feel makes us demotivated to be productive or even get out of bed. Nowadays, fatigue has become a common complaint amongst people of all ages. Sure, you can gulp down a cup of Red Bull or 5 cups of coffee to feel energetic and less tired. But these work for a while! Sodas are anyway full of sugar, destroying your health in the long term. Then, how to boost energy levels? Through natural ways, of course!</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Trying natural ways to increase energy levels is always the best approach. These work on your whole body, which is any better.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Natural ways to enhance energy levels will work for everyone, whether it is due to lifestyle factors or other causes. These causes include physical and mental illnesses that can contribute to fatigue and low energy levels.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Best and efficient natural ways to increase energy levels</strong></h3>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Eat a balanced diet</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eating a balanced diet every day is essential for staying energetic. To boost energy levels naturally, cut back on packaged food full of sodium &amp; sugar. These may provide you with taste, but they make you lethargic and unhealthy. So, stick to whole and fresh foods like vegetables, fruits, and whole grains for better energy levels. </span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Reduce stress</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stress in some situations is a push that makes us shine at moments. For instance, when you stress about a speech and work hard on it, the speech comes on well. However, if you continue to take stress every day over things you cannot control, it leads to health issues. They affect both your physical and mental health.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you suffer from chronic stress, you feel low-on energy. Thus, one of the effective natural ways to boost energy levels is to reduce stress. How?</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">By doing yoga and mediation</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">By journaling</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Go on a walk (on grass is the best)</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Talk to someone about things that are stressing you out.</span></li>
</ul>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"> <strong>Munch on healthy snacks</strong>
</h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes your energy levels deplete or decrease because you are hungry. When you do not eat enough or well, you will feel tired and lazy. If this is the case, a natural way to boost energy levels is to eat quick &amp; healthy snacks. Here are some of the <span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/are-your-kids-hungry-11-snacks-ideas-which-are-healthy-and-delicious" style="color: #167a62;"><strong>best healthy snacks</strong></a></span> to munch: </span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Peanut butter </strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/collections/peanut-butter" style="color: #167a62;"><strong>Peanut butter</strong></a></span> is rich in protein and other nutrients. If you eat it unsweetened or on a balanced diet, it is healthy for you. If you feel hungry and low on energy, get your trusty peanut butter out and spread it on toast (whole wheat) and enjoy it. Or you can eat apples and bananas with peanut butter for more energy and satiety. Peanut butter is also a great pre-workout breakfast option. It helps you boost energy levels before a workout, so you feel energetic for all your cardio. You can also have it post-workout.</span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Yogurt with fresh fruits</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yogurt is full of proteins and calcium. It is also a rich source of probiotics, healthy for your gut. So, when feeling low on energy, try eating yogurt. Also, add some fresh strawberries or raspberries for healthy carbs. They will keep you full for long.</span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Coffee</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">One cup of coffee when you are feeling hungry and low on energy is fine. Just keep it simple with less sugar. Try eating an entire grain toast with it for some carbs too. Coffee is another item to have to boost energy levels before a workout. It is proven by science! </span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Roasted chickpeas</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chickpeas are high in protein and other nutrients. It is a natural way to boost energy levels. It releases energy slowly, and also it is a yummy snack. Add sliced onions or tomatoes to perk up the flavor.</span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Take daily supplements</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you have vitamin or mineral deficiency, it can lead to fatigue and low energy levels. For instance, women battling thyroid disorder feel fatigued if they do not take their thyroid medication. The medication regulates their hormones and helps them feel better. Similarly, men whose testosterone levels are low can feel low on energy, amongst other issues. If that is the case, taking a <span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/t7-test-on-ayurveda-muscle-booster" style="color: #167a62;"><strong>testosterone booster</strong></a></span> can help you fix this issue.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other <span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/" style="color: #167a62;"><strong>natural supplements</strong></a></span> can help you with your mineral/vitamin deficiency and not feel lethargic.</span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Hydrate</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes there is a simple reason why we feel so tired. And that is not drinking enough water. When you don’t drink enough, your body becomes dehydrated, and you start feeling lethargic. The next time you feel sluggish, sip on water or coconut water to replenish your energy.</span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Get moving</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Feeling sluggish and thinking about how to boost energy levels naturally? Then get up and start moving. If you are at the office, take a break and go on for a five-minute walk. Or if you cannot,  stand and do some basic exercises like stretching or so on, anything that is feasible., Itit  will give you an immediate boost of energy.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, make exercise a part of your daily routine. A thirty-minute walk, or yoga, or cardio session can help you boost energy levels naturally.</span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Work on your sleep schedule</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Believe us, the best natural way to boost energy levels is to get sufficient sleep. If you are someone who struggles with sleep, instead of focusing on 7-8 hours a night, try to sleep soundly, even if that means for 2 hours. To do this:</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Have a sleep schedule. Sleep at a fixed time every day.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do not look at the screen before calling it a night</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Restrict or avoid naps</span></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once you start sleeping soundly, work on adding hours to get 7-8 hours of sleep.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In conclusion, natural ways to boost energy level depends on these factors: sleep, diet, workout, and stress. Irrespective of the reasons for your fatigue, if you can manage these factors, you will enhance your level of energy and instantly decrease the level of tiredness. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/immunity-detox/10-unbelievable-benefits-of-drinking-giloy-juice</id>
    <published>2021-10-19T11:01:11+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-03-21T16:32:15+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/immunity-detox/10-unbelievable-benefits-of-drinking-giloy-juice"/>
    <title>10 Unbelievable Benefits Of Drinking Giloy Juice</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Giloy juice is a new rage nowadays. Benefits of drinking giloy juice are being discussed more than before. If you are thinking of drinking giloy juice, knowing the benefits you get from it, is important. So, does knowing what exactly is giloy?</p>
<h2>What is Giloy?</h2>
<p>Giloy is a type of vine commonly found in jungles and bushes. Since ancient times, giloy has been part of ayurvedic treatment. Due to its benefits, there has been increased awareness amongst people in the recent few years. Now people have started planting Giloy vine in their homes. However, most people are still unable to identify Giloy properly.</p>
<p>Giloy is a type of vine commonly found in jungles and bushes. Since ancient times, giloy has been part of ayurvedic treatment. Due to its benefits, there has been increased awareness amongst people in the recent few years. Now people have started planting Giloy vine in their homes. However, most people are still unable to identify Giloy properly.</p>
<h2><strong>10 Benefits Of Drinking Giloy Juice.</strong></h2>
<p>Benefits of taking Giloy juice are immense.</p>
<h3><strong>1.Boosts Immunity</strong></h3>
<p>One of the benefits of drinking <span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/himalayan-giloy-mulethi-juice" style="color: #167a62;"><strong>giloy juice</strong></a></span> is that this herb contains antioxidants. These are essential as it helps our body fight diseases. It also removes the dirt and toxins present in your body, which keeps your blood clean. It helps in increasing your immunity.</p>
<h3><strong> 2. Helps in Chronic Fever </strong></h3>
<p>Giloy or Guduchi has antipyretic properties that also help in chronic fever. For this reason, consumption of Giloy is recommended to relieve fever in severe diseases like malaria, dengue, and swine flu. It is one of the many health benefits of giloy juice.<span style="font-size: 10.0pt; line-height: 187%; color: #3c3c3c;" lang="EN"></span></p>
<h3><strong>3. Improves Digestion</strong></h3>
<p>If you are troubled by digestive problems such as constipation, acidity or indigestion, Giloy can prove to be very beneficial for you. The decoction of Giloy keeps many stomach diseases away. Therefore, to get rid of constipation and indigestion, drink Giloy juice daily.</p>
<h3><strong>4. Blood Sugar Level Management</strong></h3>
<p>According to experts, Giloy acts as a hypoglycemic agent and plays an effective role in managing type-2 diabetes. Giloy juice lowers blood sugar levels, increases insulin secretion and lowers insulin resistance. In this way, it is a very useful medicine for diabetes patients.</p>
<h3><strong>5. Bone Health</strong></h3>
<p>Giloy stifles ligament inflammation by hindering the creation of fiery cytokines (particles that advance inflammation). If there should arise an occurrence of autoimmune disorder, the body’s immune system attacks the body.  Giloy is known to support the immune system due to its anti-inflammatory properties. When you take Giloy in the event of immune system illnesses, it might over-invigorate the immune system.<span> </span></p>
<h3><strong>6. Giloy Juice for Weight Loss</strong></h3>
<p>Use of giloy juice boosts immunity and digestion, which help in weight reduction. It likewise improves absorption of nutrients. These components through and through add to weight loss. To improve weight loss, you can use a limited quantity of giloy juice on an empty stomach. Take 2-3 spoons of giloy juice and blend it in with water or aloe vera juice. Drink this juice early morning on an empty stomach to reap the benefits fully.</p>
<h3><strong>7. Helps in Respiratory Function</strong></h3>
<p>Giloy is best for the management of asthma and an incessant cough. It has great calming properties and represses the reaction of cells that cause inflammation. It decreases the irritation of air entries if there should arise an occurrence of asthma and cough. One of the benefits of taking Giloy juice is that it controls bodily fluid hypersecretion because of an expansion in the quantity of phlegm (cells that secretes bodily fluid) related to asthma.</p>
<h3><strong>8. Reduces Stress And Anxiety</strong></h3>
<p>Giloy plant is otherwise called an adaptogenic (overseas stress hormone). It works by stifling overactivation of the sensory system and decreasing mental stress and nervousness. It has a calming effect on the mind. It is one of the key health benefits of drinking giloy juice.</p>
<h3><strong>9. Helps In Anemia</strong></h3>
<p>Due to the lack of blood in the body, many types of diseases start. Anemia is the most prominent of all such diseases. Women usually suffer more from anemia. Giloy juice is very beneficial for women suffering from anemia. Consumption of Giloy juice controls blood loss in the body and makes immunity strong.</p>
<h3><strong>10. Helps in Liver Health</strong></h3>
<p>Excess alcohol consumption causes liver damage in many ways. In this case, the intake of Guduchi Sattva or Giloy Sattva works as a tonic for the liver. It cleanses the blood and increases the level of antioxidant enzymes. In this way, it reduces the workload of the liver and keeps the liver healthy. Regular intake of Giloy protects against severe liver diseases.</p>
<p><strong>Who Can Drink Giloy Juice?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Giloy juice can be given to adults for a brief timeframe to deal with several issues.</li>
<li>However, consult your doctor if you are pregnant, lactating or suffering from any illness.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>How Can Diabetics Use Giloy Juice?</strong></p>
<p>Many accept that fresh Giloy juice can do some incredible things for people with diabetes. It can lower insulin levels and provide people with energy.</p>
<p>You can use Neuherbs Giloy Mulethi Juice for consumption. Add some water to get a juice-like consistency. Then, strain the blend in a glass and add a couple of drops of lemon to it. Drink it before anything else to see the benefits of drinking giloy juice.</p>
<p><strong>How to Consume Giloy Juice?</strong></p>
<p>In today’s time, most people know the benefits of drinking Giloy juice. Usually, you can use Giloy in three forms: Giloy extract, Giloy juice and Giloy powder. Nowadays, Giloy extract and Giloy juice are easily available in the market.</p>
<p><strong>Can You Drink Giloy Juice Daily?</strong></p>
<p>You can have one glass of this giloy juice daily. Take 2-3 teaspoons of Giloy Juice, add the same quantity of water to it and drink it on an empty stomach in the morning.</p>
<p> <span style="font-size: 10.0pt; line-height: 187%; color: #3c3c3c;" lang="EN"></span><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><strong><span style="line-height: 187%; color: #3c3c3c;" lang="EN"></span></strong></span><strong>How Is Neuherbs Giloy Mulethi Juice Unique?</strong></p>
<p class="shopnow"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/himalayan-giloy-mulethi-juice"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0577/6162/8330/products/NeuherbsHimalayanGiloyMulethiJuice1_1024x1024.jpg?v=1627204754" width="300px"><span>Shop Now</span></a></p>
<ul>
<li>Contains 80 % giloy, 19% mulethi.</li>
<li>Comes with the promise of purity and safety.</li>
<li>Does not contain added water, additives, artificial flavour, preservatives &amp; color.</li>
<li>Is sugar-free, naturally gluten-free &amp; laboratory tested.</li>
<li>Abundant taste and antioxidants.</li>
<li>Helps with healthy digestion and respiratory disorders.</li>
</ul>
<p>Still have questions? Get a FREE consultation from our expert nutritionists and dietitians! Scan or click the QR code below to chat now!</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> Giloy is a natural herb, with tons of proven benefits. It doesn’t have side effect, and is something you can benefit from. However, if you have any chronic illness, do consult a doctor before consuming it.</p>
</blockquote>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
