<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle.atom"/>
  <title>Neuherbs - Lifestyle</title>
  <updated>2022-04-26T16:41:54+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Neuherbs</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/top-6-pre-workout-food-for-a-robust-and-healthy-life</id>
    <published>2022-04-26T16:41:54+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-04-26T16:41:54+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/top-6-pre-workout-food-for-a-robust-and-healthy-life"/>
    <title>Top 6 Pre-workout Food for a Robust and Healthy Life</title>
    <author>
      <name>neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">With a mindset to lead a healthy lifestyle, gym memberships are rising worldwide. As the pandemic-induced lockdowns are relaxed and life returns to normal, people are once again waking up to the need to stay fit and healthy. And what better way to maintain your health than through regular focused workouts and a balanced diet!</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Reports suggest that about 1 in 4 Americans went to a gym in 2019. This number grew by about 27% between 2019 and 2020, increasing from 58 million fitness enthusiasts to 73.6. While the pandemic, which started in early 2020, put a brake on this phenomenal growth trajectory, the numbers are all set to rise as life returns to the pre-pandemic state.    </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">However, a note of caution. While the number of people going in for gym workouts continues to increase exponentially, most of them are approaching this in an unscientific manner. Prominent among this is most of them head to scheduled workouts on an empty stomach.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This is primarily because they either subscribe to the view that one should not eat anything before a workout or have no firm ideas on what they can eat before going to the gym. While this doesn't necessarily mean that you should eat heartily before a workout, you should balance the elevated energy requirements for a gym session. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The key here is to embrace a middle path — eating the right pre-workout food to balance energy requirements with your health and fitness targets.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The Popular Choices for Pre-workout Food: A Six-Point Agenda</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Besides promoting overall health and well-being, bodybuilding continues to be a highly competitive domain. It is quite easy to draw inspiration from other participants in the gym. Therefore, unsurprisingly, we often tend to be in a state of mental competition, egging ourselves onwards to achieve that perfect shape and stamina.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This competitive edge, in turn, is key for the participants because it provides the much-needed drive for attempting more stringent workouts. Promoting a faster growth of lean muscles and higher performance levels requires increased time for workouts, higher concentration and deeper focus. Therefore, we may get fatigued during such a strenuous workout and be forced to seek a solution. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Pre-workout food and supplements can be of great help here, assisting us in staying more alert, focussed and energised during the longer workout sessions. In addition, these natural nutrition sources also help promote a quicker, post-exercise recovery so that we can resume work with minimal disruptions.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Of late, pre-workout food has become popular among enthusiasts. This surge in popularity has resulted in several alternatives, either natural or synthesised. While the options for pre-workout food have multiplied, it is advisable to consult a professional before choosing your diet regimen. Careful consideration of the underlying health condition could go a long way in ensuring that the intended benefits are received.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Top 6 pre-workout food items to help you here:</h2>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">1. Oatmeal (with, or without, a Banana!)</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Oatmeal is made from oats, considered among the healthiest grains on earth. Oats are gluten-free whole grain and serve as a great source of important vitamins, minerals, fibre and antioxidants. Studies show that oatmeal has several health benefits, including promoting weight loss, lower blood sugar levels and a reduced risk of heart disease.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Recently, oatmeal has emerged as a popular pre-workout food. It has made its mark for early morning sessions, including an early run that you would normally undertake on an empty stomach because it is not advisable to have a heavy meal a few hours before. Oatmeal, being comparatively light, can be safely consumed before such sessions and is known to be light on your stomach. It also acts as a great option for providing much-needed energy. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">And should you be able to add a sprinkling of fruits to your pre-workout oatmeal, the benefits are only multiplied. Bananas can be used.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Bananas contain natural sugar and starch that give energy to the body. They are also very rich in carbohydrates, and even one banana consumed about an hour before your workouts can help you keep going for long. Trainers regularly recommend this fruit as pre-workout food for those looking to push their limits on the gym floors as a well-balanced choice of nutrients and energy. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Combining oatmeal and bananas can therefore be a great nutritional choice.   </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">2. Brown Rice and a Side of Chicken</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">While many people prefer to work out during the morning before heading to work or college, some prefer to hit the gym for an evening or night session. For those who prefer the latter alternative, brown rice with chicken is a great pre-workout food option. Nutritionists feel that brown rice is absorbed quite slowly and is a good source of carbohydrates, while chicken is the ideal form of lean meat and the best source of protein. Therefore, this combination is perfect before a workout, with a medium-sized serving of brown rice with just two slices of chicken being worth 200-300 calories.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">3. Protein Shakes</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Protein shakes are very popular among those who regularly hit the gym. Protein is vital for the all-around development of your muscles, bones and skin. A good protein shake is a must if you are not receiving adequate amounts from your natural intake. For people doing regular and intense workouts, it is important to have a protein shake before or after the session.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Some protein shakes can indeed have grave side effects, including kidney damage, if used unwisely. Users should therefore consult their doctor/nutritionist to know their recommended daily dose of safe levels of protein intake. </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">4. Peanut Butter Sandwiches/Honey and Whole Wheat Bagels</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Yes – you read that right. <strong><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/all-natural-peanut-butter">Natural peanut butter</a></strong> or organic peanut butter or honey is a great option for a pre-workout food, which is well balanced in both energy and nutrition. The idea is to select multigrain or whole wheat bread for the sandwich or opt for a whole wheat bagel instead. Apart from that, you can buy your <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/collections/peanut-butter"><strong>Omega</strong> <strong>peanut butter online</strong></a>, these days.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In case you're wondering about the overall calorie count here, please remember that if you are working out during the morning, you have been fasting for at least 8 or 9 hours already. A brown bread peanut butter sandwich (or whole wheat bagel with honey) will help address the energy deficit and give you the much-needed boost to meet and exceed your workout targets on the gym floor.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">5. Granola/Exercise bars</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Eating an exercise bar as a part of your pre-workout food regimen means having more energy reserves during the gym or run session. Exercise, or granola bars, are rich in carbohydrates, which take care of your energy requirements during a workout session. However, we should look to make sure that the exercise bar has only the minimum amount of fibre, fats and proteins to ensure the maximum benefits from such a diet.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">6. Yoghurt </h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Yoghurts, including curd and <em>Dahi</em>, contain proteins and calcium, along with natural sugar in trace quantities. A yoghurt sits easily on your stomach and digestive system and has been recognised by nutritionists, worldwide, as an effective option for pre-workout food before any intense sessions. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Combining yoghurt with whole-grain cereals, honey or fruits will provide you with a quick energy boost and help meet several nutritional requirements at the same time. It is also a great way to promote targeted weight-loss regimens, if taken in a controlled manner.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Towards a Healthy and Fit Future</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In the post-pandemic world, staying healthy is not just merely an aspirational goal. COVID-19 has driven home the validity of the age-old maxim: "Health is Wealth."</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As the world returns to normal and we start resuming our pre-pandemic routines, we must remember the health lessons of this important phase in our lives. And the most important lesson here is probably the need to work out, not just to stay in shape but also to promote our health and overall well-being. This is a vital consideration for driving into a healthy and fit future.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">At the start of the present article, we referenced the fact that global gym visits were growing at an exponential rate – a trend that is expected to grow only stronger with every passing day. However, your workouts need not just include intense gym sessions. A morning run, an evening swim, or even focused exercises and yoga sessions at home could help make a difference in your overall health and future fitness levels. The key here is to remember that while getting into and staying in shape can help boost your social profile, it is ultimately your overall health that is of vital importance. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In this regard, there is no better way to ensure the future than with regular workout sessions. Regularity and consistency will help you reap the rewards that lie in store. And should you be able to support your exercise sessions with a portion of great pre-workout food, the results will only be there for you and the world to see, appreciate and commend.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Stay Healthy!</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/simple-ways-to-boost-your-sleep-quality</id>
    <published>2022-04-22T18:24:10+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-04-22T18:24:10+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/simple-ways-to-boost-your-sleep-quality"/>
    <title>Are You Experiencing a Sleeping Disorder? 15 Simple Ways to Boost Your Sleep Quality</title>
    <author>
      <name>neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Good health and a positive outlook on life are built on a solid foundation of sound sleep. But when was the last time you woke up feeling energized, excited and eager to take on the day? Or did you fall asleep without any effort at all?</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"> As per the National Institutes of Health (NIH), in the United States, about one-third of adults suffer from a sleeping disorder. Stress can exacerbate the problem, making it even more challenging to deal with.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The National Institutes of Health recommends adults must get at least 7.5 hours of sleep every night to maintain good mental and physical health, improve quality of life and avoid the greater risk of harm. The following are their suggestions for a restful night's sleep:  </p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">15 Simple Ways to Boost Your Sleep Quality</h2>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">1. Limit your evening caffeine intake </h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">90% of the US population consumes caffeine. One dose can improve concentration, energy, as well as sports performance. Caffeine, especially taken late in the day, can interfere with your body's ability to wind down naturally at night, as it stimulates the nervous system. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Moreover, caffeine consumed within 6 hours of bedtime harms sleep quality in one study. It can take up to 8 hours for the caffeine effects to wear off in your body. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Hence, if you're sensitive to caffeine or have a sleeping disorder, it's best to avoid consuming a considerable amount of coffee after 3–4 p.m. Instead, it's best to drink decaffeinated coffee in the late afternoon or at night if you're feeling the need for a pick-me-up. </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">2. Reduce the frequency and duration of afternoon naps</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The benefits of quick power naps outweigh the risks of daytime naps that are too long or irregular. In addition, taking a nap in the afternoon can disrupt your ability to sleep at night. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Participants in one study reported feeling sleepier throughout the day due to the daytime naps. However, in a separate study, researchers found that while a 30-minute nap can improve daytime brain function, taking longer naps can hamper health and sleep.  </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">On the other hand, some studies show that those who regularly nap during the day have better quality sleep. So you shouldn't be concerned if you nap periodically during the day and subsequently get adequate sleep at night. Napping's effects vary from person to person.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">3. Don't ingest any alcoholic beverages</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Even a small amount of alcohol late at night might cause a sleeping disorder to your hormones. As a result, snoring, sleep apnea and other sleep-related issues can be aggravated or worsened by alcohol consumption.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Melatonin, an essential hormone in the body's circadian cycle, is likewise affected by light exposure at night. In addition, human growth hormone (HGH), which regulates your circadian rhythm and performs various other vital activities, was found to be reduced by nocturnal alcohol use in another study.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"> 4. Maintain a regular routine</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Repetition is key to getting a good night's sleep. Going to sleep and waking up around the same time is a good rule of the thumb. As a result, your body's biological clock will be strengthened, making it easier for you to fall asleep and wake up. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">You should begin preparing for sleep at least an hour before you intend to sleep. Go to bed by donning your pajamas, turning down the lights, reading a book or two and doing deep breathing exercises.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">5. Make sure you don't eat too late at night</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">A sleeping disorder and hormonal imbalances might result from eating a large meal before bedtime. Having particular snacks and meals a few hours before going to bed could be beneficial in this regard.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Having a late-night meal can interfere with a good night's sleep and the human growth hormone and melatonin production. That said, your late-night snack's quality and type may also impact.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">A high-carbohydrate dinner consumed 4 hours before bedtime was found to hasten sleep in one research. The fact that a low-carb diet also helped with sleep suggests that carbs aren't always important, especially if you're used to one. </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">6. Hit the gym</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Going to the gym, the first thing in the morning, can make it much simpler to fall asleep later in the day. Physical activity releases tension and gets us ready for a good night's sleep, so it's good to get some exercise early in the day to aid your sleeping disorder at night. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">According to a study published in the journal Mental Health and Physical Activity in 2011, those who exercised for 150 minutes a week were more likely to get a good night's sleep.</p>
<h3>7. Relax in the tub or the shower</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Another popular method of improving one's sleep quality is to take a bath or shower. Studies have shown overall sleep quality improvement by this method, which helps older folks fall asleep more quickly.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Opting for a hot bath for 90 minutes prior to going to bed has been shown to improve sleep quality. It can aid people to fall asleep more quickly. Instead of a complete bath at night, you can merely soak your feet in hot water to help you relax and go to sleep.</p>
<h3> 8. Maintain a regular exercise regimen but not before bed</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Physical activity is a proven method for improving sleep and overall health. It has been used to alleviate insomnia symptoms and enhance sleep quality.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In a study of older persons, exercise cut down the time it took to fall asleep by nearly half and increased sleep time by 41 minutes every night. The exercise was more beneficial than most medications for persons with severe insomnia. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">By exercising, the time taken to fall asleep was cut down by 55%, time taken to stay awake was cut down by 30%, and the time taken to fall asleep got increased by 18%. A good night's sleep depends on regular exercise, but doing it too late in the day can induce sleep issues.  </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"> 9. Drink tart cherry juice </h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Rather than drinking wine, sip on some sour cherry juice. You'll get a better night's sleep if you drink some tart cherry juice. More than 85 minutes of extra sleep were gained by elderly insomniacs who drank two eight-ounce glasses of sour cherry juice a day.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"> 10. Sleep better using an Ashwagandha tablet</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">People who take Ashwagandha may be able to fall asleep more quickly, stay asleep for a longer period, and have improved sleep quality. For example, participants in an actigraphy-based study, who took Ashwagandha for 6 weeks described their sleep to be 72% better on average. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">A variety of Ashwagandha's components may be responsible for its sleep-enhancing properties. Triethylene glycol, a naturally occurring compound in the herb, has been linked to drowsiness by researchers. In addition, Ashwagandha may affect GABA receptors, which are critical to the sleep-wake cycle. Ashwagandha's apparent medicinal properties may be due to other molecules yet to be found.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Withanolides, the primary active element in Ashwagandha, is thought to have various health advantages, including the capacity to reduce stress. Studies have shown that those under a lot of stress have a lower sleep and are more tired during the day. Therefore, if taken before bed for improved relaxation, the <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/ashwagandha-1000-plus">Ashwagandha tablets</a> can help you sleep better. </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"> 11. Make the appropriate mattress &amp; pillow purchases</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Mattresses aren't one-size-fits-all, and they don't all work for everyone. It all boils down to the mattress's level of support. Consider your height, weight, body type and preferred sleeping position when purchasing a new mattress. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">For example, if you weigh more than 200 pounds, you'll want a greater density support foam mattress or one with lower-gagged coils that will push you back and hold you in place as you sleep. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Make sure to keep this in mind while shopping for a new mattress. You must spend at least 30 days with a new bed before you can get used to and adapt to your new mattress.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">12. Refuse to overindulge right before bedtime</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Reflux might occur if you go to bed with a full stomach. Those who've been through it may attest to the fact that it's a frightening experience. Reduce the risk of this by not eating within 3 hours of going to bed.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">13. Enhance the ambience of your bedroom</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Many individuals feel that a good night's sleep results from the bedroom environment and its arrangement. Temperature, noise, light from the outside and furniture layout are all examples of environmental influences. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In numerous studies, external noise, particularly from traffic, has been linked to poor sleep and long-term health problems. Noise and light were found to significantly impact the quality of sleep for women in a recent study. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Try to keep your bedroom as quiet as possible by reducing the amount of noise, light and artificial light from gadgets like alarm clocks. Make sure your bedroom is a peaceful, restful, tidy and pleasurable location to spend time at night! </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">14. Take a couple of deep breaths </h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Take a moment to focus on your breathing if you're having trouble falling asleep because of tension. Begin the night by focusing on deep belly breathing. You can apply this method if you are prone to waking up early in the morning or even in the middle of the night.  </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"> 15. Avoid gadgets before bed</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">When it comes to pre-sleep activities, you would think that scrolling through your Instagram feed is actually calming. Checking email or social networking sites before bed might make it difficult to relax and drift off to sleep because of the light they emit and the feelings they evoke. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Blue light inhibits melatonin production. This essentially is the hormone responsible for controlling your sleep-wake cycles). As a result, when you're ready to go to sleep, set your phone into ‘sleep’ mode, as this removes the blue light from the screen. However, if possible, avoid using any electronic devices at all.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em><strong>Conclusion: Final Thoughts!</strong></em></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">You can't function properly with a sleeping disorder. Insufficient sleep was found to be associated with an 89% increase in the risk of childhood obesity and a 55% rise in adult obesity.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Studies show that having fewer than 7–8 hours of sleep per night raises the risk of type 2 diabetes and heart disease, among other health problems. To be at your healthiest and happiest, it is recommended that you prioritise sleep and use a few of the suggestions listed above.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/10-foods-to-have-before-going-to-bed</id>
    <published>2022-04-22T16:59:58+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-04-22T17:12:00+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/10-foods-to-have-before-going-to-bed"/>
    <title>10 Foods to Have Before Going to Bed</title>
    <author>
      <name>neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The majority of medical professionals advise against consuming heavy meals right before going to bed. Do late-night nibbles affect your ability to get a good night’s sleep? According to research, a person's ability to fall asleep depends entirely on the food consumed prior to going to bed.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Getting a good night's sleep is vital to your health and well-being. You can reduce your risk of facing any chronic illnesses by having a restful slumber daily. It also helps to strengthen your immune system as a whole.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">A lot of individuals find it challenging to acquire the 7 to 9 hours of unbroken sleep per night, as suggested by most experts. However, making changes in the diet can be helpful in getting a good night's sleep, as varying beverages and food items have sleep-enhancing characteristics.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">10 Best Foods to Eat Before Going to Bed to Enjoy an Improved Slumber</h2>
<h3>1. Cherries</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Researchers recently discovered that opting to drink tart cherry juice increases melatonin levels, improving sleep efficiency and quality. Taking melatonin supplements has been demonstrated to improve circadian rhythms and alleviate sleeplessness.</p>
<h3>2. Kiwi</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Should we eat fruits at night? This natural sleep-inducing food will have you curled up under your cover in no time. A study published in the Asia Pacific Journal of Clinical Nutrition discovered that participants who ate two kiwifruits around 60 minutes before bedtime, every night, for 4 weeks, fell asleep 35% faster than those who didn't eat this fruit. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Additionally, it is a source of the mood-lifting hormone serotonin, found in abundance in this fruit due to its high antioxidant and carotenoid content. Low levels of this slumber hormone, associated with REM sleep (rapid eye movement), will lead to insomnia. As with kiwi, which is high in folate, one of the health problems related to a shortage in folate is sleeplessness.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">3. Almonds</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Almonds, cashews and peanuts are recommended as excellent night-time snacks. This is because of the high calcium content of almonds, which are a must-have in any flat-belly kitchen. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This duo's combined efforts help soothe the body and ease muscle tension. When calcium is ingested, it helps the brain convert tryptophan into sleep-promoting melatonin. </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">4. Chamomile Tea</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As a herbal tea, Chamomile may have many health advantages. The flavones in it are well known. Many chronic diseases are brought on by inflammation, which the flavone family of antioxidants works on to eradicate them from your system. It has also been shown to enhance your immune system, reduce anxiety and sadness, and improve your skin's health. Another reason to give chamomile tea a try is its sleep-inducing properties.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Apigenin is specifically found in chamomile tea. This antioxidant attaches to receptors in your brain that may help you fall asleep and stay asleep more easily by increasing your drowsiness and decreasing your sleeplessness. Sleep problems are often linked to depression, and individuals who drink chamomile tea are likely to experience less of it. Having this beverage before going to bed can help get a better night's sleep, so give it a shot.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">5. Fatty Fish</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It is good to eat fatty seafood like salmon, tuna and trout. Vitamin D is what sets them apart from the rest. For instance, Sockeye salmon has 570 IU or international units of vitamin D in a  serving of 85 grams. That's 70% of your DV or daily value. 81% is the daily farmed rainbow trout intake recommended. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Additionally, fatty fish are rich in omega-3 fatty acids, such as DHA and EPA, which are beneficial for the human body. EPA and DHA's anti-inflammatory properties have long been recognized. There's also evidence that omega-3 fatty acids can assist in improving cognitive function, as well as preventing heart disease. Vitamin D and Omega-3 fatty acids additionally are known to augment sleep quality by increasing serotonin synthesis. Both of them are found in fatty fish. </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">6. Walnuts</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Walnuts are kind of tree nuts that are widely consumed. A 28-gram serving of walnuts includes more than nineteen types of minerals and vitamins and approximately 1.9 grams of fibre. Manganese and copper are also found in abundance in walnuts.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Linoleic acid and omega-3 fatty acids which are found in high proportions in walnuts, make them an excellent source of fat. The 4.3 grams of protein in each ounce may also help to reduce hunger.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Walnuts help in improving cardiovascular health. Many studies have looked into their ability to reduce cholesterol, which is a major risk factor for heart disease. Walnut's fatty acid profile may also aid in the improvement of sleep quality. A host of foods items include omega-3 fatty acid alpha-linolenic acid (ALA), which is then processed by the body into DHA for brain and eye health. DHA may increase serotonin synthesis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">However, if you have trouble falling asleep, try munching on a few walnuts before going to bed. About a quarter of a cup of walnuts is the ideal serving size.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">7. Cereal with Low-Fat Milk</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As a night-time snack rather than breakfast, a combination of low-sugar cereal with skim milk is ideal. The sleep-inducing hormone serotonin is synthesised from the amino acid tryptophan, which is found in milk. On the contrary, whole milk with a higher fat content will take longer to digest, keeping you up instead of putting you to sleep. Hence, skim milk is preferable in such cases.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The time it takes to fall asleep can be reduced by half when you consume a high-glycemic carbohydrate such as jasmine rice (or rice cereal) 4 hours (240 minutes) before bed, as reported in the American Journal of Clinical Nutrition. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In other words, high-glycemic carbs can assist raise the ratio of tryptophan in your blood by diverting other amino acids to your muscles, which causes blood sugar and insulin to climb more quickly than with low-GI foods. You will be able to get more of the sedative into your brain since tryptophan is able to compete with the other amino acids for entry into your brain.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">8. Low-Fat Yoghurt Parfait</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Combine low-fat Greek yoghurt, honey and a banana for a tryptophan triple treat. Tryptophan is found in both yoghurt and bananas, and the carbs in the banana will aid in the absorption of the tryptophan-rich foods. Combine the yoghurt with some uncooked oats, which are an excellent source of tryptophan.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">9. Passionflower tea</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">How can a cup of tea not cure any ailment? At the very least, zero insomnia! Flavones, flavonoids and resins in many herbal teas have sedative properties. Flavone chrysin, which is a mild sedative and excellent anti-anxiety component, is present in passionflower tea. This helps you relax at night so you can get a good night's sleep.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">10. Cottage Cheese</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Your weight loss objectives may suffer if you completely forget about healthy late night <strong><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/collections/diet-nutrition">snacks for weight loss</a></strong> before going to sleep. To avoid going to sleep with a full stomach, try some cottage cheese. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It contains the amino acid tryptophan as well as casein protein, a slow-releasing milk protein that helps curb night-time hunger pangs. To get an extra dose of tryptophan (the amino acid present in chickpeas), mix it with hummus or guacamole, or eat it on its own.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;">Other Sleep-Inducing Foods and Beverages </h4>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">A wide variety of additional foods and beverages have been shown to aid in the process of falling asleep. Additionally, you might add a couple of <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/true-vitamin"><strong>multivitamin supplements</strong></a> like <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/deep-sea-fish-oil"><strong>omega-3 fish oil capsules</strong></a> to meet your daily nutritional requirements. </li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">As already mentioned high levels of the amino acid, tryptophan helps to raise serotonin and melatonin, which essentially assists in the sleeping process. However, in certain circumstances, little research has been done on the exact effects of these substances on sleep patterns.  </li>
</ul>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;">Some of the other sources of Tryptophan are: </h4>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<strong>Bananas:</strong> Found in the banana peels, Tryptophan has a number of benefits. The fruit itself does have a certain extent of magnesium. Both of them can be beneficial in improving sleep quality.  </li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<strong>Oatmeal:</strong> The carbohydrate content of oatmeal is similar to rice, but it has higher fibre content and has been demonstrated to produce a level of sleepiness if consumed prior to bedtime. Certain evidence even suggests that oats contain tryptophan and melatonin, which aid with sleep. </li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<strong>Dairy products:</strong>  Items like plain yoghurt, milk and cottage cheese have Tryptophan. Milk, along with modest exercise, is known to be helpful in providing better sleep to older individuals.  </li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Conclusion: Final Thoughts!</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Treating your sleep issues starts with figuring out what's causing them in the first place. Stress, noise or discomfort may be causing you to not get a good night's rest. Keeping a sleep journal is a great way to evaluate your sleeping habits and identify areas for improvement. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">You must often wonder about what food to eat at night? Even if you don't get a good night's sleep, what you consume during the day can keep you up at night. If you eat meals rich in sleep-inducing vitamins, minerals and nutrients, you will have no trouble drifting off to sleep at night.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/green-coffee-v-s-green-tea-which-is-better-for-losing-weight</id>
    <published>2022-04-06T18:14:45+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-04-06T18:14:45+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/green-coffee-v-s-green-tea-which-is-better-for-losing-weight"/>
    <title>Green Coffee V/S Green Tea: Which is Better for Losing Weight?</title>
    <author>
      <name>neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Anyone looking to shed a few pounds knows that there is no magic powder or a diet that can help them lose weight. To lose those extra kilos, you have to be consistent with your diet and exercise. Still, you can take a few things to support your weight loss by increasing your metabolism. Everyone who is trying to lose weight has heard about the benefits of drinking green tea. It is full of antioxidants that keep our body healthy and support weight loss. When it comes to warm drinks supporting weight loss, everyone always looks up to green tea. Brewing the water and adding it to a bag or using green leaves to make this drink is immensely helpful in losing weight.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">However, recently, one more drink is gaining momentum for weight loss support, and that is green coffee. Green coffee beans are said to possess more antioxidants and properties that can aid us in accomplishing our weight loss goals. Green coffee is unroasted coffee beans with higher content of chlorogenic acid, which is imperative for us to lose weight or lower cholesterol levels.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The question that many people have in their mind is- whether to drink green tea or green coffee to lose extra kilos? Is green coffee for weight loss an effective strategy? To get answers to these questions, let’s compare the two of them below.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Your Guide to Green Coffee- </strong></h3>
<p class="sort-description" style="text-align: justify;">Coffee is an incredible drink. This drink is best whether you drink it warm or cold. However, the regular coffee that we drink is not in its natural form. The brown colour of coffee beans comes after processing the natural coffee beans. The unprocessed coffee beans are <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/green-coffee-beans"><strong>green coffee</strong></a> which has better taste, aroma, colour and is high in nutrients too. Since it is raw, it is high in chlorogenic acid, which has more nutrients than regular coffee.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Green Coffee helps with weight loss</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It promotes weight loss as it has chlorogenic acid, which helps burn fat and glucose. It even prevents blood sugar from spiking, which keeps fat in control. When you consume green coffee regularly, you increase your metabolic rate, which can help with fat loss.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Green Coffee may prevent cancer</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">High content of free radicals in our body can lead to multiple diseases, like cancer. Antioxidants can help reduce the damage that free radicals cause to your body. Green coffee is said to have a high number of antioxidants and nutrients. It can help prevent the growth of tumours in your body.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Green Coffee reduces inflammation</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Green coffee for PCOS is a great thing because inflammation is one of the reasons for PCOS. Green coffee has anti-inflammatory properties that can help lower the inflammation helping you reverse PCOS. Also, the anti-inflammatory properties of green coffee help lower cholesterol levels.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Also Read: <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/women-health/8-best-protein-items-to-include-in-your-diet-for-pcos">8 Best Protein Items to Include in Your Diet for PCOS </a></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Green Coffee boosts mood and brain functions</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Since green coffee is rich in antioxidants, it can help with brain functions. Green coffee beans' benefits include enhancing cognitive performance &amp; psychomotor helping prevent Alzheimer’s disease. Caffeine helps release dopamine which helps uplift attention, mood, alertness, and other brain functions.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>How many cups of green coffee should you have?</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It is best to limit your intake of green coffee to two cups a day. Also, if you are drinking green tea and green coffee beans simultaneously, it is best to have one cup a day for each.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Green tea-Everything about this weight-loss support drink</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Green tea is a tea that uses Camellia Sinensis leaves and buds. It doesn’t undergo the same oxidation and withering process that oolong or black teas go through.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>It improves bone health</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Green tea can help improve your bone health by making your bones healthy and reducing your chances of osteoporosis.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>It can help oral health</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">When you drink green tea regularly, it can help with bad odour and improve oral hygiene. It has catechins that help improve the health of your mouth.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>It makes your heart healthy</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Heart issues are the leading cause of death. Thus, you need to take care of your diet and nutrition to make your heart healthy. Taking green tea is another way to make your heart healthy. Also, it can reduce the chances of stroke.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>It reduces inflammation</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Similar to green coffee, green tea has anti-inflammatory properties. Consuming it once a day can help reduce inflammation.</p>
<h5 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Types of green tea</strong></h5>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Green tea comes in multiple varieties, these three famous ones:</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">Sencha: The commonest green tea is Sencha, and it is also the most drinkable green tea. The leaves are steamed and rolled to create crude tea.</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">Matcha: Tencha, which is stone ground instantly before shipping is known as Matcha. You fully consume the leaves when you drink matcha. In Japan, people use matcha in savoury dishes as well.</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">Hojicha: To make Hojicha, you roast sencha or other green teas. It has a distinctive aroma and is also less bitter than other types of green tea.</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Shincha: It is the ‘new tea’ of the season. It has low contents of caffeine and catechins, making it perfect for someone who doesn’t like strong green tea.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Which is better? Green tea or green coffee?</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Green coffee beans for weight loss or green tea? To answer this question, we will compare some points similar to both these drinks.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Caffeine content</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It is the main point of comparison for both green tea and green coffee. The amount of caffeine in green coffee beans is 100 mg in a 250 ml cup of coffee. If you go green coffee capsule (supplements). The caffeine content is somewhere around 20-50 mg. Also, you can get green coffee that is decaf or has lower caffeine content. Just ensure that whichever you get, it is organic.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Green tea, on the other hand, has 35 mg of caffeine in the same cup. The caffeine content may differ based on the plant and the growing condition of the plant.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Verdict:</strong> If you need a higher boost of caffeine, green coffee is best. The caffeine will boost your mood, metabolism, and gain all the other green coffee beans benefits. However, for bedtime, always go with green tea or nothing with caffeine. Otherwise, your sleep patterns will suffer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Their taste</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Apart from their properties, green tea and green coffee vary in their taste too. Green tea is bitter and has a strong taste. Even though it is bitter, people drink it worldwide for better health. Green coffee has a milder and more herbal flavour. There is no bitter aftertaste, and you will actually like its taste.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Verdict:</strong> If you don’t like the bitter aftertaste of green tea, you should go for green coffee. It is milder than even black coffee. And its benefits are numerous.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Brewing methods</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Your brewing methods should be perfect, so that you can enjoy several benefits of both green tea and green coffee. The brewing method for both of them is different. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Green tea:</em>  You can either get tea leaves, powder, or a bag. To brew it, boil water and add it to a cup with a bag, leaves or powder. (Do strain the leaves)</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Green coffee:</em> If you have green coffee beans, grind them and add them to your cup. Pour hot water on it and mix it well. Alternatively, you can also use instant green coffee or green coffee powder.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Our verdict: Both are easy to brew, be it green coffee or green tea, choose any if brewing method is your preferred choice.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Better for weight loss: Green Tea V/S Green Coffee</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you look at the caffeine content, <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/green-coffee-beans-powder"><strong>green coffee powder</strong></a> has a high content of the same. The antioxidants and anti-inflammatory properties of both these drinks make them ideal drinks for weight loss. Yet, research shows that green coffee beans/powder/instant coffee is better at aiding weight loss. Why? Due to the presence of chlorogenic acid in green coffee, which speeds up your weight loss goals without worrying about following fad diets. (Though, you do need to work out along with a balanced meal). </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Our verdict:</strong> If you want to speed up your weight loss journey, start drinking green coffee in the morning. Green coffee beans' benefits are more than just weight loss.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">That doesn’t mean that you cannot consume green tea. You can take green tea during the day or at night. Or even switch it up because it too helps the weight loss journey.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Wrapping up, start your day with a hot cup of coffee brewed using instant green coffee or green beans. You don’t need to add any milk to this drink, and it works perfectly to increase your metabolic rate. Thus, drinking it before working out gives you the energy to complete your workout better. Green coffee for PCOS or cholesterol control is also perfect as it helps you get rid of inflammation and toxins, which leads to these diseases. Along with consuming green coffee beans, lead a healthy lifestyle. Proper rest, diet, and sleep routine are essential for a healthy life and to keep the weight off forever.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/what-are-the-signs-of-vitamin-b-deficiency-9-foods-rich-in-vitamin-b</id>
    <published>2022-02-25T17:32:28+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-02-25T17:32:30+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/what-are-the-signs-of-vitamin-b-deficiency-9-foods-rich-in-vitamin-b"/>
    <title>What Are the Signs of Vitamin B Deficiency? 9 Foods Rich in Vitamin-B</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do you know 8 nutrients come together to make the complex vitamin B? Incredible, right? Most people think that vitamin B is a single nutrient, but it consists of eight nutrients, and all of them have different functions and are essential for our body.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Vitamin B is a water-soluble nutrient, providing our body with multiple benefits. These benefits include:</strong></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Prevention of infection in the body</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cell growth</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The smooth functioning of nerves</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Good digestion</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Healthy appetite</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cardiovascular health</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Good energy levels</span></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>The eight nutrients that make up this complex vitamin B includes:</strong></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thiamine (B1)</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Riboflavin (B2)</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Niacin (B3)</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pantothenic acid (B5)</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pyridoxine (B6)</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Biotin (B7)</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Folate (B9)</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cobalamin (B12).</span></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Each of these nutrients is essential, and deficiency of any of one of them leads to different symptoms. The good news is sources of vitamin B are available with ease. With a balanced diet of fruits, grains, and vegetables, you can absorb all vitamin-B nutrients and lead a healthy life. Also, dietary supplements like true vitamins are perfect to fill any gaps your body has in vitamin B.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How do you know if you have a vitamin B deficiency? A blood test can tell you for sure, and to get that, here are a few signs to look out for in your body.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Signs of vitamin B deficiency</strong></h2>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Vitamin B12 deficiency signs</strong></h3>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Constipation</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Loss of appetite</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tingling and numbness in feet and hands</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fatigue</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Weakness</span></li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">
<span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span><strong>Vitamin B-6 deficiency signs</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span>
</h3>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nausea</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Confusion</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Depression</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Prone to infections</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dermatitis or skin rashes</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Anaemia</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Oral ulcers</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<span style="font-weight: 400;">Chapped lips</span> </li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">
<strong>Vitamin B9 deficiency signs</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> </span>
</h3>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Diarrhoea</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sore mouth</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">High chances of birth defect during pregnancy</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mood changes</span></li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><em><strong> Vitamin B7 deficiency signs</strong></em></h3>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Frizzy hair</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Conjunctivitis</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<span style="font-weight: 400;">Hair loss</span> </li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every vitamin B nutrient causes different symptoms if there is a deficiency of the same. Thus, it is best to discuss your symptoms with a doctor instead of self-dignosisng. With a proper diet and supplements, you can overcome this deficiency.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>9 Best sources of vitamin B</strong></h3>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>1. Whole grains like rice or millet</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whole grains are one of the best sources of vitamin B. It is rich in vitamins B1 and B2. These include whole wheat, barley, millets, and brown rice. The last three are, especially, high in vitamin B and should be part of your diet. Fortunately, these are also great for losing weight, so they can be part of most people’s diet.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The reason experts recommend you to eat more whole grains as refined grains have no nutrients. The processing of them removes most nutrients from white rice, bread, or pasta.</span></p>
<strong>2. Salmon</strong>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Salmon is a fatty fish that is rich in multiple vitamin B. It is a good source of vitamin B, including B1, B2, B5, B3, B6, and B12. It is also rich in omega-3 fatty acids, essential for heart health. Even pregnant women can consume this, as this fish has a low amount of mercury.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can include it in your salads or make a main course out of this delicious fish. Even tuna is a good source of vitamin B and a low-mercury option in fish.</span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>3. Leafy green vegetables</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you love vegetables, it is time to include them in your diet big time. Most leafy green vegetables are a good source of vitamin B9 or folate. These include spinach, turnips, romaine lettuce, and more. These also have other nutrients, so you can enjoy them raw or cooked to absorb all the nutrients.</span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>4. Eggs</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eggs are a breakfast staple in many countries and this protein-rich food is also high in vitamin B12, B2, and B5. To ensure you get the full benefits of eggs, take two large eggs and make a scramble or eat it after boiling.</span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>5. Avocados</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are not eating avocado once a week, you miss out on tons of nutrients. Firstly, avocados are a rich source of healthy fats, which your body needs. Furthermore, a cup full of an avocado provides you with so much vitamin B6 and B9 (folate). There are other benefits of avocados too, like they boost your health, mood, heart, and bone strength.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eat it as part of your salad, mix it in your smoothie, or enjoy it as a spread on your toast.</span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>6. Meat and poultry</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are non-vegetarian and have low vitamin-B levels, try to include more meat and poultry in your diet. Pork, chicken, turkey, beef, and so on are rich in multiple vitamin-B, like B12, B3, and B6.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, these are rich in zinc, protein, and other nutrients, providing you with benefits. Furthermore, you can tweak them to fit your diet recipes.</span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>7. Milk and other dairy products</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most dairy products, including milk, are rich in vitamin B12. Research shows that people absorb B12 better from milk and other dairy sources. These include yogurt or cottage cheese, or cheese. Remember that vegan yogurt is not a good source of vitamin B unless fortified.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Milk also has other vitamin B nutrients like B5, B2, and B1. One glass of milk per day can give you tons of nutrients. You can switch to low-calorie milk if you are trying to lose weight.</span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>8. Legumes</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Legume is a family of food that includes green peas, chickpeas, black beans, lentils, kidney beans, and more. Other than being a high source of protein, they are a rich source of folate or vitamin B9. Moreover, it is rich in multiple other vitamin B, making it a must in your daily rotation of meals.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are pregnant and have low levels of folate, do include these items after consulting with your doctor.</span></p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>9. Nutritional yeast</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nutritional yeast is inactive, so its use is restricted to adding flavours to multiple dishes. It is mostly fortified and is a good source of vitamin B.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vitamin-B is crucial for multiple health benefits, as we read above. Try to include many natural sources of vitamin B in your diet. Also, taking dietary supplements to increase your daily intake of vitamin B is not a bad idea. Talk to your doctor if you see any signs of deficiency and start working on resolving it with diet and supplements.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/why-is-eating-more-vitamin-c-rich-food-essential-for-you</id>
    <published>2022-02-25T16:50:49+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-03-21T15:35:07+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/why-is-eating-more-vitamin-c-rich-food-essential-for-you"/>
    <title>Why Is Eating More Vitamin C-rich Food Essential for You?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many of us start our day with a sip of amla juice or lemon water. We consider it detoxicating and full of nutrients, and we are pretty on point, as both of these are full of vitamin C. It is a nutrient that our body needs in abundance. A regular intake of vitamin C can make our body healthy and keep infections at bay.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Benefits of vitamin C like we find in lemon or amla juice or strawberries may not include helping you lose weight magically. But it sure supports our immune system and metabolism, which is essential for healthy weight loss and overall health.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vitamin C is an antioxidant, and unfortunately, our body does not make it. Thus, you need to take it through food or supplements. There is an abundant source of vitamin C in nature, like:</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Citrus fruits like oranges, lemon, and their juices</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Potatoes</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bell peppers</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Strawberries</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Broccoli</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Amla or amla juice. It is super rich in vitamin C, and you should consume it first thing every morning.</span></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why you should take vitamin C? Due to the benefits, it provides you. The same we are discussing below.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>It can help reduce the chances of chronic diseases-Take amla juice every day</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The benefits of vitamin C include reducing the body’s chances of contracting chronic diseases. Vitamin C is an antioxidant and is a molecule that fights free radicals in our body. When you take foods or supplements rich in vitamin C every day, you ensure that the number of free radicals in your body does not increase. Vitamin C helps fight inflammation, which is another reason why chronic diseases attack our body.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Starting your day with fresh amla juice is one way to include vitamin C in your diet. Also, amla juice is great for your hair.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Vitamin C is imperative for the synthesis of collagen-Use lemon in your meals</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Collagen is a protein necessary for the health of connective tissue, nails, hair, and skin. As we age, its production in our body slows. However, we can increase the same by increasing our intake of vitamin C.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">This antioxidant is necessary for our body to synthesize the production of collagen in our body. Thus, drink unsweetened lemon juice, it is refreshing, and your body also gets a good amount of vitamin C. Moreover, you can squeeze a lemon into your meals to take advantage of this fruit.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>It can help your skin stay healthy-Take triple immune C</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vitamin C can help your skin from sagging, both in its natural form and in topical cream or serum form. When you include vitamin C enriched foods and supplements like <span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/triple-immune-c" style="color: #167a62;"><strong>triple immune C</strong></a></span> in your diet, it helps collagen production. That helps skin from sagging and keeps it younger looking. Also, it helps your skin fight inflammation, which reduces the chances of acne.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, you can use vitamin C serums or cream tropically to ensure your skin has less pigmentation and is radiant. (Also, do a patch test to see if your skin reacts well to such serums or creams).</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>It may prevent your cold from getting serious-Eat potatoes or strawberries</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the record, the benefits of vitamin C do not include curing cold or common flu. The only thing that makes it better is rest and fluids. However, if you do not have a sore throat during your cold/flu, taking orange juice or lemon water or eating other vitamin-C-rich food can help you get better. It makes your body fight infection and ensures that your cold does not get serious. It prevents the chances of you getting pneumonia or lung infections.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you have a cold or flu, talk to your doctor about including vitamin C in food or taking a triple immune C supplement to get better fast.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>It increases your immune system-Take amla juice, oranges, lemon water</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the best benefits of vitamin C is its potential to increase the immune system. When you eat a decent amount of vitamin C-rich food (do not overeat), it can strengthen the immune system. It helps your body fight infections while reducing the chances of chronic disease.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, vitamin C helps build your immune system by reducing oxidative stress and decreasing tissue damage.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>It helps prevent eye damage-Take vitamin C supplement</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some studies show that a daily intake of 500 mg worth of vitamin C can protect your eyes. Not only does it reduce the chances of a person developing a cataract, but it can also help decrease the progression of AMD.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are thinking about taking vitamin C supplements for your eyes, do consult your doctor. It will ensure that you do not risk developing any other disease.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>It helps the brain function and reduces chances of stress-related disease-Do eat oranges every day</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Several studies claim that vitamin C can improve the cognitive functions of the brain. It also helps improve the functions of the brain's neurotransmitters, whose job is to send messages to the rest of the body. This antioxidant is said to improve both these functions.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, if you are stressed, your body depletes vitamin C fast, making you susceptible to illnesses. Thus, it is essential to increase your vitamin C intake to fight stress and other illnesses. The best thing to do is eat an orange or two every day. Oranges are also low in calories, making it a perfect snack.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vitamin C can help your body fight infection, amongst other things. Try adding natural food items like oranges or <span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/amla-juice" style="color: #167a62;"><strong>amla juice</strong></a></span> to your diet. Also, you can take vitamin C supplements like a triple-C immune booster to ensure you take the required daily amount. Do keep in mind that you do not overindulge in vitamin C as it can cause an upset stomach.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/proven-tips-for-better-sleep</id>
    <published>2022-02-05T17:56:37+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-02-05T18:14:48+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/proven-tips-for-better-sleep"/>
    <title>Can Ashwagandha Help You Sleep Naturally?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">How to sleep peacefully? Do you often wrestle with this question or go on the internet to find some tips to help you sleep peacefully? Yes? Then this blog is for you.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Everyone craves a peaceful sleep at night without popping in pills. However, for some people, it becomes challenging to sleep or sleep throughout the night. The reason for the same can be many. It can be menopause in women, which leads to insomnia. Or some other cause like pain or stress can keep you awake irrespective of your gender.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are continuously unable to sleep at night or are not getting proper sleep, it is cause for alarm. When you are sleep-deprived, you invite problems like hormonal imbalance, obesity, type 2 diabetes, and a weakened immune system. The last one means you will be attracting all menial infections into your body.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, sleep deprivation can cause emotional problems like mood disorder, stress, anxiety, irritability, and more. Thus, getting a good night’s sleep is essential. There are natural ways that can help you sleep better at night. You can even try the best foods to eat before bed to induce sleep, ensuring better health.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In this blog, we will learn about how to sleep better at night naturally? And also learn whether ashwagandha can help with sleep issues?</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Ashwagandha - Can it help you sleep better?</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ashwagandha is a natural herb with multiple benefits. In India, people use it for stress, anxiety, and many other ailments. Studies are suggesting that taking <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/ashwagandha-1000-plus" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>ashwagandha tablets</strong></a> can help you sleep better and improve the overall quality of your sleep. Why take ashwagandha?</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since it is a natural remedy, it does not have harmful side effects.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> It is available in the form of pills, powder, and tea.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It can help with insomnia.</span></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Consult a doctor if you have an underlying health condition or are pregnant.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>7 Tips for better sleep</strong></h2>
<h3><strong>1. Keep your body moving</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Being active throughout the day is your answer to how to sleep better at night naturally? When you work out or go for a walk or keep yourself active through any means, you promote the sleep hormone-melatonin. It helps you fall asleep quickly at night. Many research shows that people who work out at least four to five times a week fall asleep quickly and stay asleep throughout the night.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is best to get your body moving in the morning because a morning workout helps the natural circadian rhythm, helping you sleep better.</span></p>
<h3><strong>2. Create a soothing night-transition routine</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A transitioning night routine is something you do every night. It needs to be consistent. It ensures that starting the routine, sends a signal to your body that it is time to sleep. The routine does not need to be complex. It can, and should be simple, which you can do every night without fail.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For instance, try this routine of drinking a cup of warm milk or herbal tea followed by writing a journal or doing mediation. Or you can listen to soothing music and more. You should pick any routine that you can follow through.</span></p>
<h3><strong>3. Eat these best foods before bed for better sleep</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are certain best foods before bed that can promote sleep. When you eat or drink them before bed, it enhances the quality of sleep and even improves your circadian rhythm. These foods include:</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chamomile tea: It is rich in antioxidants, promoting sleep. Also, it can improve the quality of your sleep as well. Drink either the caffeinated version or the herbal one. Both of these can help promote sound sleep.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Warm milk: Drinking warm low-fat milk with turmeric or cinnamon or nuts (almonds or cashew) promotes sleep quality. It is because it has tryptophan, which can promote sleep, especially in adults.</span></p>
<h3><strong>4. Tune in to your body’s cycle of sleep</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are times at night when you feel sleepy. But you do not pay attention to them and keep yourself busy either with work or chores or something else. Then by the time, you get to bed, you feel wide-awake. Sounds relatable? If yes, then start sleeping at the time when you feel sleepy, whether it is 9 pm or 11 pm. This is your body’s way of telling you that it is time to sleep. If you do not listen to your body, then it will take you a long time to fall asleep again.</span></p>
<h3><strong>5. Avoid alcohol or coffee late at night</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Coffee is high in caffeine, and if it is something that keeps you awake and alert, do not drink it later than 4 pm. It takes more than 6 hours for caffeine to get out of your system. Thus, it can affect your sleep and disturb your circadian rhythm.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Similarly, having too many drinks at night can disturb your sleep pattern, leading to sleep apnea or disturbed sleep. Limit or avoid drinking alcohol late at night.</span></p>
<h3><strong>6. Make your bed comfortable</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">With WFH starting, several people use their beds as their office. It is not a good thing to do or watch TV while in bed. The bed should have only two purposes-sleep &amp; sex. Also, make the ambiance in your bedroom cozy so that sleep comes naturally to you. It means making it warm, darker, and soothing.</span></p>
<h3><strong>7. Use lavender to promote sleep</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Lavender is another herb that can promote sleep naturally. There are a few ways to use it, like:</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Adding lavender to water and spraying it on your bed before you climb into sleep</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ironing lavender petals to your sheet works too, as the scent promotes sleep.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use lavender essential oil and put it in a diffuser. The diffuser will spread the scent of lavender everywhere, enhancing sound &amp; quality sleep. </span></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wrapping up, these natural remedies work, but they are not a miracle worker. It will take time for them to work, you, however, have to be consistent in your efforts, and gradually sleep will come.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unless you do not have a choice but to take sleeping pills, try these natural tips. Also, include the best foods to have before bed to sleep peacefully.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/7-low-calorie-breakfast-ideas-to-start-your-morning</id>
    <published>2022-02-03T18:11:12+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-02-03T18:11:12+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/7-low-calorie-breakfast-ideas-to-start-your-morning"/>
    <title>7 Low-calorie Breakfast Ideas to Start Your Morning</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, this new year, you have decided to lose those extra pounds you gained over the holiday season. It is a good resolution and something you should keep up with. There is no time better than today to start being healthy and lose some weight as obesity leads to multiple chronic diseases. When trying to lose weight, the trick is to eat low-calorie breakfast and meals. A low-calorie breakfast means making a breakfast that is between 300- 450 calories. Also, ensure that you have a high-protein breakfast as it helps you build muscle and lose fat.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you work out for an hour or two, your body releases a lot of energy. To replenish it, breakfast is essential, and skipping it for diet culture is the worst thing to do. A low-calorie breakfast can help you maintain energy throughout the day without craving junk or sugar.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">All this can be too much, especially when you are going down this path for the first time. Determining a high-protein breakfast that is rich, healthy, yet delicious can be challenging. Therefore, to help you out, we are listing the best breakfast for weight loss that is both low-calorie and rich in protein.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>7 Low-calorie Breakfast Ideas</strong></h2>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Idea 1: Sprouts salad</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sprouts are versatile breakfast options. It is a high-protein breakfast that is also rich in fiber. It will keep you full for a long time. It has around 260 calories per bowl. So, you can even enjoy one and a half bowls. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Add sliced onions, tomatoes, chillies, and more to your sprouts with herbs &amp; spices to make them delicious.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Idea 2: Zucchini pancakes with instant oats</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Zucchini is rich in antioxidants and water, which can help your digestive system. Switch your morning sweet pancakes with savory zucchini pancakes, which are high in protein and a low-calorie breakfast option.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It will keep you full, help release energy slowly into your body,, and is quite delicious too.</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Add instant oats to grated zucchini to make it bind and more fulfilling. Add herbs, spices, onions, eggs, and anything you like to the mix. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The steps for making zucchini pancakes are similar to the sweet ones. Also, add a scoop of low-fat Greek yogurt for more protein and taste.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Idea 3: Moong dal chila or green gram lentil pancake</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pancakes or chilla are a staple breakfast dish in India. When you make pancakes out of moong dal or green gram lentils, it is one of the best breakfasts for weight loss. It is low in calories and high in protein, making it a perfect post and pre-workout meal. One moong-dal chila has only 128 calories.</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can make it rich by adding grated cottage cheese, carrot, onion, tomatoes, and more. Add spices to grated vegetables, and it will be a treat in your mouth.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eat this low-calorie breakfast with coconut or coriander dip, and it will be a perfect combination.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Ideas 4: Overnight rolled oats with strawberries or blueberries</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A low-calorie breakfast option that is soothing, comforting, and easy to make is overnight oats. We all know that oats are rich in fiber and protein. They are easy to digest as well and when you have them in breakfast, your craving for junk is less.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">To make this low-calorie breakfast also rich in protein, add chia seeds, nuts, milk (dairy or non-dairy), greek yogurt, and fresh servings of fruits. You can make oatmeal or twist it with overnight oats, which roughly have around 260 calories.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overnight oats can have many variations all depending on your taste.</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a jar, add <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/rolled-oats"><strong>rolled oats</strong></a>, greek yogurt, chia seeds, nuts of your choice, and a bit of milk. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mix well and store in the fridge. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the morning, add fresh blueberries or strawberries and enjoy this delicious breakfast with your morning coffee.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Idea 5: Smoked bagel with salmon</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A high-protein breakfast with only 314 calories is a smoked bagel with salmon. It is a super delicious and protein-rich meal making it another best breakfast for weight loss. </span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">To make it healthy and low in calories, switch refined bagels with a whole wheat bagels.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the filling, take low-fat cream cheese, smoked bagel, sprouts, and anything else you want. Enjoy it with a cup of hot espresso and feel energetic throughout the day.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Idea 6: Chia pudding</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most people grab a sandwich or just run out with coffee in hand in the mornings due to lack of time. Thus, eating something high in calories or nothing at all. With this low-calorie breakfast option, time is not an issue. All you need is 10 minutes, and your chia pudding is ready. Or you can make it overnight.</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/chia-seeds"><strong>Chia seeds</strong></a> are a superfood as it is rich in omega-3, fiber, and calcium. It is very healthy and fulfilling, and you can make it protein-rich too by adding nuts or protein powder. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you want to get more benefits, use a superfood mix, which is a mix of multiple seeds, to make this pudding.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just add chia seeds to the milk, and your pudding is ready. For more benefits, add protein powder, nuts, fresh fruits, and greek yogurt if you wish.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Idea 7: Scrambled egg/cottage cheese </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In India, people make an egg or paneer bhurji which is equivalent to a scrambled egg. If you are a vegetarian, you can substitute egg with cottage cheese or tofu.</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mix lots of vegetables and saute till you get the desired consistency. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eat it as it is or with whole wheat toast or make a sandwich out of the filling. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The total calorie is around 350 calories depending on what you add to the mix.</span></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">To lose weight, you have to be in a calorie deficit while working out. That does not mean that you eat only 1200 calories per day. It means whatever your daily calorie requirement is, you eat a bit less than that without starving yourself. To do this, starting your day with a high-protein breakfast is ideal. We hope these low-calorie breakfast options give your mornings a nice twist and your waist some fewer inches.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/want-a-healthy-heart-include-these-7-foods-for-a-healthy-cardiac-diet</id>
    <published>2022-02-03T18:00:54+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-02-03T18:00:54+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/want-a-healthy-heart-include-these-7-foods-for-a-healthy-cardiac-diet"/>
    <title>Want a Healthy Heart? Include These 7 Foods for a Healthy Cardiac Diet</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">No beauty shines brighter than a healthy heart-Parade</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">This quote is so true. If our heart is not healthy, we can only dream of living a healthy life. Every year, many people die of heart disease. People who get diagnosed with a heart issue, most of them die within five years of diagnosis. Thus, you must keep your heart healthy. Without a properly beating heart, it will not pump blood to other parts of the body. It can lead to other health issues.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">That is why it is so essential to keep your heart healthy. There are many ways to do it, and the first thing you can do with ease is change your diet. Several of us eat a diet rich in fat and grease, contributing to heart problems. It is time to switch to a cardiac diet to ensure our heart functions correctly.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">So which food is good for the heart? In this blog, we will list down the seven best food for the heart that everyone must eat. Try to include them in your diet while eating your favorite foods in moderation.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>7 food good for the heart to include in your diet</strong></h2>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>1. Fatty fish</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fatty fishes are rich in omega-3 fatty acids. There is numerous research showing how they benefit our heart health. These fishes like tuna or salmon can lower your risk of many heart diseases. Furthermore, they reduce blood sugar and cholesterol levels &amp; may aid in depression, all good for heart health.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Try adding <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/deep-sea-fish-oil"><strong>fish oil</strong></a> to your diet if you cannot include more seafood in your cardiac diet.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>2. Avocadoes</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Which fruit is best for the heart? The answer- Avacado. Yes, this green fruit is rich in monounsaturated fats. They are healthy for your heart. Including it as part of your cardiac diet will ensure lower levels of cholesterol and reduce the risk of heart disease. It is also rich in potassium, which you need to control blood pressure levels. A high blood pressure level can ruin your heart health.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, do enjoy an avocado whole wheat toast once a week in your breakfast.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>3. Whole grains</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Which food is best for the heart which you can eat daily? The group is known as whole grains. Most diets have some staple like rice or chapati or bread. When you eat them, ensure they are whole-grain and not refined. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It's because whole grains have bran, germ, and endosperm, making them highly nutritious and good for your heart. Wholegrain includes oats, whole wheat, rye, barley, buckwheat, <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/quinoa-seeds"><strong>quinoa seeds</strong></a>, and brown rice. They can protect your heart, so choose them carefully. Do not let multigrain fool you!</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>4. Asparagus</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Asparagus needs to be part of your cardiac diet. It is rich in folate, which ensures that the quantity of homocysteine, an amino acid, doesn't increase in your heart. It can lead to heart diseases like coronary artery disease.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>5. Lentils and legumes</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Increase your intake of legumes and lentils, like chickpeas or beans. They are rich in antioxidants, protein, &amp; fiber, making your heart healthy. They can also significantly decrease the number of LDL in your body, leading to a healthier heart.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>6. Berries</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Who doesn't love berries? Another answer to which fruit is best for the heart? All types of berries- strawberries, blueberries, raspberries, and more are good for your heart. They have antioxidants that can reduce oxidative stress and inflammation in the body leading to heart health.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>7. Seeds</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Seeds like <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/chia-seeds"><strong>chia seeds</strong></a> or <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/flax-seeds"><strong>flaxseeds</strong></a> are a good vegan source of omega-3 fatty acids. They also ensure less build-up of plaques in the arteries, thus, contributing to a healthy heart. Start sprinkling them in your morning oatmeal or smoothies.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Lifestyle changes for a healthy heart</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now that you know what food is good for the heart, it is time to look at some other things which can make your heart healthy. Following a cardiac diet is good, but top it off with these other healthy habits for a healthy heart.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Manage stress</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">We know that eating a cardiac diet, which is rich in fruits and vegetables is necessary for a healthy heart. However, a thing that we often overlook is stress. Some stress is good as it can help us be more productive and resilient. But when stress becomes chronic and unbearable, it can lead to many health problems.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unchecked stress can lead to chronic mental problems like anxiety and depression. Also, it affects your heart, making it weak and slowing its function of pumping blood to other organs. Thus, it becomes necessary to manage stress through yoga, meditation, journaling, or talking to a therapist.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Take your vitamins and minerals</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If your diet does not fulfill the nutrient requirement for your body, take true vitamins and mineral supplements. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Quit smoking</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Smoking can increase your chances of heart attack and heart disease. Thus, it becomes essential that you do not indulge in smoking, also a leading cause of lung cancer. Also, ensure that second-hand smoke doesn't get you. It means politely asking anyone who is smoking near you to move.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Limit alcohol</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Drinking in moderation can help your heart work better by a lot. Drinking too much will lead to heart problems and increase your risk of a heart attack. Cut your drink by one glass a day for better heart health.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Maintain a healthy weight</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Obesity can lead to many diseases, and one of them is heart disease. Ensure you maintain a healthy weight and reach that weight by following a proper diet and workout routine. No crash diets!</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Stay active</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Move, walk, or dance! Do any physical activity that makes you move as regularly exercising and staying active is good for your heart.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">With these tips, you can reduce your chances of heart disease. What food we eat matters, and when you provide your body with food good for the heart, it will live more and do its function properly. A healthy heart is necessary for a healthy life, and this cardiac diet with other subtle life changes can help you achieve this. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/7-benefits-of-quinoa-seeds-the-mother-of-all-grains</id>
    <published>2022-02-03T17:35:08+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-02-03T17:35:10+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/7-benefits-of-quinoa-seeds-the-mother-of-all-grains"/>
    <title>7 Benefits of Quinoa Seeds- the Mother of All Grains</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Quinoa is not a new thing. For eons, people in South America have been cultivating this grain. Inca and their descendants used to eat quinoa seeds as part of their staple diet. However, in recent times, quinoa is becoming quite prevalent as it is naturally gluten-free, and the benefits of quinoa are impressive.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you go out for a salad, you will find it challenging to get one that doesn't have cooked quinoa seeds in the salad. It is becoming so popular in many westernized countries that people replace their rice with quinoa seeds. Also, the benefits of quinoa for weight loss are ample too. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, if you are trying this seed for the first time, there may be confusion in your mind. You may wonder, is it another fad diet? Or does quinoa have some actual proven benefits? Happy to say, it is the latter, and in this blog, we are discussing the benefits of quinoa that you can enjoy.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>7 Benefits of quinoa seeds</strong></h2>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>1. Quinoa seeds are gluten-free</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the best benefits of <strong><a title="quinoa seeds" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/quinoa-seeds">quinoa seeds</a></strong> is that it is naturally free of gluten. Many people have celiac disease or are intolerant to gluten. For them, the alternative to gluten is corn or rice, or other gluten-free grains. Out of all available grains, quinoa is the best, as the benefits of quinoa exceed everything else. When you replace your white rice with quinoa, you are eating a dish that provides your body with protein, iron, fiber, and calcium. Thus, you eat a balanced dish that is also gluten-free.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, there are so many things that you can add to quinoa seeds to make them rich and delicious.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>2. It is a great source of plant-based protein and amino acids</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our body requires protein to function well and stay fit. It also needs nine essential amino acids for proper functioning, which the body does not make. Fortunately, quinoa has all nine amino acids and 8 grams worth of protein per 100 grams. It makes it a complete protein package that is also plant-based. Thus, the benefits of quinoa for weight loss are ample, as it keeps you full and retains muscle while losing fat.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>3. It has a low glycemic index value</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Foods with low GI value are better for your health as they do not raise your blood sugar levels. When you consume a food high in GI value, like sugar, it raises the blood sugar level extremely high quickly before falling. Thus, your energy levels are all haywire.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Benefits of quinoa include lasting energy due to low GI value, which is sustainable for your health.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>4. Quinoa has a high concentration of minerals</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Minerals like zinc, magnesium, and iron are essential for our bodies. When your diet doesn't have enough magnesium, you suffer from headaches, fatigue, insomnia, muscle cramps, diabetes, and more. An iron deficiency can lead to anemia and low levels of RBCs. Low RBC levels imply that your body will be slow in fighting infections.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fortunately, quinoa has enough minerals, especially iron and magnesium. When you eat quinoa daily, you get multiple benefits of quinoa for weight loss and maintaining a healthy body.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>5. It aids weight loss</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The benefits of quinoa for weight loss are multiple. As we mentioned above, it has high protein content, which keeps you full for a long time. Other than this, it has enough insoluble fiber, which can again increase the feeling of satiety in you. That is why many experts recommend eating quinoa for breakfast. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another benefit of this mother of all grain is its ability to increase metabolism. It, in turn, helps decrease food cravings and calorie intake, thus, supporting weight loss.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are a vegan or vegetarian, include quinoa seeds in your diet for better and quicker weight loss. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>6. It has anti-inflammatory properties and is high in antioxidants too</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Quinoa is a plant-based food rich in plant compounds known as flavonoids. Two of the flavonoids make the benefits of quinoa even richer. These plant-based compounds have anti-inflammatory properties, which works as antioxidants in our body. Thus, they support the body in fighting excessive free radicals. These free radicals can increase your chances of many chronic diseases, including cancer. Thus enjoying quinoa in a salad or the main course can give you more than just vitamins and minerals.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>7. It is a rich source of lysine</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For your skin, the benefits of quinoa seeds are impressive. It is one grain with a high amount of lysine, an amino acid. It is responsible for building carnitine, which most body cell requires for tissue repairing and growth.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It helps restore your skin, and vitamin B helps with dark spots and other signs of aging. Also, lysine helps store fat and burn it into energy, helping you stay active, alert, and energetic.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>How to eat quinoa seeds?</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the major benefits of quinoa seeds as per us is that you can cook them easily and in many forms. There are three types of quinoa seeds available- red, white, and black. All three cooks the same way: </span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Take 1 cup quinoa</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Take 2 cups of water and let the water come to a boil.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once it starts boiling, add quinoa to it and let it cook (just like rice).</span></li>
</ul>
<ol style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since quinoa is bland and a bit bitter, you can introduce many flavors to it to make it spicy and flavorsome. For instance, quinoa vegetable pulao is a great dish. Just make vegetable rice without the rice by replacing it with quinoa.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cooked quinoa even goes well with any salad you like, adding texture and nutrients along the way.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Replace your roti flour with quinoa flour to make chapati.</span></li>
</ol>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wrapping up, quinoa seeds are versatile. You can use them in the main course or salads. Or make quinoa oatmeal for weight loss or even make a protein bar for snacking. In any form, you will get the benefits of quinoa. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Note: introduce it gradually to your diet. Also, never eat it in massive quantities per day. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/want-a-healthy-heart-try-these-7-diet-tips-now</id>
    <published>2022-01-07T12:09:58+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-01-31T18:44:25+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/want-a-healthy-heart-try-these-7-diet-tips-now"/>
    <title>Want a Healthy Heart? Try These 7 Diet Tips Now!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The heart is an essential organ in our body. This organ pumps nutrients and oxygen throughout the body. It is responsible for keeping the body in good working conditions. It works non-stop, and we must work on keeping it healthy always.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Unfortunately, heart diseases known as cardiovascular diseases are becoming common amongst people. Even seemingly healthy people are dying of heart attacks, which is a cause for concern. Around the globe, heart disease is one of the major causes of death in both women and men. Thus, it is essential to keep your heart in good shape. Exercise and diet are the best way to do so. If you have any cardiovascular disease, it is critical to follow diet tips for a healthy heart. Along with the medications, diet is imperative.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Moreover, everyone should eat a variety of food that is good for their heart. A <strong>healthy heart diet</strong> along with exercise is necessary for everyone. Not sure what diet tips for a healthy heart to follow? Then read the excerpt below for ideas.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Top 7 Diet Tips For Healthy Heart!</h2>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>1. Limit your intake of sugar and salt</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">One of the <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/want-to-get-better-health-include-these-10-nuts-and-seeds-in-your-diet-then"><strong>best diet tips for a healthy heart</strong></a> is to lower the amount of salt (sodium) and sugar in your diet. When you eat too much of these, it can accumulate in your arteries. Thus, making the job of the heart harder, leading to other issues.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you suffer blood pressure problems, it is best to limit salt. Adding too much or too little salt can lead to problems. Never add table salt to any of your dishes. Use herbs or spices instead of salt for flavouring your food.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Also, remember that when you eat processed or canned food, the amount of sugar and salt in them is high. So, always read the labels when buying canned food especially.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>2. Limit unhealthy fats</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Eating trans or saturated fat increases your risk of coronary artery diseases and high blood pressure. It can clog your arteries and lead to stroke or heart attacks. Thus, ensure that you eat healthy fats like olive or canola oil, nuts, avocado, vegetable oil. Limit saturated fat and avoid trans-fat altogether. Most food items do not have trans-fat now due to legal reasons. Yet reading the labels is essential.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>3. Include nuts and seeds in your diet</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">There are many benefits of including <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/collections/diet-nutrition"><strong>nuts and seeds</strong></a> in your diet. If you want to follow one diet tip for a healthy heart, start with this as it is simple, and most people enjoy eating seeds or nuts. Here is what you can or should eat.</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li>
<strong>Walnuts:</strong> Walnut is high in fibre and omega-3 healthy fat, good for your heart health. Eat a handful of them every day. Or you can use walnut oil in your salads too.</li>
<li>
<strong>Sunflower seeds:</strong> These seeds are full of nutrients. <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/sunflower-seeds"><strong>Sunflower seeds</strong></a> have protein, omega-3 fatty acids, vitamins B1, B6, and E. it is also rich in other nutrients, thus reducing your risk of many diseases.</li>
<li>
<strong>Almonds:</strong> They are rich in fibre and can lower bad cholesterol levels in your body.</li>
<li>
<strong>Flaxseeds:</strong> <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/flax-seeds"><strong>Flax seeds</strong></a> are high in omega-3 fatty acids, phytochemicals, and fibre. Grind them to use on cereals or oatmeal.</li>
</ul>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>4. Eat fish</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Salmon and Tuna are two fishes that can keep your heart healthy as they are rich in omega-3 fatty acids. Salmon can even reduce inflammation in the body, which is a source of many illnesses. Make sure you add little oil to grill these fishes and use herbs to pack flavours in them. You Can also Take <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/deep-sea-fish-oil"><strong>Fish Oil Capsules</strong></a></span> For Healthy Heart.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>5. Eat tons of vegetables and fruits</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>One of the easiest diet tips for a healthy heart</strong> to follow is to increase daily intake of fruits and vegetables. When you increase their quantity, you make healthy eating choices. Use less oil and salt to absorb the nutrients they provide.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">All fresh fruits or vegetables work, even frozen or canned ones. The last one should have less sodium in it. If you see frozen fruit with tons of added sugar or vegetable gravy with lots of cream in it, avoid it for better heart health.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>6. Choose whole grains always</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Who doesn’t like to eat pasta or bread? But the white version of these is not good for your heart. Another diet tip for a healthy heart that all need to follow is choosing whole grains. Grains, like wheat or buckwheat or <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/rolled-oats"><strong>oats</strong></a> or millets. Eat pasta or bread made using these and enjoy your life while having a healthy heart.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>7. Indulge sometimes</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you are craving a chip or cake someday, go for it. Make sure you do not overindulge. But if you restrict yourself too much, it can derail you from following the diet tips for a healthy heart. Even when you indulge, keep in mind portion control to ensure you do not overeat or binge-eat anything.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">No one food can cure you magically of any ailment. However, eating a balanced diet including these foods will help your heart remain healthy. Also, keep stress at bay or manage it to ensure our heart doesn’t take too much burden and remains fit.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
