<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss.atom"/>
  <title>Neuherbs - Weight Management</title>
  <updated>2022-05-02T16:29:07+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Neuherbs</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/best-summer-recipes-for-weight-loss</id>
    <published>2022-05-02T16:29:07+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-05-02T16:29:07+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/best-summer-recipes-for-weight-loss"/>
    <title>Best Summer Recipes for Weight Loss</title>
    <author>
      <name>neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">One of the best ways to beat the heat and stay cool in the summer is through one’s diet. Your ideal summer diet for weight loss must not include fatty and greasy food and have more seasonal veggies, light meals and summer weight loss drinks to keep you cool. A perfect summer weight loss diet can keep you refreshed and energetic throughout the season. You can spruce up your diet by including veggies such as cucumber, bottle gourd, melons, squash and fruits such as litchis, mangoes and pineapples. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">You must also stay hydrated throughout the summer months. You can include cooling drinks and healthy smoothies in your summer weight loss diet that can rehydrate and provide your body with the much-needed vitamins and minerals. Pick seasonal veggies and fruits and toss up fresh salads, light curries and so on. You can try fresh fruit juices, interesting popsicles, sorbets and sugar free mango or jamun ice creams for desserts and drinks. Here we share with you the top summer recipes for weight loss that you can explore and make the most of the season.  </p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Best 15 Summer Recipes for Weight Loss In 2022</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Here are some refreshing summer recipes for weight loss that require minimum cooking. You can whip up satisfying, delicious meals as a part of your summer weight loss diet while staying cool. The ingredients in these recipes are summer-ready – greens, fruits, yogurts etc. </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">1. Coconut Water with malai</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Coconut water with malai or coconut meat is the perfect refreshing drink for a scorching summer day. This has a nice texture, different from any other juice you may have tasted. Coconut water with the meat has a pulpy texture and tingles your taste buds with its sweet flavour when served chilled. Refrigerate the coconut water first and then blend it with the malai right before serving. Try out this ideal summer weight loss drink that helps hydrate, recharge and maintain the electrolytes balance.   </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">2. Punjabi Lassi</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Punjabi lassi is not only refreshing but also satiating during the summer months. You must refrigerate the curds as soon as it sets to obtain a thick, luscious flavor that is perfect for dahi ki lassi. All you need is a little sugar and fresh curds to make this simple yet satisfying summer drink. The thick, sweet Punjabi lassi can be a meal by itself. Use chilled curd for the lassi or refrigerate until serving. You can add water to smoothen the lassi, skip the sugar and season it with saffron or cardamom as a unique healthier twist. </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">3. Fruit/Vegetable Salad with mint dressing</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This is a colorful, dynamic salad with all ingredients ideal for your weight loss diet. Chop up your favorite veggies such as lettuce, spinach, kale, carrots, cucumber, bell peppers, tomatoes etc. To it, add the fruits of your choice – be it apples, papaya, musk melon, watermelon etc. Then for a punchy flavour, top it up with mint dressing. For best results, grind up the mint dressing with a mortar-pestle coarsely. For extra tanginess, squeeze some lemon, and lo-behold, another healthy summer meal is ready. </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">4. Kale and Apple Salad</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Kale, a tastier version of cabbage, is a popular ingredient in salads worldwide. In India, you can get kale in supermarkets and specialty stores. The delicious Kale and Apple salad combine the unique flavour and texture of kale leaves with crunchy apple strips, melon seeds and shredded cabbage. A dressing of lemon and honey adds to the tanginess of the salad and offers a spectrum of flavors to your taste buds. A freshly tossed Kale and Apple salad is an ideal light meal option for the summer months.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">5. Palak Raita</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The palak raita is visually and gastronomically appealing as a summer treat. A bowl of palak raita with tomatoes and onions is simple, refreshing and offers a splash of healthy colors such as green and red. With no other masala flavor, the palak raita only needs onions, tomatoes and black salt for the flavor boost. Onions give it the extra crunch, while the tomatoes give it the tanginess. This raita is an awesome accompaniment to rotis and parathas when served chilled. </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">6. Curd Rice</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Just like khichdi is for Gujarat and rajma chawal is for Punjab, curd rice is the staple food for south India. A very simple dish made using the basic ingredients, curd, rice and aromatic seasoning, is comfort food and an ideal candidate for summer meals, especially during travel. Curd rice is the mandatory finish to every traditional south Indian spread. Cook and mash the rice thoroughly, add the curds, salt and mix well. Then temper it with mustard seeds, urad dal, green chilis and curry leaves for the added flavour. You can either serve the wholesome curd rice right away or chilled. Curd rice or dahi chawal can be accompanied by any pickle of your choice and is an ideal choice for a summer weight loss diet. </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">7. Nutella Mousse</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This quick and easy eggless Nutella mousse is bound to be a hit, especially during the summer season. This low-calorie vegetarian Nutella mousse with only 2 simple ingredients, Nutella and low fat whipped cream, is the perfect dessert for weight loss. In just a few minutes, you can whip up the Nutella mousse in a serving glass for parties or dinner get-togethers. With its creamy texture and hugely popular Nutella flavor, this dish is bound to be devoured by children and adults alike. </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">8. Sol Kadi</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Sol kadi is made from kokum and coconut milk. It helps relieve acidity, is a natural digestive, and helps cool down the stomach after spicy food. This summer drink originates from Maharashtra’s Konkan region and is a very popular health drink during the summer months.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">9. Watermelon Soup</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">What an innovative way to make watermelon a part of your summer diet for weight loss! Consume the most popular fruit of summer-the watermelon- spicy watermelon soup! Deseed the watermelon, puree it along with mint leaves and simmer it with ginger, garlic, and chili flakes. This spicy watermelon soup is best served chilled. You can also add ice cubes and a spoon of olive oil to this soup to boost the flavor.  </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">10. Stuffed Lauki</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Lauki is a popular summer vegetable but not all people like it due to its bland taste. Stuffed lauki is an interesting variation of this vegetable. Blanch the bottle guard, marinate in lemon, chilli, garam masala, stuff with cottage cheese, and bake. This is a tasty, wholesome and healthy summer dish enjoyed by all.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">11. Yellow Squash Spaghetti</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Give a “desi summer” twist to the evergreen Italian dish, Spaghetti, by combining it with yellow squash and bottle gourd. Cook the spaghetti, thinly shred the yellow squash and bottle gourd, stir in some green chillies, herbs, basil leaves, and sprinkle with some cheese. It’s a simple, healthy variation of spaghetti that will satiate the palette of both kids and adults.  </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">12. Mango Kulfi</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Summer is never complete without some indulgence in mangoes, and everyone loves the evergreen Indian dessert, kulfi. So what could be a better summer recipe for weight loss than mango kulfi? To make this delicious summer treat, blend together 1 cup of chopped mangoes and condensed milk. You can include light cream and season with cardamom or saffron. Pour into moulds and freeze for more than 6 hours until the kulfi sets. Enjoy chilled mango kulfi to beat the heat.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">13. Jamun Popsicles</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">You can get creative with the tarty summer fruit Jamun and turn it into pretty purple-hued popsicles to impress your guests. Easy, light on the waist, and a good way to cool down the body, these yummy popsicles are a great and light summer dessert. You can also sprinkle some chaat masala or black salt to get a desi twist.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">14. Mango smoothie</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The super creamy, lip-smacking mango smoothie recipe is one of the best smoothie recipes for weight loss India. This ultimate taste quencher is made with fresh mangoes and a handful of ingredients. Toss the mangoes, a banana, low-fat milk, and yoghurt into a blender, transfer it to a cup and sip away. </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">15. Blueberry cake with a healthy twist</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This blueberry cake recipe is amazing - it's light, fluffy, with a hint of lemon and lightly sweet. This magic blueberry cake is perfect for a light summer dessert or midday brunch. This is a non-indulgent cake with a healthy spin. Instead of rich butter, it is made with olive oil, yoghurt, and applesauce. You can mix the above with egg and add it to the flour and brown sugar. You can spread a layer of fresh blueberries for a lovely topping. Enjoy this guilt-free dessert any day of summer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Apart from the above best summer recipes for weight loss, include plenty of watermelons, cucumber, mint, green leafy vegetables, onions, lemonade, and celery in your summer diet for weight loss. You can also include <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/quinoa-seeds"><strong>quinoa seeds</strong></a> and <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/chia-seeds"><strong>chia seeds</strong></a> in your summer diet for weight loss and see quick results. Try your hand at any of the above innovative summer recipes for weight loss and create a sensational, healthy summer menu. Create a summer weight loss diet that is light on the stomach and perfect for a hot day. </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/top-10-low-carb-diet-for-weight-loss</id>
    <published>2022-05-02T15:46:38+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-05-02T15:57:54+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/top-10-low-carb-diet-for-weight-loss"/>
    <title>Top 10 Low Carb Diet for Weight Loss</title>
    <author>
      <name>neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Carbohydrates are one of the leading food types that the human body needs to work correctly. Carbs give the body the appropriate energy to do work and its daily activities. The body breaks down carbs to use them immediately or later. Unused carbs get stored in the muscles and liver of your body to be utilized later. However, if the body does not use these stored carbs, it converts them to fat stored in various body parts.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">One big reason for weight gain is the accumulation of these fats in our bodies that don't get burnt. This is why we are often recommended to switch to a low carb diet to help us reduce fat and lose weight, along with an exercise routine. A low carb diet plan puts a limit on the number of carbohydrates a person eats. They can now focus on eating more proteins, fruits and vegetables, and healthy fats as part of low carb food for vegetarians.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Below we discuss ten low carb foods that we can include in our schedule and healthily lose weight. These can be included in a low carb diet plan for vegetarians and you can walk your way towards health.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Best 10 Low Carb Diet for Weight Loss In 2022</h2>
<h3>1. Vegetables</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">A low carb diet veg plan essentially includes vegetables low in calories but rich in vitamins, minerals and other essential nutrients. In addition, green leafy vegetables are high in fibre and low in carbs, making them ideal for low carb diets. Some vegetables like bell peppers and capsicums are delicious low carb foods. They contain carotenoids, which are good antioxidants that reduce body inflammation and protect cholesterol and fats from oxidizing.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Tomatoes, onions, Brussel sprouts, cauliflowers, eggplants and cucumbers have fewer carbs and are good for health. Also, green leafy vegetables like Asparagus, Zucchini, avocados, green beans and spinach have fewer carbs. They can constitute a part of a healthy, fat-free and low carb diet plan for vegetarians.</p>
<h3>2. Cauliflower and Broccoli</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">For a low carb diet veg plan, Broccoli appears to be a true superfood that belongs to the cruciferous vegetable family. This vegetable family includes radishes, brussels sprouts, kale and cabbage. According to research, Broccoli may help reduce insulin resistance in people suffering from Type 2 Diabetes. Every serving of Broccoli contains 4 grams of carbs that are digestible. It also has a high content of vitamins.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Cabbage and lettuce are also low carb veggies with a lot of vitamins. If you take one cup of raw cabbage, finely chopped, roughly 90 grams of cabbage, it has 5 grams of carbs. Amazingly, 3 of those grams are fibre. Similarly, cauliflower is an excellent low carb vegetable. It’s extremely fit for keto diet cooking, with only 4% carbohydrate content. You can use these veggies in your low carb food for vegetarians.</p>
<h3>3. Nuts and seeds</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Nuts are a popular and very healthy source of vitamins and are loaded with essential nutrients. Walnuts, hazelnuts, pine nuts, almonds and even peanuts are rich sources of low-fat nutrients. Though peanuts are categorised under legumes, they're commonly considered nuts. So, you can include a handful of them in your daily low carb diet plan for vegetarians and enjoy them the same way as nuts.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Eating nuts promotes heart health and provides the body with its daily dose of low carbs. Along with whole nuts, nut butter is also a natural source of low carbs. For low carb diet veg, you can use them as an alternative to butter or oil. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">For example, almond butter is a nutritious type of butter made by grinding almonds into a paste. Peanut butter also falls in the same category. You can add natural nut butter to make low carb smoothies that provide heart-healthy fats and proteins. They can also be used as a low carb spread for fruits and crackers.</p>
<h3>4. Oils</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Based on general perception, people consider all oils as pure fat. They do not contain any carbohydrates. However, from a health perspective, some oils are better than others and can be used for cooking according to a low carb diet plan for vegetarians. For example, coconut oil is plant-based oil made from coconut flesh. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Similarly, olive oil is considered one of the healthiest oils available. It is made by pressing olives, which are naturally high-fat sources. Olive oil extracted from the olives on the first press is known as extra virgin olive oil, which is the least processed and highest in quality. Avocado oil, made from pressed avocados, is another excellent oil choice to be included in low carb diet veg meals.</p>
<h3>5. Fruits</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Many fruits contain high sugar content and therefore become automatically rich sources of carbohydrates compared to vegetables. But these sugars present in fruits in the form of sucrose, fructose and glucose serve a healthy purpose in the low carb diet plan for vegetarians when taken in appropriate amounts.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Some fruits, like watermelon, musk melons and cantaloupe, have higher water content and have fewer carbs in each serving. Fruits with high fibre content also have lesser absorbable carbohydrates or net carbs. Berries, like strawberries, blueberries, raspberries, avocados and peaches are also low in carbs and excellent sources of antioxidants and vitamin C. You can include them in your low carb diet veg plan. </p>
<h3>6. Green Coffee Beans</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">There has always been a debate about drinking black coffee or <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/green-coffee-beans"><strong>green coffee</strong></a>. Green coffee beans are known to assist in weight loss in the body. The regular coffee beans are thoroughly roasted to give coffee the actual flavour, and green coffee powder comes from unroasted green coffee beans. These green coffee beans are crushed to get the <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/green-coffee-beans-powder"><strong>green coffee powder</strong></a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Green coffee is known to possess antioxidants that enhance metabolism and also assist in weight loss. Green coffee beans are also necessary for blood sugar management and detoxification. They also help improve the body's insulin function, essential for maintaining sugar levels in the blood.</p>
<h3>7. Apple Cider Vinegar</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">We all know about the fantastic effects of <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/organic-apple-cider-vinegar-with-mother"><strong>apple cider vinegar</strong></a>. It can assist you in losing weight, reducing heartburn, improving digestion, and even has beneficial skin toning qualities. Especially for people on low carb diets, you can use apple cider vinegar to help you boost fat loss in your body.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">neuherbs Apple Cider Vinegar uses naturally fermented apple juice with mother enzymes and is the perfect component for your low carb diet.</p>
<h3>8. Eggs</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">While some vegetarians exclude eggs from their diet, many consider eggs an integral part of their diet. Eggs are the most popular constituents of low carb food for vegetarians and are immensely popular with people due to a variety of dishes being made from them. In your breakfast diet, you can include eggs in various forms, such as scrambled eggs, fried eggs, boiled eggs or just plain whole eggs. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Eggs are good sources of proteins and can promote weight loss and reduce insulin resistance when consumed daily. One large egg generally has a composition of less than 1 gram of carbs. It has less than 6 grams of protein, making it an ideal food product for a low carb diet. Eggs can help you reduce appetite, and thus you will consume less food and reduce your food intake.</p>
<h3>9. Unsweetened Dairy Products </h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Most of the time, we associate rich and creamy dairy products like milk, cheese, curd, butter and yoghurt to be rich foods. However, when consumed in the right amounts, they can make a perfect low carb food. The impact of dairy foods on a person differs from one person to another. While some people do pretty well consuming large amounts, others can only consume little to no dairy.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Many great dairy options can be taken as low carb food for vegetarians, such as whole-milk Greek yoghurt, cream, cheese and butter. Here, milk will be considered a nutritious whole food rich in fats, proteins and carbohydrates. Generally, milk fermented with bacteria has low carb content than non-fermented dairy.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Similarly, cheese is excellent low carb food. During the process of cheese making, milk is treated with bacteria that cause the lactose to be fermented into lactic acid. This process removes most of the carbs. The same is the case with yoghurt production.</p>
<h3>10. Low Carb Snacks</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">While low carb foods include vegetables, fruits, dairy products, eggs and lean meats, various snacks are tasty yet have less carb content. You can generally have three low carb meals, but to satiate your hunger cravings in between meals, you can have some healthy and low-carb snacks without the fear of disturbing your carb intake.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">You can always choose some fruits, such as apple slices or some berries, or full-fat yoghurt. Even a couple of hard-boiled eggs or cucumber slices and carrots with some peanut butter and a few nuts can function as excellent low carb snacks for mid-meal hunger pangs.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Summing Up</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you have made up your mind to go on a low carb diet for some time, it is always recommended as it gives your body a necessary break. You can utilise this opportunity to restrict your carb intake and avoid consuming foods such as pasta, bread and other processed foods. Any type of low carb food for vegetarians is high in proteins and fats and can cause weight loss and improve health.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/are-you-obese-or-overweight-6-illnesses-you-are-inviting-how-to-overcome-them</id>
    <published>2022-02-25T16:29:47+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-04-14T18:13:53+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/are-you-obese-or-overweight-6-illnesses-you-are-inviting-how-to-overcome-them"/>
    <title>Are You Obese or Overweight? 6 Illnesses You Are Inviting &amp; How to Overcome Them!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every other person you meet is struggling with extra weight. Isn't it? Having a few extra pounds is okay, sometimes all you need is to work out a bit more to lose those extra pounds. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">But if you are obese or overweight, you have an unhealthy amount of fat or an uneven distribution of the same. The risks of being overweight are severe health problems. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It can lead to inflammation in your body, hormones imbalance, and strain on organs &amp; muscles to work extra hard. All this leads to severe health issues.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>In this blog, we will talk about the risks of being overweight and few simple ways you can manage it.</strong></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Obesity leads to type-2 diabetes </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The risk of being overweight is type-2 diabetes. Stress and obesity cause increased blood sugar levels, leading to diabetes. It is a chronic disease that you can keep at bay with proper diet, moderate exercise, and managing stress. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once you have type-2 diabetes, your chances of contracting other diseases increases. This include:</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Nerve problems</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">kidney disease</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Heart problems, and more.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Obesity leads to high blood pressure</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another risk of being overweight is high blood pressure. The normal blood pressure is 120/80 (it may vary as per age and situation). If you are constantly getting higher blood pressure during checkups, you have hypertension. In this condition, blood flows through the vessel at a higher than normal pressure causing strain to your heart. It also leads to kidney problems and other health diseases. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also Read: <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/diet-tips-for-weight-loss"><strong>11 Diet Tips for Weight Loss You Must Know</strong></a></span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Obesity leads to depression (Instant green coffee can help!)</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you think that the risks of being overweight are limited to just physical ailments, you are wrong. Obesity has high links to major depressive episodes. People judge others who are overweight, and it can lead to guilt and more. Some people who are obese, are sad because of their weight and go into depression. It makes it challenging for them to lose weight as depression makes you not care about your body. You should take therapy, do moderate exercise and drink <span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/green-coffee-beans" style="color: #167a62;"><strong>green coffee</strong></a></span>. All of this can help with beating depression and obesity. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Why green coffee?</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well, it has caffeine and antioxidants. So, it helps boost metabolism, which is necessary for losing weight. Also, caffeine is known to relieve symptoms of mild depression. Thus, starting your day with green coffee and a healthy breakfast can help with both.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Obesity leads to heart problems</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another risk of obesity is heart disease. Anyone can get heart issues. Yet, when your weight is higher than normal, your risk of getting heart disease increases. Also, obesity leads to high blood pressure, an increase in LDL and blood sugar, and triglycerides levels. All this increases your chances of blocked arteries. It leads to severe heart problems and a risk of cardiac attack. Losing weight can make you less susceptible to heart problems.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Obesity can increase your risk of cancer</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cancer is a term everyone is afraid of, and rightly so. Even in remission, cancer can come back, and the treatment is harsh. There is no one cause for cancer, as experts are still trying to understand what causes it and more. However, obesity is one factor that can increase your risk of cancer. When you are overweight, your immune system and other organs are at risk. Thus, it increases your chances of getting some cancers like kidney or prostate cancer, cervix and uterus cancer, and more.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Obesity leads to complications in pregnancy</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are pregnant and overweight, you are at risk of developing multiple problems. It can lead to high blood pressure, heart issues, insulin increase, and more. It also leads to complications in pregnancy, like:</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Birth defects</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Miscarriage</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Premature birth</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Heavy bleeding after birth</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gestational diabetes</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still-birth and more.</span></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Women usually gain weight in pregnancy. It is okay to gain some weight. However, if you gain excess weight or are obese, you need to work out a plan to keep your weight in check. That is essential for a healthy you and baby.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>What causes obesity?</strong></h3>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Leading a sedentary lifestyle and not moving enough.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eating a lot of junk and sugar and ditching vegetables and fruits.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hereditary. Sometimes, obesity runs in family. However, with simple steps, you can avoid being overweight.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Certain medications can also lead to obesity</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, certain treatments like chemotherapy can lead to weight gain in some people.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hormonal issues are another reason for weight gain.</span></li>
</ul>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>How to manage obesity?</strong></h2>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Eat a balanced diet</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to beating obesity, your diet is of utmost importance. If you are not eating right, you will gain weight, and also your body will not absorb any nutrients you need. Here are a few tips to eat a balanced diet:</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eat tons of vegetables and fruits</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eat fatty fish, meat, and poultry</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ditch added sugar in your morning green coffee or tea</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Avoid high-fat milk</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Avoid drinking too many fruit juices. Cut back on sodas, even the diet ones.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Practice portion control</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fill up on lean protein</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cut back on alcohol and quit smoking</span></li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Workout and get moving</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Along with a proper diet, you also need to get your body moving. Without physical exercise, you cannot achieve proper weight loss. Starting with a 30-minute walk is a great start. You can also include:</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">HIIT</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cardio and strength training</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yoga and pilates</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jogging, swimming, dancing, and Zumba.</span></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">NOTE:</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mediation should also be part of your weight loss journey as it keeps your mind healthy, which is imperative for overall health.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong> Fat-burners</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are some natural items that you can add to your diet to burn fat better by increasing your metabolism. They are:</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Green coffee:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Unprocessed coffee beans have more chlorogenic which helps your metabolism. Thus, helping with fat loss.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong><span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/organic-apple-cider-vinegar-with-mother" style="color: #167a62;">Apple cider vinegar</a></span>: </strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">It has multiple properties that can help you burn fat faster. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wrapping up being overweight causes you to lose confidence. It also invites so many problems, as we read above. The risks of being overweight expand to your mental health as well. Thus, it is impertinent that you start working out, eat a balanced diet, and take care of your mental health. Together all these will help you stay fit, healthy, and happy. It may sound overwhelming, but start taking small steps, and you will be fine.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/7-mistakes-during-weight-loss-you-should-avoid</id>
    <published>2022-02-25T16:20:03+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-04-14T18:11:33+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/7-mistakes-during-weight-loss-you-should-avoid"/>
    <title>7 Mistakes During Weight Loss You Should Avoid</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Everyone wants to lose weight, and they eat clean while also working out five times a day. Yet, they do not see the numbers dipping on the scale. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why is this happening? What is the reason behind this? The reasons are unintentional mistakes during weight loss that we make like not reading the labels or overexercising and eating less. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even though we think we are making healthy choices, sometimes we are not! And these small mistakes can put a dent in our weight loss journey. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">But do not get disheartened! As with lifestyle changes, you can ensure that you are healthy and lose weight permanently.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In this blog, we will explore the multiple mistakes during weight loss that many people make. </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>7 Mistakes can hinder their weight loss journey.</strong></h2>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>1. Drinking coffee or juice with tons of sugar- Switch to green coffee</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do you love your morning <span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/green-coffee-beans" style="color: #167a62;"><strong>green coffee</strong></a></span> or latte? Yes! good! Coffee is great to boost your metabolism, helping you shed extra pounds. Also, it makes you energetic, and you exercise better. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, if your go-to coffee is from Starbucks or one with sugar and cream, it will not help you lose weight. These drinks have around 40grams of sugar. Also, if you consume beer, wine, soda, or fruit juices, it simply adds more sugar and calorie to your diet. This only increases your cravings.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The best thing is to drink water first thing in the morning. If you want to drink other beverages, switch to green coffee &amp; green tea. Also, drink black coffee or latte with low-fat milk and no sugar.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also Read: <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/try-these-5-easy-exercises-at-home-now">Want to Loose Weight at Home? Try These 5 Easy Exercises at Home Now!</a></span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>2. Focusing on scale-Switch to measuring inches with a tape</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you weigh yourself every day thrice a time, it is an obsession that you need to get over. Sometimes the scale does not tip, making you doubt why your healthy lifestyle is not helping you lose weight. The important thing to remember here is that there are several reasons why your scale is not tipping, like:</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You are gaining muscles and losing fat. In this case, the scale may not tip, but your clothes will tell you if you are losing weight.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You are stressed</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is water retention in the body due to hormonal changes leading to no changes in weight</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, the food and liquid you consume every day can make the measurement different.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Avoid this mistake during weight loss. Instead, use a measuring tape to check your waist size and other inches. It will give you a clear understanding of your weight loss.</span></li>
</ul>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>3. Skipping meals- switch to an eating schedule</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Several people skip meals to eat fewer calories a day, thinking it will help them lose weight. However, that only leads to them binge-eating at the next meal, leading to guilt and weight gain. Also, when you skip meals, it can lead to an increase in blood sugar, less metabolism, and more.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instead, make an eating schedule and follow that every day. Make sure you eat at the same time every day without skipping meals. Note: If you follow intermittent fasting, do it under the guidance of a licensed practitioner.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>4. Eating low-fat or diet food- Switch to healthy fats</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the biggest mistakes during weight loss that people make is to eat diet food or low-fat food. They believe that diet food or food with labels like low-fat is healthy can unintentionally hinder your weight loss journey. It is because these diet foods have hidden sugar which can lead to weight gain. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, low-fat food doesn’t mean that it has the good fat which your body needs. If the low-fat food has saturated or trans-fat, it is in no way healthy for your body. Thus, check labels and look for hidden sugar like sucrose and healthy fat like monu or polyunsaturated fat.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Switching to natural healthy fats can help you maintain weight. Try adding avocado to your diet or drink green coffee with a bit of ghee or coconut oil in it to start your day with healthy fats.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>5. Exercising too little or too much- switch to routine with strength training and cardio</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you restrict calories and do not exercise, you will not lose fat but will lose muscle mass.  It leads to a decrease in metabolic rate, which keeps you from losing weight. Similarly, if you over-exercise, your body may go under stress, and your hormones may suffer, leading to other health issues.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">To avoid this mistake during weight loss, exercise for 30 to 60 minutes at least four times a week. Also, include a variety of exercises like strength training, cardio, yoga, and walking to see the best results.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>6. Not sleeping well- switch to a consistent sleep routine</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you think sleep has nothing to do with weight gain, you are wrong. When you don’t sleep well or sleep for fewer hours, it can decrease the level of leptin hormone while increasing the level of ghrelin hormone.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It means that the hormone which tells your body that it's full is not working well, while the hunger hormone is overflowing. Thus, you eat more and also crave sugar and unhealthy fat. All this leads to an increase in your weight.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thus, sleeping well is essential. Aim for 7-8 hours per night and also maintain a consistent sleep schedule.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>7. Not eating enough protein or fiber- switch to a meal with a balanced portion of both</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you eat a meal high in carbs but low in protein and fiber, you will not lose weight. Protein and fiber help you lose weight by reducing your cravings, making you feel full, and helping build overall health and muscles.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, avoid this mistake during weight loss by adding fiber and protein to every meal. The everyday requirement may differ for everyone, so eat accordingly.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wrapping up losing weight is imperative for a healthy life. However, if you go about this wrongly, you will hurt your health more. So, remember these tips and avoid these mistakes during weight loss. Furthermore, take help from a nutritionist and trainer if necessary.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/diet-tips-for-weight-loss</id>
    <published>2022-02-25T15:52:58+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-03-21T16:25:05+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/diet-tips-for-weight-loss"/>
    <title>11 Diet Tips for Weight Loss You Must Know</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Everyone knows that weight loss is 80% diet and 20% exercise. Still, people focus more on their gym schedules and working out for hours on end, and focusing less and less on their diet. If they follow any diet tips for weight loss, it either doesn’t work for them or gives them only short-term goals.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The reason? People will follow any diet tips for weight loss that they come across. Just because a particular diet works for someone else doesn’t mean it can work for you. General diet tips for weight loss like drinking green coffee before working out or eating more protein are good. However, if you follow a crash diet like drinking only shakes because it helped someone lose a few pounds, then it is not correct.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thus, do your research, talk to a dietitian, and follow diet tips for weight loss that is sustainable for you in the long term. Following any crash diet that helps you lose 4-5 kg per month is tempting. However, it does not work for long, and your mental and physical health may suffer due to a restrictive diet.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Here are realistic diet tips for weight loss that experts recommend.</strong></h2>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Start your day with water</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Drinking water first thing in the morning is the <span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/easy-ways-to-weight-loss-from-plant-based-foods" style="color: #167a62;"><strong>best weight loss tips</strong></a></span>. It helps hydrate your body, which is thirsty from a long time. Also, it helps start your system and detox it. It is a myth that you need to add several things to your morning cup of water to help detoxify your body. All you need is some lukewarm water, and you are good.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Drink sugar-free green coffee</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">We understand the need to drink <span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/green-coffee-beans" style="color: #167a62;"><strong>green coffee</strong></a></span> first thing in the morning. It keeps us going, makes us productive, and even helps us perform better at the gym. However, if you add tons of sugar or cream to your green coffee, it defeats the purpose of drinking caffeine.  The antioxidants will help your body better if you drink it without any added sugar.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is better to drink it plain or with some milk if you prefer. On a similar note, ditch all drinks loaded with sugar like soda.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Do not give up on healthy</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When we are trying to lose weight, one of the diet tips for weight loss we follow is to cut down all fats. While cutting down on unhealthy fats like saturated or trans-fat is impeccable for your health. You do not have to cut down on healthy fats, the ones you find in olive oil, avocados, nuts, seeds, or ghee. They help you feel fuller, so you do not end up binge-eating.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Skipping breakfast is not ideal</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Skipping breakfast means missing out on tons of nutrients that your body needs. If you eat dinner at 6 pm, and you do not eat anything till 11 am, the next day, your body goes into stress mode. Also, it means that you will crave sugar/fat, and you will overeat at your next meal.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Do not skip reading food labels</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another great diet tip for weight loss is to read food labels. If you learn to read food labels, then you know what you are putting into your body. Also, you can figure out a way to add that food into your diet without increasing your daily food intake. Moreover, when you read food labels, you understand which food has hidden sugars or trans-fat, bad for your health.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Eat at the dining table</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">We often eat while watching TV or scrolling through social media. Some people also eat on their bed, which is never a great idea. These can distract you from what you are eating, making you consume more calories than what your body needs. Moreover, when you are distracted, you tend to eat faster and chew less, impacting your digestive system.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eat at the dining table, it also gives you a chance to eat around people who love you and have a memorable meal.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Cook your meals from scratch</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is nothing wrong with eating out, and if you are conscious about what you are eating, it can be healthy too. However, if you are trying to lose weight, make sure you cook most of your meals at home. When you cook from scratch, you control the ingredient, and you can even make a normal dish delicious and healthy. You learn so much when you start cooking your meals, that you will not feel like ordering in food.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Stop drinking in your calories</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">We tend to watch what we are eating to control our calories. However, you also need to check what you are drinking because drinks like sweetened coffees, flavoured water, or juices can be high in calories. They can also have a high amount of added sugar. So be mindful of what you are drinking and what you are eating.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Stop banning food from your diet</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">We see people banning a particular food or food group from their diet to lose weight. It is one of the worst diet tips for weight loss ever. Why? Simply because it makes you crave them more, and then sometimes you end-up binge-eating. Try to add your favorite foods to your diet smartly for overconsuming them later.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Say no to refined carbs</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Refined carbs are not good for your weight loss journey or health as they have no nutrients. Cut back on them and switch them up with complex carbs like quinoa or oats or barley or whole grains.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Don’t skimp on vegetables</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">People eat meats and dairy for protein to lose weight, leaving out vegetables. However, that is not an ideal thing to do, as vegetables provide you with tons of nutrients.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wrapping up, losing weight is never as easy as gaining weight. Thus, follow diet tips for weight loss that works for you. Also, never restrict any food group unless you are allergic. Work with a nutritionist to ensure your weight loss journey is healthy mentally and physically.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/try-these-5-easy-exercises-at-home-now</id>
    <published>2022-02-03T15:20:06+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-02-18T15:56:47+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/try-these-5-easy-exercises-at-home-now"/>
    <title>Want to Loose Weight at Home? Try These 5 Easy Exercises at Home Now!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>When it comes to losing weight, you get advice from multiple people, and all of these vary from person to person. But one thing that everyone agrees on is that exercise and diet are essential for weight loss.</p>
<p>To lose weight and maintain the correct weight for yourself, you have to focus 20% on exercise and 80% on your diet. The diet should contain a balanced meal and to lose weight, maintaining a calorie deficit is essential.</p>
<p>Thus, working on your diet is essential. But what about choosing the best exercises for weight loss? There is a lot of confusion while choosing the correct exercise to lose weight. It is especially challenging when trying to shed the extra weight at home.</p>
<p>The good thing is that there are multiple easy exercises for weight loss that do not require you to join any gym or heavy pieces of equipment. These weight-loss workouts require a willing person and ample space.</p>
<p>These are the only two requirements, and if you are intrigued by this, here are the best and easy exercises for weight loss at home that everyone should try. Also, know about the best fat-burning foods you should include in your diet.</p>
<h2>Try These 5 Easy Exercises at Home Now</h2>
<h3>Exercise 1: Skipping </h3>
<p>One of the best exercises for weight loss at home for you is to try skipping. Jumping rope involves your entire body. Thus, it is perfect to increase strength and metabolism while helping you burn calories. Depending upon your body type, you will get distinctive results. However, most people can burn around 1300 calories per hour. </p>
<p>Also, skipping pumps blood to your entire body as it makes your heart beat faster. It can also calm you down and help ease anxiety and depression in some people. <br>Also, sip a cup of <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/green-coffee-beans"><strong>green coffee</strong></a> before you start with your workout at home. It will increase your metabolism and pump you with energy to do your best. <br><strong>To do this, you need a jumping rope</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Stand on your yoga mat and keep your back straight, feet close, and hands to your side.</li>
<li>While jumping off the ground, let the rope pass underneath your feet and come back up.</li>
<li>Repeat the steps while also increasing your speed.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Exercise 2: Plank</h3>
Plank is one of the best exercises for weight loss. It is an effective workout that focuses on your entire body. Not only does it help you in losing weight and burning calories. But it also targets your body posture and most lungs, keeping them safe. It strengthens most of your muscles. The trick is to keep holding the plank pose for a long time. If you can keep holding it for long, it can provide you with better benefits. There are many variations, but the most standard one is apt for beginners. After working out, you need proper nutrition, which is high in protein and carbs. Chia seeds pudding is a great breakfast option. Light and full of nutrition.<br>
<h3>Exercise 3: Forward lunge and have green coffee</h3>
One exercise for weight loss that should be part of your weight-loss regime is the forward lunge. It is easy to perform at home, and you do not need any equipment, making it an apt workout for beginners. It not only tones your body but helps you strengthen your core as forward lunges also increase your muscle mass. It also helps your posture and body balance. To do this:<br>
<ul>
<li>Stand tall and keep your feet one inch apart</li>
<li>Keep your hands on your side. (You can also hold weight if you want to do it with equipment)</li>
<li>Take your right leg forward. Make sure your back is straight.</li>
<li>Now, lower your body till your back, and front leg makes a 90-degree angle.</li>
<li>Repeat with the left leg and do a repeat set of 2 and increase gradually.</li>
<li>Again, sip on green tea 30 minutes before a workout for energy.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Exercise 4: Push-ups or pull-ups </h3>
A popular workout that is one of the apt exercises for weight loss at home you can do. It pushes you away from the ground, making you exert energy in extreme, helping you burn calories. It works on larger muscles of the body while ensuring that your body is physically fit. It also helps you strengthen your core and build lean muscles. To do this:<br>
<ul>
<li>On your mat, place your hands facing forward. There should be a slight gap between the hands but not wider than your shoulder.</li>
<li>Your feet should be together or a bit apart as per your comfort level.</li>
<li>Bend the shoulders towards the ground as low as you can push up back upwards, straightening your arms.</li>
<li>Start with 2 repetitions of this and increase gradually.</li>
</ul>
<p>Having something before workouts is highly important for proper energy. Don't feel like having coffee or breakfast? Then, it is best to have a protein-rich laddu using flak seeds. For this, you can make a protein laddu using flax seeds, coconut flakes, jaggery or dates, and watermelon seeds along with some nuts. Eating one of these laddus every day will help you lose fat and not muscles.</p>
<h3>Exercise 5: Mountain climbers</h3>
<p>One of the most fun exercises for weight loss is mountain climbers. It is fun, but it will help you burn more fat. Also, it will pain a lot initially, but after a while, you will enjoy this workout. To do this:</p>
<ul>
<li>Go in the plank position, and raise your right leg towards your knees/</li>
<li>Do not raise your hips or allow the foot to hit the ground. Repeat with the left foot and continue till a minute and increase gradually.</li>
</ul>
After you work out, eat a protein-rich salad with a bit of organic apple cider vinegar spread on it. It will help cut the insulin that carbs have, making the salad even healthier for you.<br> <br><strong>Wrapping up</strong>, performing these exercises for weight loss at home will give you control over your life. To enjoy your life fully, being healthy is essential and working out along with eating a healthy balanced diet is the key. Try these easy exercises for weight loss at home and have a proper meal to fuel your body with the right nutrition.]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/how-to-lose-weight-without-dieting</id>
    <published>2022-01-10T17:08:26+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-03-21T18:26:25+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/how-to-lose-weight-without-dieting"/>
    <title>How to Lose Weight Without Dieting?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">We all know that to lose weight, exercise and dieting are essential. However, sticking to a conventional diet regime is not possible for everyone. Restrictive dieting, tracking every food you eat, maintaining a diary, and limiting foods you love can do the opposite. It may start playing games with you, and instead of eating less, you will eat mindlessly. Binge-eating not only leads you to gain weight but becomes unhealthy.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">To lose weight without dieting, you have to be in a calorie deficit and be physically active. For instance, according to your BMI, if your dietitian suggests you eat 2500 calories per day, then eat within this limit or 100 calories less. That is the best way to lose weight without putting your body through restrictive dieting. How can you do this? By following these efficient trips that will help you lose weight without dieting.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>10 Tips To lose weight without Dieting</strong></h2>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Tip 1: Take time while eating your meals</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">With our busy lives, most of us wolf down our food! Within five minutes, we finish our meals, which doesn't let our stomach tell our brain that it is full. When we eat too fast, we don't even savour what we are eating, thus, not feeling full or satisfied.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thus, it is best to take your time to eat. This way, you do not overeat as you savour each bite and feel full. The best way to do so is by setting a timer of 15-20 minutes. Also, do not watch TV or be on your phone when eating. Without distractions, you pay attention to what you are eating.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Tip 2: Consume green coffee</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Coffee has caffeine, which aids weight loss. Caffeine in coffee increases our metabolism, helping in burning fat. When it comes to consuming coffee, <span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/green-coffee-beans" style="color: #167a62;"><strong>green coffee</strong></a></span> is becoming popular in helping people lose weight without dieting in extremes.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #167a62;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/instant-green-coffee-premix" style="color: #167a62;"><strong>Instant green coffee</strong></a></span> has chlorogenic acid, which promotes the burning of fat while preventing the absorption of carbs. Even regular black coffee provides all these benefits, but consuming green coffee may be a better choice for people looking for the best ways to lose weight. Since it doesn't go through the roasting process, it is raw. It means that you get better benefits due to the high concentration of chlorogenic acid.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Type 3: Include protein in your diet</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Protein is essential for losing weight. If you are in a continuous calorie deficit and don't introduce proteins in your diet, you will start losing muscle weight. That is not ideal as it is not a healthy way to lose weight.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, if you want to lose weight without dieting conventionally, increase protein intake during every meal. It will provide nutrients and keep you full longer, so you do not feel hunger pangs. For example, eating a fruit bowl with yogurt is a better breakfast option. Since you are eating both carbs and proteins, you feel full and satisfied.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Tip 4: Sleep well</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sleep is necessary for your overall health. But do you know that when you sleep more, you can lose weight without dieting? When you replace idle activities with sleep at night, you do not binge-eat. Snacking is a culprit that can lead to weight loss. Also, when you do not sleep well at night, your hormones are whacked, and you tend to eat more.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Tip 5: Add more vegetables in your diet</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Try including more varieties of vegetables in all your meals. It ensures that you get multiple nutrients and eat more flavoursome food. You can cut down on bread or chapati, but eat at least two veggies at every meal.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, don't add butter or unhealthy fat to your veggies. Otherwise, you will gain weight instead of losing.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Tip 6: Do eat a bowl of soup </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Soups are tasty, aromatic, filling, and less in calories. Thus, they are one of the best ways of losing weight. Only remember to pick low-sodium soups also which are not creamy. When you include soup as an appetiser, you curb your appetite. Thus, you tend to eat less, which helps you lose weight.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Tip 7: Start working on managing stress </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stress is a part &amp; parcel of everyone’s life, and it can be good in a few situations. But chronic stress or stress that affects your daily life will lead to weight gain. When you are in a state of chronic stress, your hormones suffer, and your body releases too much cortisol &amp; glucocorticoids. It leads to weight gain and emotional eating. It is another factor contributing to gaining extra pounds. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Tip 8: Choose whole grains </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A simple way to lose weight without dieting is to add whole grains &amp; cut back on refined ones. Whole grains like oats, whole wheat, or barley are low in calories and fulfilling.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Tip 9: Say no to sugary drinks</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instead of gulping down a soda or sports drinks that are high in sugar, choose better options. Water with lemon or strawberry is a better choice. Or go for green coffee, kombucha, or iced tea for something refreshing. If you feel like drinking a soda, go for a no-sugar one. It has empty calories, but it is better than sugary sodas.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Tip 10: Cook at home</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The best tip to lose weight without dieting is to cook at home. Eating home-cooked meals and making them from scratch gives you control over the ingredients. SO, you can substitute unhealthy butter for better fats like ghee or mustard oil. Try this, and you will feel a change.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">We hope we answered your question about how to lose weight without dieting? The trick is to eat every nutrient group but within your daily calorie limit. Also, be active, and that doesn't require 2 hours of cardio or HIIT. Dancing, walking, swimming, and yoga too can help you lose weight. Lastly, do include fat-burning substances like instant green coffee in your diet. It will increase your metabolism to lose weight without dieting.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/effective-ways-to-lose-weight-with-indian-diet</id>
    <published>2022-01-07T15:27:39+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-01-07T15:27:39+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/effective-ways-to-lose-weight-with-indian-diet"/>
    <title>Effective Ways To Lose Weight With Indian Diet</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to shedding off a few pounds or losing weight to a specific number, there is no short of advice that guarantees results. Right? Every person you meet has diet tips or a ready diet plan for weight loss that they swear works like magic. Alas! There is no magic when it comes to losing weight. Why? Because losing weight is not the goal, the goal is to achieve and maintain that magic number on the scale to look your best and be healthy at the same time. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you are wondering what are the <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/easy-ways-to-weight-loss-from-plant-based-foods"><strong>best diet tips for a speedy weight loss</strong></a>, you have come to the right place. This will have</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tips that will help you in accelerating your weight loss effectively. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">We will list out food items that need to be part of your diet plan for weight loss.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are sharing Indian food, which is readily available in any Indian household. It is full of vegetables and fruits and can help you lose weight.</span></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is no strict diet here, only the right combinations of food, that will help your body absorb the right nutrition, accelerate metabolism and lose weight.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Intrigued? Read on then! </span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>The best Indian foods to include in your diet plan for weight loss</strong></h2>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Weight loss drinks</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Adding drinks to your weight loss diet plan is essential when it comes to losing weight. Not the sugary drinks! We are talking about drinks that can help boost your metabolism. Or help in removing toxins from your body. </span></p>
<h3><strong>Water for weight loss<br></strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The best drink for weight loss and removal of toxins from the body is water. Thus, make sure you drink one-two glasses of water after waking up. Drinking warm water is beneficial in the morning. You can also add a bit of lemon or lime or apple cider vinegar to it if it suits your taste buds. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Green coffee <br></strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/green-coffee-beans"><strong>Green coffee</strong></a>, like all other coffee, contains caffeine, which is rich in antioxidants. Along with this, it also has anti-inflammatory properties, which help fight chronic inflammation. Also, antioxidants help fight other diseases. When it comes to losing weight, green coffee helps enhance metabolism. It can aid your weight loss goals.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, drinking green coffee before a workout enhances your performance. Thus, it is a must for your weight loss diet. Try drinking it before a workout or in between meals. If you feel heartburn, take it with a fruit or a piece of toast. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Tea</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Green tea or Assam black tea is safe to drink and helps relieve stress. It also provides your body with antioxidants and energy. Avoid adding sugar to it. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Vegetables</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every diet chart for weight loss must have tons of vegetables in it. Every veggie offers different nutrients. Your body needs every one of them for building muscles and losing weight. Here are the must-haves- spinach, tomatoes, okra, onion, mushrooms, kale, broccoli, eggplant, and beans. </span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Fruits</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">A lot of people avoid eating fruit as they contain ‘sugar’. It is hilarious because it is natural sugar, which doesn’t harm your body. Sure, eating fruits within the limit is also essential. But make sure you eat a variety of fruit throughout the day. At breakfast, along with a protein dish, load up on apples or papaya or pomegranate. For snacks, take mango, berries, oranges, or kiwi.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Protein </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your body requires protein to build muscles. Thus, include cottage cheese (paneer) or tofu in your<a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/easy-ways-to-weight-loss-from-plant-based-foods"><strong> vegetarian Indian weight loss diet</strong></a>. Other veg sources of protein include dairy products or <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/want-to-get-better-health-include-these-10-nuts-and-seeds-in-your-diet-then"><strong>nuts &amp; seeds</strong></a>.</span></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Whole-grain foods </strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Carbs are not your enemies. The body needs it for energy and to feel full, along with healthy fats, like ghee or coconut milk, or sesame oil. When it comes to whole grains, include whole-grain bread or chapati. Or brown rice or millet or buckwheat to your <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/go-for-these-indian-breakfasts-for-weight-loss"><strong>diet chart for fast weight loss</strong></a>. </span></p>
<h2><strong>Diet tips for weight loss and other pieces of advice</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Eat lots of fiber</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fiber is a magic food, and if your fiber intake is good, you will lose weight and maintain it too. It is one of the best diet tips for fast weight loss, as fiber is essential for gut health. If your digestive system is proper, you feel good, and losing weight becomes easy. Include oats, salad, and other <strong>vegetables rich in fiber</strong>.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Take supplements</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If your body lacks any nutrients, losing weight can become a problem. For instance, if you have low-iron, you will be prone to injuries. Thus, lifting weights or working out can cause pain. Thus, taking iron supplements can help you. Talk to your doctor and take a test to know what supplements you need. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes, the food you eat is enough for this. However, sometimes it isn’t. For example, Vitamin B12 is found only in animal products, so you may need to take supplements for it. Also, try inch burn supplements. It is a natural, gluten-free product. It can help increase your metabolism and lose weight.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Say no to added-sugar</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Natural sugar that you find in vegetables and fruits is good for you. But drinks and foods with added sugar are unhealthy and make you gain weight. Food items like candy or cakes, or soda are unhealthy and a reason for obesity. Even your green coffee will become unhealthy if you add tons of sugar or whipped cream to it.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Eat mindfully</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Vegetables and fruits help you lose weight. It is true! However, if you eat them in excess, it can lead to issues. It is because binge-eating anything is bad. Thus, mindful eating is imperative. For this, avoid eating in front of the TV.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Walk, walk, walk</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is not a diet tip, but it should be part of your weight loss diet. Why? Because after eating, a 20-minutes’ walk can help you digest the food better. Also, being in nature or the outdoors is extremely helpful for your whole body and soul.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">To conclude, you have to focus on your diet to lose weight because 80% of weight loss depends on appropriate diet. Thus, follow these weight loss diet tips, and you will start losing weight healthily and naturally.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/benefits-of-green-coffee-beans-for-your-skin-hair-and-body</id>
    <published>2021-11-01T10:52:11+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-01-13T17:05:23+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/benefits-of-green-coffee-beans-for-your-skin-hair-and-body"/>
    <title>Benefits Of Green Coffee Beans For Your Skin, Hair, And Body</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p align="justify"><span style="font-weight: 500;">Nowadays people have started consuming green coffee to stay fit and healthy from the inside out. Also, it uplifts the mood of those who are under stress</span><span style="font-weight: 500;">.</span></p>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-weight: 500;"> </span><strong>Did you know?</strong> <span style="color: #000000; background-color: #d4eee2;"><a style="color: #000000;" title="Green coffee" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/green-coffee-beans">Green coffee</a></span> is an unroasted coffee bean that grows on a coffee plant called Coffee Arabica.   </p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><em><strong>These Unroasted Coffee Beans Are a Rich Source of Antioxidants and Therefore Have Plenty of Benefits When Compared to the Normal Roasted Coffee Beans.</strong></em> </span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><em><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0577/6162/8330/files/Green_Coffee_800x300.jpg?v=1636442860" alt=""></strong></span></em></p>
<p style="font-size: 19px;"><strong>Check Out The Benefits Of Green Coffee Beans:-</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<span style="font-weight: 400;">Green coffee beans comprise </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chlorogenic Acid</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that may increase the metabolism rate and may ensure faster weight reduction.</span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Green coffee beans are high in antioxidants that may reduce the damaging effects of radicals in our bodies.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Green coffee beans can control pointless food cravings and stop us from overeating.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Green coffee beans lower high sugar levels in the blood and may result in controlling Type 2 Diabetes.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Green coffee beans provide natural detoxification which cleanses the liver, making it free of toxins, bad cholesterol, unwanted fats, and so forth.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Green coffee beans have high degrees of antioxidants that may maintain healthful skin and reduce the appearance of wrinkles.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<span style="font-weight: 400;">Buy Green Coffee Beans</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, if taken on a regular basis, might help make hair stronger, far healthy and beautiful.</span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Green coffee beans contain fatty acids and esters which nourish skin and heal it from severe damage.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Consuming green coffee beans on a regular basis can reduce the level of low-density lipoprotein or bad cholesterol in our bodies.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Green coffee beans are also regarded as a terrific way to naturally heal dull and acne-prone skin.</span></li>
</ul>
<p style="font-size: 19px;"><strong>Know How To Prepare Green Coffee From Beans</strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #ff6666;"><strong>Step 1:</strong></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Soak the green coffee beans for some time in the water. You can increase the amount of water in a similar amount as the beans.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #ff6666;"><strong>Step 2:</strong></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Heat up this combination of soaked beans and water on the stove. After the first boil, simmer the mixture on low fire for 15 minutes. Stir and filter it.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #ff6666;"><strong>Step 3:</strong></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> What you presently have is concentrated and strong enough coffee to be consumed directly. You can add water to dilute the beverage.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #ff6666;"><strong>Step 4:</strong></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Pour yourself a cup of green coffee and enjoy!</span></p>
<p align="justify"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In case you have prepared a large amount of coffee using green coffee beans, you can store the rest in the fridge, which can be consumed within 3 days. </span>Add cardamom and different added substances to carry more taste to this wellbeing drink.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/easy-ways-to-weight-loss-from-plant-based-foods</id>
    <published>2021-10-30T16:55:08+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-01-13T17:18:44+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/easy-ways-to-weight-loss-from-plant-based-foods"/>
    <title>Easy Ways to Weight Loss from Plant-Based Foods</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most of those who look to lose weight either skip the meals or tend to cut the portions. Apart from that, there are so many suggestions to eat one particular food, which is effective weight loss. Well, the truth is there are few foods, which are packed with proteins. They also aid in boosting the metabolism to speed up calorie burning.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When trying to lose weight, skipping meals or cutting on certain nutrients is the worst advice. The best thing to do diet-wise is to follow a meal plan that makes you feel full while giving you the required nutrients. All that, under the required calorie intake for your weight goal.</span>  </p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;" text-align:=" justify="><span style="color: #127a61;"><em><strong>If you are looking for food items that are plant-based and help lose weight, look no further. Here we are sharing 10 plant-based foods to include in your meal plan to start losing weight now.</strong></em></span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
<p style="font-size: 19px;"><strong>Top 10 plant-based foods for Weight loss</strong> </p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>1. Oatmeal</strong></span></p>
<p>Oats are a rich protein source, also full of dietary fiber. It makes you feel fuller and digest slowly, helping you to control the cravings. A bowl of oatmeal with strawberries and some nuts would be an ideal breakfast choice for weight loss. Also, you can add a cup of rolled oats to your protein shakes for your post work out protein drink.</p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>2. Quinoa</strong></span></p>
<p>Another grain that is in high demand these days is Quinoa. The sturdy grain is the best breakfast cereal for now. It has the highest protein compared to all other breakfast cereals, also it has essential amino acids making it a complete protein. Quinoa has a low-glycemic index and is high in magnesium and iron.</p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>3. Green Coffee</strong></span></p>
<p><strong></strong>Many research studies indicated that <span style="color: #000000; background-color: #d4eee2;"><a style="color: #000000;" title="Green coffee" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/green-coffee-beans">Green coffee</a></span> has properties that could aid in weight loss. The naturally occurring elements like flavonoids and caffeine in green tea not only boost the metabolism rate but also increase the fat oxidation. So, make it a part of your diet if you want to lose weight right away.</p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>4. Salmon</strong></span></p>
<p><strong></strong>Salmon is full of nutrients and should compulsorily figure in any weight loss diet plans. It is full of omega-3 fatty acids, which are essential for weight loss. Fish and <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/deep-sea-fish-oil" style="background-color: #d9fedb;">fish oil</a> benefits for weight loss are proven beyond doubt. Salmon is also a rich source of vitamin D as well.</p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>5. Grapefruit</strong></span></p>
<p><strong></strong>The naturally occurring enzyme in Grapefruit called Activated Protein Kinase (AMP) is proven to be effective for weight loss. It enhances the body’s capacity to produce energy, thus boosting metabolism. Hence, it should be a must in every weight loss diet. If you want to weight loss then buy Green Coffee Extract.</p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>6. Avocado</strong></span></p>
<p><strong></strong>According to a research study published in the Journal of American Heart Association, Avocado reduced the LDL, bad cholesterol by a whopping 35 % compared to other diets. Also, it is low in calories and rich in micronutrients, which aid the weight loss process.</p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>7. Spinach</strong></span></p>
<p><strong></strong>Spinach, the thick green leafy vegetables, is a superfood for sure. It is crazy rich in vitamins and nutrients. It is also rich in iron, magnesium, and folate. Of course, it is also a rich source of antioxidants. Moreover, it is low in calories. Hence, it makes for the right choice for weight loss. Why? Because it kills the cravings by making you feel fuller for a longer time.</p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>8. Cabbage</strong></span></p>
<p><strong></strong>Cabbage is another low-calorie food that is recommended for weight loss. Belonging to the calciferous vegetable family, the cabbage has many disease- fighting properties, including cancer. The Cabbage Soup diet for weight loss is known all over.</p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>9. Yogurt</strong></span></p>
<p><strong><strong></strong></strong>Yogurt is a popular fermented milk product. The bacteria ferment the natural sugars in milk and convert the milk into yogurt. It is full of many essential nutrients, including calcium, vitamin B, phosphorus, and magnesium. It is the best probiotic for the gut as it helps replenish the good bacteria in the gut. Thus, promoting digestive health. It is helpful for weight loss as well.</p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>10. Whole eggs</strong></span></p>
<p><strong></strong>Eggs are complete foods, unlike many other foods. Eggs are nutrient-rich, have high-protein and very low on calories. Studies have been indicating that whole eggs are good for boosting metabolism. Also, eggs are very filling and the best bet to start your day.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/20-surprising-uses-for-apple-cider-vinegar</id>
    <published>2021-10-30T16:41:30+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T18:03:31+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/20-surprising-uses-for-apple-cider-vinegar"/>
    <title>20 Surprising Uses for Apple Cider Vinegar</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">From the past 5-6 years, science is coming up with the health benefits of interestingly Apple Cider Vinegar. But if we talk about ancient times, then it was always there as proven health and medical benefits.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">This age-old and antique ingredient has been used for various cooking and household purposes. Its usage not only benefits in lower blood sugar, cholesterol, and weight loss, but it's improvised version also helps in controlling symptoms of diabetes.</span></p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;" text-align:=" justify="><span style="color: #127a61;"><em><strong>It can also be used in all sorts of recipes, including salad dressings, soups, sauces, hot drinks and more.</strong></em></span></p>
<h2 style="font-size: 19px;"><strong>Here are the 20 Ways to use Apple Cider Vinegar.</strong></h2>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;">
<span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>1. To Lower Blood Sugar</strong></span> </h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="color: #3bbf4a;"><strong><span style="color: #000000; background-color: #d4eee2;"><a style="color: #000000;" title="Apple cider vinegar" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/collections/apple-cider-vinegar">Apple cider vinegar</a></span> </strong><span style="color: #000000;">is claimed to help diabetics control their blood sugar levels. Some studies have shown that consuming vinegar after a high-carb meal can improve insulin sensitivity by as much as 34% and reduce blood sugar levels significantly. </span><br><span style="color: #000000;">However, if you’re on medication for diabetes, you should check with your doctor before taking apple cider vinegar.</span></span></p>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>2. To Help You Feel Full</strong></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Apple cider vinegar is sometimes recommended as a weight loss aid. This is because it may help you feel full. <br>Some short-term studies have shown that consuming apple cider vinegar may help you eat fewer calories, lose weight and reduce belly fat. However, its long-term effects on weight loss are unknown and likely to be small unless other dietary and lifestyle changes are made.</span></p>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>3. To Preserve Food </strong></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just like other types of vinegar, apple cider vinegar is an effective preservative. In fact, people have used vinegar as a pickling agent to preserve foods for thousands of years. It works by making the food more acidic, which deactivates its enzymes and kills any bacteria in the food that may cause spoilage.</span></p>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>4. As a Deodorizer</strong></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Apple cider vinegar is known to have antibacterial properties. Because of this, it’s often claimed that apple cider vinegar can eliminate bad smells. There isn’t any research to back up these claims, but you can try it out by mixing apple cider vinegar with </span><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">water</span></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to make a deodorizing spray.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">This makes a natural alternative to odour neutralizers. You can also mix it with water and Epsom salts to make a foot soak, like this. This may help get rid of unwanted foot odour by killing off odour- causing bacteria.</span></p>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>5. To Make a Salad Vinaigrette</strong></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">One easy way to use </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">apple cider vinegar</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is to make a simple salad dressing. Homemade salad dressings can be much healthier for you than store-bought ones, and they’re often tastier, too. </span></p>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>6. To Make an All-Purpose Cleaner</strong> </span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Apple cider vinegar is often a popular choice for a natural alternative to commercial cleaning agents. This is because of its antibacterial properties. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mix 1 cup of water with half a cup of apple cider vinegar, and you’ll have a natural all-purpose cleaner.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, it’s worth noting that although vinegar such as apple cider vinegar can kill some bacteria, they aren’t as effective at killing harmful bacteria as commercial cleaning agents</span></p>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>7. To Soothe a Sore Throat</strong></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Apple cider vinegar is a popular home remedy for sore throats. It’s thought that its antibacterial properties could help kill off the bacteria that could be causing the problem. However, there is no evidence to support its use in this way. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you try this at home, make sure you mix the vinegar with water before gargling.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is because <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/organic-apple-cider-vinegar-with-mother"><strong>apple cider vinegar</strong></a> is very acidic and has been known to cause throat burns when consumed undiluted</span></p>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>8. As a Facial Toner</strong></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Anecdotally, apple cider vinegar is claimed to help remedy skin conditions and reduce the signs of ageing.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">As such, many people like to use apple cider vinegar to make a skin tonic. The general recipe is 1 part apple cider vinegar to 2 parts water. This is then applied to the skin using a cotton pad. However, if you have sensitive skin, you may want to make a more diluted solution.</span></p>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>9. To Trap Fruit Flies</strong></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fruit flies can be a pest. Interestingly, it’s really easy to use apple cider vinegar to make a cheap fruit fly trap.  Simply pour some apple cider vinegar into a cup, add a few drops of dish soap (so that any trapped flies sink) and you’re good to go.</span></p>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>10. To Boil Better Eggs </strong></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Adding vinegar to the water you use to boil or poach </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">eggs</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> can help you produce consistently good eggs. This is because the protein in egg whites firm up more quickly when exposed to a more acidic liquid</span></p>
<strong><strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you’re poaching eggs, you want the egg whites to firm up as quickly as possible so that the eggs keep their shape. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Using vinegar when boiling eggs can also speed up the coagulation, or clotting, of the egg whites. This can be useful if the shell cracks while the egg is being boiled.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></strong></strong>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>11. As a Marinade</strong></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another way to use apple cider vinegar when cooking is to make a marinade. In fact, apple cider vinegar is a popular ingredient in many steak marinades, as it gives the meat a nice sweet and sour flavour.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Combine it with wine, garlic, soy sauce, onion, and cayenne pepper to give your steak a delicious flavour.</span></p>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>12. To Wash Fruits and Vegetables</strong></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pesticide residue on fruits and vegetables can be a concern for many people. That’s why some people like to wash their fruits and vegetables in apple cider vinegar. The hope is that it’ll remove more of the chemical residues than water alone. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although it’s not entirely clear if it will remove more pesticides than simply washing with water, it may help kill any dangerous bacteria on food.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For example, washing foods in vinegar has been shown to remove dangerous bacteria like </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">E. coli</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Salmonella</span></i></p>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>13. To Clean Dentures</strong></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can also use apple cider vinegar to clean dentures. Although there’s no consensus on the best method to clean dentures, it’s thought that the residues justify by apple cider vinegar could be less harmful to the skin in your mouth than other cleaning agents</span></p>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>14. In the Bath</strong></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the same reasons people like using apple cider vinegar as a homemade facial toner, they also like using it in the bath. If you want to try it, add 1–2 cups of apple cider vinegar to your bathwater and enjoy a soak in your tub.</span></p>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>15. As a Hair Rinse</strong></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">An apple cider vinegar hair rinse is said to remove product build up, detangle and add shine to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">your hair</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Try mixing 1 part apple cider vinegar with 1 part water and pour the mixture over your hair. Leave it in for a few minutes before washing it out.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you have sensitive skin, then you should try doing this with a weaker dilution first, as the vinegar is quite acidic.</span></p>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>16. As a Dandruff Treatment</strong></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Massaging diluted apple cider vinegar into your scalp may help get rid of dandruff. It’s unclear how effective this is, but the theory is that the acid in the vinegar could help stop the growth of the fungus </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Malassezia</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which may contribute to dandruff.</span></p>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>17. In a Sauce</strong></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Apple cider vinegar can be a great ingredient for a tangy sauce for your food. Try adding it to tomato-based sauces to give them a fuller flavour.</span></p>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>18. In Soup</strong></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Adding vinegar to a soup can help bring its flavours to life. If your favourite homemade soup tastes a little bland, try adding a little vinegar to it at the end. Add it gradually until the soup tastes great.</span></p>
<h3 style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>19. As a Weed Killer</strong></span></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another great use for apple cider vinegar is as a homemade weed killer.  Spray undiluted vinegar on unwanted weeds in your garden to get rid of them. You can also try mixing it with soap and lemon juice to see if that makes it more effective. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Studies show that if you are using Apple Cider Vinegar in your diet in a specific amount, then it can manage your overall health problems. Although an excess of anything is injurious to health, if you keep a track on the dosage of Apple Cider Vinegar, then it can support your health in various ways.</span></p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>20. To Lower the Risk of Cancer</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> It’s often claimed that apple cider vinegar can help lower your risk of cancer.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In test-tube studies, vinegar has been shown to kill cancer cells Some observational studies, which can’t prove causation, have also linked consuming apple cider vinegar with a decreased risk of oesophageal cancer. However, other studies have linked it with an increased risk of bladder cancer</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Overall, there is insufficient evidence to make any claims regarding the effects of apple cider vinegar on the risk of cancer.</span></p>
<p style="color: #0e101a; background: transparent none repeat scroll 0% 0%; margin-top: 0pt; margin-bottom: 0pt; text-align: justify;"> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/top-5-myths-and-facts-about-carbohydrates</id>
    <published>2021-10-28T18:12:54+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-02-04T15:10:37+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/top-5-myths-and-facts-about-carbohydrates"/>
    <title>Top 5 Myths and Facts About Carbohydrates</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Carbohydrates are the body’s main source of energy. 1 gram of carb provides 4 kilo-calories. It gets converted into glucose &amp; released into the blood to provide energy in the body throughout the day.</p>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%; text-align: center;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>MYTHS</strong></span></td>
<td style="width: 50%; text-align: center;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>FACTS</strong></span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;">Carbohydrates are not good for health!</td>
<td style="width: 50%;">No! Carbs offer a richness of nutrients like vitamins and fiber.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;">Carbohydrates make you fat!</td>
<td style="width: 50%;">No! Carbs are perfect for weight control. It reduces calorie intake due to its fiber content.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;">There’s Too Much Sugar in Carbs!</td>
<td style="width: 50%;">No! Stick to the natural sugars in fruits rather than adding sugar and using processed white foodstuff.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;">Every Carb Has Gluten!</td>
<td style="width: 50%;">No! There are some gluten-free grains such as quinoa, amaranth, and brown rice. Vegetables, fruits, and legumes also are gluten-free.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="width: 50%;">Don’t Eat Carbs Before Exercise!</td>
<td style="width: 50%;">No! It’s all about timing and the type of carbs you choose to consume. It provides immediate energy and improves performance.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p> </p>
<p style="font-size: 19px;" text-align:=" justify="><span style="color: #000000;"><em><strong>Explore more myths about your food…</strong></em></span></p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>All White Foods Are Unhealthy  </strong></span></p>
<p style="font-size: 13px;">Moderation is the key, white foods can be part of a healthy diet if taken in a limited quantity </p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>Only Bread and Grains Contain Carbs  </strong></span></p>
<p style="font-size: 13px;">Other than bread and grains, nutritious whole fruit, starchy vegetables, rice, and cereals also contain carbs.</p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>Low-Carb Diets Are Healthier</strong></span></p>
<p>They help to maintain weight and are optimal for human health.</p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>Carbs Cause Inflammation</strong></span></p>
<p>It is not a rapid process. A diet full of too much added sugar for a longer period can be a risk factor for inflammation in the body.</p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>Avoid Fruits Due to it's High Sugar Content</strong></span></p>
<p>Fruits contain natural sugar along with good fiber and water content.</p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>Sugar-Free = Carb - Free</strong></span></p>
<p>Sugar-free foods are not carbohydrate-free foods. They can still raise blood sugars, especially when eaten in excess.</p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>All Carbs Are the Same No Matter Where They Come From</strong></span></p>
<p>All seem pretty much alike, but they are not the same or equal. Whole carbs are unprocessed and contain more fiber. However, refined carbs have been processed and had the natural fiber stripped out.</p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>All Simple Carbs Are Bad; All Complex Carbs Are Good</strong></span></p>
<p>Moderation is the key, white foods can be part of a <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/looking-for-energy-boosting-snacks-for-work-try-these-8-healthy-munchies">healthy diet</a>. Only if taken in a limited quantity.</p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>Conclusion:</strong></span></p>
Carbohydrates are essential for your body. They are the source of energy. So avoiding them completely will make you sick. Talk to your dietitian to add carbs to your diet mindfully.]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/go-for-these-indian-breakfasts-for-weight-loss</id>
    <published>2021-10-19T13:08:11+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-01-19T18:26:13+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/go-for-these-indian-breakfasts-for-weight-loss"/>
    <title>Trying to Lose Weight? Then Try These Indian Breakfasts Now!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;">Breakfast, as the name suggests, is a meal we take to break nearly 10 to 12 hrs of fasting overnight. As it is the first meal, we should consume a healthy breakfast. It should be fulfilling and have essential nutrition that prepares us for the whole day. Also, it is the best time to give our body protein, fiber, and complex carbohydrates to keep the cravings at bay. It is a compulsory meal for all and a must for people trying to lose weight.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Skipping breakfast for <span style="color: #2d8b0d;"><span style="color: #000000; background-color: #d4eee2;"><a style="color: #000000;" title="Green coffee" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/collections/weight-management">Weight Loss</a></span> <span style="color: #000000;">is a blunder many people make every day. They think they are cutting calories, but it backfires. Yes! It backfires every time. </span></span></p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><em><strong>The ideal healthy breakfast should pack some protein, fiber, and carbohydrates.</strong></em> </span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="color: #2d8b0d;"><span style="color: #000000;"> In India, we have a wide variety of breakfast recipes from north to south India. Most breakfasts are best suited to a specific region. However, people trying to shed a few kilos need to be careful about their breakfast choices.</span></span></p>
<p style="font-size: 19px;"><strong>Here are Top 6 Healthy Indian Breakfast Recipes for Weight Loss</strong></p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong> <span style="color: #127a61;">1. Stuffed Paratha</span></strong></h3>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<p style="text-align: left;">Paratha, specifically stuffed paratha, is savored in the northern region of India everyday morning.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">From Punjab to Bihar, you find many varieties of parathas, particularly as a healthy breakfast dish. Paratha made with whole wheat flour or multigrain atta can be a powerful source of protein and fiber.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Also, you can stuff the paratha with many fresh vegetables. They are rich in protein, like green peas, cauliflower, radish, etc. You can also add cottage cheese. Instead of using oils and butter, parathas can be made healthy by adding ghee, a healthy fat, for weight loss.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong> <span style="color: #127a61;">2. Poha</span></strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;">Poha is a popular breakfast item in the western region of India. Also, it is an equally famous breakfast meal all through India, including South India. The best thing about poha is, you can add anything you desire to the dish. The taste will only enhance with every little tweak you make.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Depending on the diet and calorie requirement, you can tweak this a little bit. Add a lot of fresh vegetables like carrots, beans to the poha.  Also, increase the protein intake by adding roasted peanuts or soaked chana dal. Lastly, garnish with some herbs, like coriander, if you wish for more flavor.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong> <span style="color: #127a61;">3. Khichdi</span></strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;">Khichdi is another healthy breakfast, which people consume all over the nation. Cook it with either the leftover rice from the previous night or cook fresh rice. When freshly cooked, you can use brown rice instead of white rice.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Also, You can use millets, also known as ancient grains, as a replacement for rice. Again, do not forget to add as many fresh vegetables as you can to make it more nutrient-rich.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong> <span style="color: #127a61;">4. Chana Dal</span></strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;">Another item to consume for breakfast is Chana dal. To be precise, chana dal is a better choice for breakfast as it is sumptuous and fulfilling.</p>
<p>Overnight soaked chana is best as a side dish for breakfast. It improves the protein value. Also, if you want to eat it as a stand-alone item, it will work too.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Boil, soak and saturate with healthy fats and many vegetables to improve the fiber content in it. Also, add peanuts to boost your protein intake further. It is the best weight loss breakfast choice which is low in calories too, but not in nutrients.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong> <span style="color: #127a61;">5. Whole wheat toast with peanut butter</span></strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;">Bread is a popular healthy breakfast choice in India. Of course, it’s full of carbs, but not all carbs are bad, and they help you feel full. Use whole-wheat bread and multigrain bread. They are healthy choices and aid in weight loss.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">To cover up the lack of protein, you can add peanut butter instead of bread spread or butter. To further enhance the nutrient value, top the slice with banana pieces.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: left;"><strong> <span style="color: #127a61;">6. Porridge</span></strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: left;">Porridge is almost an Indian breakfast now. Of course, oatmeal porridge is one of the best breakfasts anywhere in the world. Particularly, porridge with milk is children's favorite breakfast. As is the case with India, we turn porridge into masala oats to enjoy a hot and spicy breakfast.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="background-color: #ffe1e1;"><strong>Conclusion:</strong> Breakfast is essential. Period! If you skip it, you end up binge-eating later in the day. Thus, it is best to eat a fulfilling breakfast and use the above healthy ideas to start your journey.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/3-proven-ways-to-lose-weight-quickly-in-7-days</id>
    <published>2021-10-06T14:00:00+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-01-13T18:33:23+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/3-proven-ways-to-lose-weight-quickly-in-7-days"/>
    <title>3 Proven Ways to Lose Weight Quickly in 7 Days</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Obesity is usually a result of lifestyle. Fat body or body fat does not look good at all. If you adopt only three habits daily, then you can lose weight fast in a few days.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are many ways to lose weight fast. But always choose the healthy way. Here we are talking about including some things in your daily diet that help in rapid weight loss. Home remedies for weight loss are dependent on a balanced, healthy diet and foods.</span></p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><em><strong>The biggest principle of reducing fat is to spend the same amount of calories you consume. Intrigue, what measures can help you lose weight in only seven days? Then, continue reading.</strong></em></span></p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><strong>These Are Three Surefire Measures Which Will Help You Lose Weight Fast!</strong></p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>1. Change your eating pattern</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Want to become lean fast</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or reduce obesity within a week? Then changing your daily routine is </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">necessary.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> You will have to change your eating habits. Our body feels what we eat.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Avoid </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">eating the type of food that has more sugar and calories. For example, baked goods, fried foods, and sweet beverages should </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">not be part of your</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> diet. There is too much fat in these things, which increases obesity.</span></p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>2. Have Green Coffee</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Healthy diet food is needed to reduce fat. There is also a need for foods that can improve metabolism. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Green coffee is perhaps the best drink to have in winters that supports weight loss. It is because it:</span></p>
<ul style="text-align: left;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Boosts your metabolism</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Improves blood circulation</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Burns fat</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Decreases the absorption of sugars</span></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The best method is to drink <span style="color: #2d8b0d;"><span style="color: #000000; background-color: #d4eee2;"><a style="color: #000000;" title="green coffee" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/green-coffee-beans">green coffee</a></span> <span style="color: #000000;"> daily, as<span style="font-weight: 400;"> it has</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> chlorogenic acid. It cuts fat fast. Thus, making your fat loss journey easier. You will feel lighter and better with everyday usage. Green Coffee Beans for Weight Loss.</span></span></span></span></p>
<p style="font-size: 17px;"><span style="color: #127a61;"><strong>3. Use Apple Cider Vinegar</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When we talk about fast weight loss, the name apple vinegar or apple cider vinegar comes first. <strong>Apple cider vinegar helps burn body fat</strong>. If you consume a spoonful of apple cider vinegar in a glass of water, it will aid in weight loss. To lose weight fast, consuming one spoon of honey with apple cider vinegar is more beneficial.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Consuming Apple Cider Vinegar helps to:</strong></p>
<ul style="text-align: left;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Manage blood sugar levels</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Manage weight</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Detoxifies body</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Manage cholesterol levels and heart health</span></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Want to give this 3-step proven method to lose weight a try? Then try this </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">unique solution for weight loss.</span></p>
<em><em><strong><strong>Check out the solution for weight loss by Neuherbs!</strong></strong></em></em>
<ul style="text-align: left;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Helps remove body sludge toxins.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Supports a healthy immune system.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Relieves muscle pain from exercise.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Helps soothe dry throat.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Is without preservatives, gluten &amp; added sugar.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Boost metabolism and immunity for faster weight loss.</span></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">To conclude, no one benefits from obesity. If you do not have any underlying cause, you can reduce fat with simple lifestyle changes. Using this combination pack will help you in your journey.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/which-one-is-better-green-tea-or-green-coffee</id>
    <published>2021-10-06T14:00:00+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-01-13T17:23:48+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/weight-loss/which-one-is-better-green-tea-or-green-coffee"/>
    <title>Which One Is Better : Green Tea or Green Coffee?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is believed that no magic pill or powder can make you lose fat. There are a small bunch of ingredients that may help support digestion and upgrade weight loss efforts. Your morning cup of Green Coffee or Green Tea may really help your weight reduction efforts.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> However, with regard to weight reduction, which one is to be favored from these two, <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/collections/green-coffee"><strong>Green Coffee</strong></a> or Green Tea? Both green tea and green coffee have their own benefits but which one is better especially when both are loved by fitness enthusiasts equally? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Green tea</strong> has its own space in the wellness world. It appears to have the majority of the spotlight, taking everything into account. It has antioxidant and calming properties, which make it very appealing!  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, lately another drink has pulled in much consideration as a healthy weight loss enhancing refreshment, which is green coffee. It is accepted to be truly viable in managing heart illnesses and diabetes alongside causing weight reduction. </span></p>
<h2><strong>What is Green Tea?</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Green tea is produced using the leaves, stem, and bud of the plant ‘Camellia sinensis’. It is frequently consumed as a drink. It isn’t matured like numerous teas, it is rather made by steaming fresh leaves at high temperatures. The steaming cycle improves the polyphenols in it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Polyphenols present in green tea help in forestalling inflammation and swelling in the body. It likewise has 2-4% of caffeine that makes it successful in boosting digestion and animating the sensory system, heart, and muscles by the arrival of synapses.</span></p>
<h2>
<span style="font-weight: 400;"></span><strong>What is Green Coffee?  </strong>
</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Customary green coffee is very much similar to the coffee produced using roasted coffee beans. Coffee beans are normally light earthy colored, dim earthy colored, red earthy colored, green or gray. They turn earthy brown-black to black because of the burning process. Since green coffee beans are not roasted, certain nutrients remain in it. Green coffee, for instance, contains substantially more phenols and terpenes (counting cafestol and kahweol) than roasted coffee.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, green coffee is essentially coffee made with unroasted coffee beans. If you pick coffee beans, they are typically dim green to brown-green in shading. Only after roasting the coffee beans they get their common brown-black to totally dark color and strong sweet-smelling scent.</span></p>
<h3><strong>How Green Coffee Helps In Weight Loss?</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Green espresso contains chlorogenic acid in a significant amount, which is believed to be liable for its weight loss effects. According to a study, it’s highly effective in burning fat fast.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">CHLOROGENIC ACID MIGHT PROMOTE FAT LOSS BY INCREASING THE ACTIVITY OF PPAR-Α WHICH IS A GENE INVOLVED WITH UNSATURATED FAT TRANSPORT AND OXIDATION AND DECREASE THE PRODUCTION OF NEW FAT CELLS THROUGH ITS ANTIOXIDANT EFFECTS.</span></p>
<p><strong>Green coffee acts as a catalyst in the oxidation of fat.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is rich in the antioxidant polyphenol, which helps in breaking down the fat and increases energy in the body.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">It helps release the fatty acids in the body.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">It improves metabolism.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">It improves mental clarity and concentration.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">It stimulates the absorption of fat in the liver.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Brings down blood pressure.</span></li>
</ul>
<h4><strong>The Verdict : Green Tea Or Green Coffee?</strong></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Both green coffee and green tea have some extraordinary health benefits. They improve general wellbeing and help burn fat. In any case, in light of recent researches, while discussing weight loss, green coffee is significantly more powerful as weight loss results show up quicker. It helps individuals getting fitter without crash diets.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yet again, the proof for weight loss with green coffee beans is marginally higher than green tea. Green tea offers various health advantages, yet its effects are seen much more slowly than the effect green coffee beans has on a person.</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Considering this, Green Coffee is certainly a better option.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<h3><strong>Why Neuherbs Green Coffee Beans Are Unique?</strong></h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pure and unroasted <strong><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/green-coffee-beans">Green Coffee Beans</a>.</strong><br></span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Green Coffee Beans Helps body remove toxins.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Green Coffee Beans Supports a healthy immune system.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Are without preservatives or gluten.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Boost metabolism for faster weight loss.</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Quicker results.</span></li>
</ul>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
