<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/women-health.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/women-health"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/women-health.atom"/>
  <title>Neuherbs - Women Health</title>
  <updated>2022-01-06T17:14:25+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Neuherbs</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/women-health/8-best-protein-items-to-include-in-your-diet-for-pcos</id>
    <published>2022-01-06T17:14:25+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-01-06T17:22:53+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/women-health/8-best-protein-items-to-include-in-your-diet-for-pcos"/>
    <title>8 Best Protein Items to Include in Your Diet for PCOS</title>
    <author>
      <name>Neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Having PCOS or polycystic ovary syndrome is overwhelming, and that is the harsh truth. Even though it is a common ailment, mental and physical exhaustion is too much for every woman. One woman out of 10 suffers from this disease, which is a hormonal imbalance.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you are one of the 10 women who suffer from PCOS, you need to pay attention to your diet. One of the best diets for women with PCOS is the protein diet PCOS. How does protein help with this illness? And what are the best proteins for PCOS? If you want answers to these questions, keep reading below and find out how to manage your symptoms with diet changes.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">Best protein for PCOS - How protein can help with PCOS?</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Protein keeps you full</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Women suffering from PCOS often complain of frequent hunger pangs. They also crave carbohydrates a lot, which can lead to weight gain. By including more protein in your diet, you can feel full and suppress hunger pangs. For instance, when you eat an omelet or oatmeal with fruits or a high-protein sandwich, you will be able to feel full till lunchtime. However, if you eat a burger or plain toast, you will have a craving for eating something junk.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>It boosts metabolism</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">PCOS is a hormonal condition affecting your metabolism, which is necessary for maintaining weight. When you eat the best proteins for PCOS, you fuel your body with things that can <strong>increase your metabolism</strong> rate and help you burn calories fast, sometimes even 100 a day.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Protein reduces cravings</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Cravings are a massive drawback of PCOS. With a protein-rich diet, you can counteract it as protein promotes the growth of glucagon, peptide YY, and cholecystokinin. All these hormones control satiety, thus, controlling cravings for foods that one has with PCOS.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Vegetarian protein may reduce your risk of ovulatory infertility</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">A study says that if you consume vegetarian sources of protein, like legumes, the risk of ovulatory infertility in women with PCOS may be reduced.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">Best proteins for PCOS - Foods to eat</h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Almonds</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Almonds are a great nut that provides you with 6g of protein per ounce. Start your day by eating a handful of almonds, raw or soaked overnight in water. You can even snack on them during the day or add them to your smoothies or more.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Leafy green vegetables</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="color: #3bbf4a;"><strong><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/diet-nutrition/10-vegetarian-foods-that-are-loaded-with-iron" style="color: #3bbf4a;">Leafy green vegetables</a></strong></span> are a good choice for everyone who wants to be healthy and lean. They are rich in protein, iron and Vitamin-B, and other minerals. Also, they are low in calories, making them a wondrous choice.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Leafy greens are the best proteins for PCOS as women suffering from this usually have Vitamin-B deficiency. Spinach &amp; Kale are the best things to include in your diet to fulfill this deficiency.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Greek yogurt</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Greek yogurt has 7g of protein per serving. It also has probiotics, which keep your gut healthy. Thus, it is one superfood you need to include in your diet, irrespective of having PCOS or not. You can eat it as it is or add fruit to it. Or you can make a smoothie using Greek yogurt and enjoy the yummy taste along with getting all the benefits.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Cottage cheese</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Each serving of cottage cheese has around 28g of protein, which is a lot. Thus, make sure your diet includes cottage cheese at least twice a week or more, if you like the taste. You can make a cottage cheese scramble or use it in your sandwich. Either way, it is delicious and one of the best proteins for PCOS.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Lentils</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">A cup of cooked lentils has 18g of proteins, and it is one of the best proteins for PCOS women who are vegan or vegetarian. There are several ways to consume legumes, and you can have them even for breakfast by making pancakes out of these lentils. These are savory pancakes that are too good, and adding tons of vegetables as fillings make them even healthier.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Oatmeal</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Oatmeal is a whole grain food item that has fiber and 11 grams worth of protein. Both are good for women suffering from PCOS as <span style="color: #3dc14c;"><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/super-food-mix" target="_blank" style="color: #3dc14c;" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>whole grain food</strong></a></span> items can keep your insulin level in check.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Shrimp</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Low in calories and rich in multiple nutrients, if you eat fish, shrimp is the best protein for the PCOS diet. It has 18 grams of protein. It is also rich in Vitamin B-12, which is also imperative for your body.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Chicken</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Chicken has 27g of proteins and other things you should add to your PCOS diet. Look up healthy chicken recipes to add to your diet as they are fulfilling and keep you lean too.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Protein and carbohydrates can help with insulin resistance and weight issues, managing these two can help you fight this disease better. However, when including the best proteins for PCOS, talk to your <span style="color: #3bbf4a;"><strong><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/neuherbs-health-consult" target="_blank" style="color: #3bbf4a;" rel="noopener noreferrer">doctor/dietitian</a></strong></span> before making any changes to your diet.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Diets do make a positive impact on women with PCOS. Though, it will take you some time to figure out a diet that suits your needs. Don’t give up on this fight, and never forget the best proteins for PCOS, which also helps your body stay lean and fit. It is a micronutrient that your body surely needs.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
