<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/tagged/lifestyle.atom"/>
  <title>Neuherbs - Lifestyle</title>
  <updated>2022-04-26T16:41:54+05:30</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Neuherbs</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/10-foods-to-have-before-going-to-bed</id>
    <published>2022-04-22T16:59:58+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-04-22T17:12:00+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/10-foods-to-have-before-going-to-bed"/>
    <title>10 Foods to Have Before Going to Bed</title>
    <author>
      <name>neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The majority of medical professionals advise against consuming heavy meals right before going to bed. Do late-night nibbles affect your ability to get a good night’s sleep? According to research, a person's ability to fall asleep depends entirely on the food consumed prior to going to bed.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Getting a good night's sleep is vital to your health and well-being. You can reduce your risk of facing any chronic illnesses by having a restful slumber daily. It also helps to strengthen your immune system as a whole.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">A lot of individuals find it challenging to acquire the 7 to 9 hours of unbroken sleep per night, as suggested by most experts. However, making changes in the diet can be helpful in getting a good night's sleep, as varying beverages and food items have sleep-enhancing characteristics.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;">10 Best Foods to Eat Before Going to Bed to Enjoy an Improved Slumber</h2>
<h3>1. Cherries</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Researchers recently discovered that opting to drink tart cherry juice increases melatonin levels, improving sleep efficiency and quality. Taking melatonin supplements has been demonstrated to improve circadian rhythms and alleviate sleeplessness.</p>
<h3>2. Kiwi</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Should we eat fruits at night? This natural sleep-inducing food will have you curled up under your cover in no time. A study published in the Asia Pacific Journal of Clinical Nutrition discovered that participants who ate two kiwifruits around 60 minutes before bedtime, every night, for 4 weeks, fell asleep 35% faster than those who didn't eat this fruit. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Additionally, it is a source of the mood-lifting hormone serotonin, found in abundance in this fruit due to its high antioxidant and carotenoid content. Low levels of this slumber hormone, associated with REM sleep (rapid eye movement), will lead to insomnia. As with kiwi, which is high in folate, one of the health problems related to a shortage in folate is sleeplessness.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">3. Almonds</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Almonds, cashews and peanuts are recommended as excellent night-time snacks. This is because of the high calcium content of almonds, which are a must-have in any flat-belly kitchen. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">This duo's combined efforts help soothe the body and ease muscle tension. When calcium is ingested, it helps the brain convert tryptophan into sleep-promoting melatonin. </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">4. Chamomile Tea</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As a herbal tea, Chamomile may have many health advantages. The flavones in it are well known. Many chronic diseases are brought on by inflammation, which the flavone family of antioxidants works on to eradicate them from your system. It has also been shown to enhance your immune system, reduce anxiety and sadness, and improve your skin's health. Another reason to give chamomile tea a try is its sleep-inducing properties.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Apigenin is specifically found in chamomile tea. This antioxidant attaches to receptors in your brain that may help you fall asleep and stay asleep more easily by increasing your drowsiness and decreasing your sleeplessness. Sleep problems are often linked to depression, and individuals who drink chamomile tea are likely to experience less of it. Having this beverage before going to bed can help get a better night's sleep, so give it a shot.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">5. Fatty Fish</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It is good to eat fatty seafood like salmon, tuna and trout. Vitamin D is what sets them apart from the rest. For instance, Sockeye salmon has 570 IU or international units of vitamin D in a  serving of 85 grams. That's 70% of your DV or daily value. 81% is the daily farmed rainbow trout intake recommended. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Additionally, fatty fish are rich in omega-3 fatty acids, such as DHA and EPA, which are beneficial for the human body. EPA and DHA's anti-inflammatory properties have long been recognized. There's also evidence that omega-3 fatty acids can assist in improving cognitive function, as well as preventing heart disease. Vitamin D and Omega-3 fatty acids additionally are known to augment sleep quality by increasing serotonin synthesis. Both of them are found in fatty fish. </p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">6. Walnuts</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Walnuts are kind of tree nuts that are widely consumed. A 28-gram serving of walnuts includes more than nineteen types of minerals and vitamins and approximately 1.9 grams of fibre. Manganese and copper are also found in abundance in walnuts.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Linoleic acid and omega-3 fatty acids which are found in high proportions in walnuts, make them an excellent source of fat. The 4.3 grams of protein in each ounce may also help to reduce hunger.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Walnuts help in improving cardiovascular health. Many studies have looked into their ability to reduce cholesterol, which is a major risk factor for heart disease. Walnut's fatty acid profile may also aid in the improvement of sleep quality. A host of foods items include omega-3 fatty acid alpha-linolenic acid (ALA), which is then processed by the body into DHA for brain and eye health. DHA may increase serotonin synthesis.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">However, if you have trouble falling asleep, try munching on a few walnuts before going to bed. About a quarter of a cup of walnuts is the ideal serving size.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">7. Cereal with Low-Fat Milk</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">As a night-time snack rather than breakfast, a combination of low-sugar cereal with skim milk is ideal. The sleep-inducing hormone serotonin is synthesised from the amino acid tryptophan, which is found in milk. On the contrary, whole milk with a higher fat content will take longer to digest, keeping you up instead of putting you to sleep. Hence, skim milk is preferable in such cases.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The time it takes to fall asleep can be reduced by half when you consume a high-glycemic carbohydrate such as jasmine rice (or rice cereal) 4 hours (240 minutes) before bed, as reported in the American Journal of Clinical Nutrition. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In other words, high-glycemic carbs can assist raise the ratio of tryptophan in your blood by diverting other amino acids to your muscles, which causes blood sugar and insulin to climb more quickly than with low-GI foods. You will be able to get more of the sedative into your brain since tryptophan is able to compete with the other amino acids for entry into your brain.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">8. Low-Fat Yoghurt Parfait</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Combine low-fat Greek yoghurt, honey and a banana for a tryptophan triple treat. Tryptophan is found in both yoghurt and bananas, and the carbs in the banana will aid in the absorption of the tryptophan-rich foods. Combine the yoghurt with some uncooked oats, which are an excellent source of tryptophan.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">9. Passionflower tea</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">How can a cup of tea not cure any ailment? At the very least, zero insomnia! Flavones, flavonoids and resins in many herbal teas have sedative properties. Flavone chrysin, which is a mild sedative and excellent anti-anxiety component, is present in passionflower tea. This helps you relax at night so you can get a good night's sleep.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;">10. Cottage Cheese</h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Your weight loss objectives may suffer if you completely forget about healthy late night <strong><a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/collections/diet-nutrition">snacks for weight loss</a></strong> before going to sleep. To avoid going to sleep with a full stomach, try some cottage cheese. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It contains the amino acid tryptophan as well as casein protein, a slow-releasing milk protein that helps curb night-time hunger pangs. To get an extra dose of tryptophan (the amino acid present in chickpeas), mix it with hummus or guacamole, or eat it on its own.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;">Other Sleep-Inducing Foods and Beverages </h4>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">A wide variety of additional foods and beverages have been shown to aid in the process of falling asleep. Additionally, you might add a couple of <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/true-vitamin"><strong>multivitamin supplements</strong></a> like <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/deep-sea-fish-oil"><strong>omega-3 fish oil capsules</strong></a> to meet your daily nutritional requirements. </li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">As already mentioned high levels of the amino acid, tryptophan helps to raise serotonin and melatonin, which essentially assists in the sleeping process. However, in certain circumstances, little research has been done on the exact effects of these substances on sleep patterns.  </li>
</ul>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;">Some of the other sources of Tryptophan are: </h4>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<strong>Bananas:</strong> Found in the banana peels, Tryptophan has a number of benefits. The fruit itself does have a certain extent of magnesium. Both of them can be beneficial in improving sleep quality.  </li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<strong>Oatmeal:</strong> The carbohydrate content of oatmeal is similar to rice, but it has higher fibre content and has been demonstrated to produce a level of sleepiness if consumed prior to bedtime. Certain evidence even suggests that oats contain tryptophan and melatonin, which aid with sleep. </li>
</ul>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">
<strong>Dairy products:</strong>  Items like plain yoghurt, milk and cottage cheese have Tryptophan. Milk, along with modest exercise, is known to be helpful in providing better sleep to older individuals.  </li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Conclusion: Final Thoughts!</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Treating your sleep issues starts with figuring out what's causing them in the first place. Stress, noise or discomfort may be causing you to not get a good night's rest. Keeping a sleep journal is a great way to evaluate your sleeping habits and identify areas for improvement. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">You must often wonder about what food to eat at night? Even if you don't get a good night's sleep, what you consume during the day can keep you up at night. If you eat meals rich in sleep-inducing vitamins, minerals and nutrients, you will have no trouble drifting off to sleep at night.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/green-coffee-v-s-green-tea-which-is-better-for-losing-weight</id>
    <published>2022-04-06T18:14:45+05:30</published>
    <updated>2022-04-06T18:14:45+05:30</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/lifestyle/green-coffee-v-s-green-tea-which-is-better-for-losing-weight"/>
    <title>Green Coffee V/S Green Tea: Which is Better for Losing Weight?</title>
    <author>
      <name>neuherbs Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Anyone looking to shed a few pounds knows that there is no magic powder or a diet that can help them lose weight. To lose those extra kilos, you have to be consistent with your diet and exercise. Still, you can take a few things to support your weight loss by increasing your metabolism. Everyone who is trying to lose weight has heard about the benefits of drinking green tea. It is full of antioxidants that keep our body healthy and support weight loss. When it comes to warm drinks supporting weight loss, everyone always looks up to green tea. Brewing the water and adding it to a bag or using green leaves to make this drink is immensely helpful in losing weight.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">However, recently, one more drink is gaining momentum for weight loss support, and that is green coffee. Green coffee beans are said to possess more antioxidants and properties that can aid us in accomplishing our weight loss goals. Green coffee is unroasted coffee beans with higher content of chlorogenic acid, which is imperative for us to lose weight or lower cholesterol levels.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The question that many people have in their mind is- whether to drink green tea or green coffee to lose extra kilos? Is green coffee for weight loss an effective strategy? To get answers to these questions, let’s compare the two of them below.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Your Guide to Green Coffee- </strong></h3>
<p class="sort-description" style="text-align: justify;">Coffee is an incredible drink. This drink is best whether you drink it warm or cold. However, the regular coffee that we drink is not in its natural form. The brown colour of coffee beans comes after processing the natural coffee beans. The unprocessed coffee beans are <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/green-coffee-beans"><strong>green coffee</strong></a> which has better taste, aroma, colour and is high in nutrients too. Since it is raw, it is high in chlorogenic acid, which has more nutrients than regular coffee.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Green Coffee helps with weight loss</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It promotes weight loss as it has chlorogenic acid, which helps burn fat and glucose. It even prevents blood sugar from spiking, which keeps fat in control. When you consume green coffee regularly, you increase your metabolic rate, which can help with fat loss.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Green Coffee may prevent cancer</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">High content of free radicals in our body can lead to multiple diseases, like cancer. Antioxidants can help reduce the damage that free radicals cause to your body. Green coffee is said to have a high number of antioxidants and nutrients. It can help prevent the growth of tumours in your body.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Green Coffee reduces inflammation</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Green coffee for PCOS is a great thing because inflammation is one of the reasons for PCOS. Green coffee has anti-inflammatory properties that can help lower the inflammation helping you reverse PCOS. Also, the anti-inflammatory properties of green coffee help lower cholesterol levels.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Also Read: <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/blogs/women-health/8-best-protein-items-to-include-in-your-diet-for-pcos">8 Best Protein Items to Include in Your Diet for PCOS </a></p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Green Coffee boosts mood and brain functions</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Since green coffee is rich in antioxidants, it can help with brain functions. Green coffee beans' benefits include enhancing cognitive performance &amp; psychomotor helping prevent Alzheimer’s disease. Caffeine helps release dopamine which helps uplift attention, mood, alertness, and other brain functions.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>How many cups of green coffee should you have?</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It is best to limit your intake of green coffee to two cups a day. Also, if you are drinking green tea and green coffee beans simultaneously, it is best to have one cup a day for each.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Green tea-Everything about this weight-loss support drink</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Green tea is a tea that uses Camellia Sinensis leaves and buds. It doesn’t undergo the same oxidation and withering process that oolong or black teas go through.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>It improves bone health</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Green tea can help improve your bone health by making your bones healthy and reducing your chances of osteoporosis.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>It can help oral health</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">When you drink green tea regularly, it can help with bad odour and improve oral hygiene. It has catechins that help improve the health of your mouth.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>It makes your heart healthy</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Heart issues are the leading cause of death. Thus, you need to take care of your diet and nutrition to make your heart healthy. Taking green tea is another way to make your heart healthy. Also, it can reduce the chances of stroke.</p>
<h4 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>It reduces inflammation</strong></h4>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Similar to green coffee, green tea has anti-inflammatory properties. Consuming it once a day can help reduce inflammation.</p>
<h5 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Types of green tea</strong></h5>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Green tea comes in multiple varieties, these three famous ones:</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">Sencha: The commonest green tea is Sencha, and it is also the most drinkable green tea. The leaves are steamed and rolled to create crude tea.</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">Matcha: Tencha, which is stone ground instantly before shipping is known as Matcha. You fully consume the leaves when you drink matcha. In Japan, people use matcha in savoury dishes as well.</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1">Hojicha: To make Hojicha, you roast sencha or other green teas. It has a distinctive aroma and is also less bitter than other types of green tea.</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Shincha: It is the ‘new tea’ of the season. It has low contents of caffeine and catechins, making it perfect for someone who doesn’t like strong green tea.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Which is better? Green tea or green coffee?</strong></h2>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Green coffee beans for weight loss or green tea? To answer this question, we will compare some points similar to both these drinks.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Caffeine content</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">It is the main point of comparison for both green tea and green coffee. The amount of caffeine in green coffee beans is 100 mg in a 250 ml cup of coffee. If you go green coffee capsule (supplements). The caffeine content is somewhere around 20-50 mg. Also, you can get green coffee that is decaf or has lower caffeine content. Just ensure that whichever you get, it is organic.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Green tea, on the other hand, has 35 mg of caffeine in the same cup. The caffeine content may differ based on the plant and the growing condition of the plant.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Verdict:</strong> If you need a higher boost of caffeine, green coffee is best. The caffeine will boost your mood, metabolism, and gain all the other green coffee beans benefits. However, for bedtime, always go with green tea or nothing with caffeine. Otherwise, your sleep patterns will suffer.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Their taste</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Apart from their properties, green tea and green coffee vary in their taste too. Green tea is bitter and has a strong taste. Even though it is bitter, people drink it worldwide for better health. Green coffee has a milder and more herbal flavour. There is no bitter aftertaste, and you will actually like its taste.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Verdict:</strong> If you don’t like the bitter aftertaste of green tea, you should go for green coffee. It is milder than even black coffee. And its benefits are numerous.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Brewing methods</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Your brewing methods should be perfect, so that you can enjoy several benefits of both green tea and green coffee. The brewing method for both of them is different. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Green tea:</em>  You can either get tea leaves, powder, or a bag. To brew it, boil water and add it to a cup with a bag, leaves or powder. (Do strain the leaves)</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><em>Green coffee:</em> If you have green coffee beans, grind them and add them to your cup. Pour hot water on it and mix it well. Alternatively, you can also use instant green coffee or green coffee powder.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Our verdict: Both are easy to brew, be it green coffee or green tea, choose any if brewing method is your preferred choice.</p>
<h3 style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Better for weight loss: Green Tea V/S Green Coffee</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align: justify;">If you look at the caffeine content, <a href="https://www.neuherbs.com/products/green-coffee-beans-powder"><strong>green coffee powder</strong></a> has a high content of the same. The antioxidants and anti-inflammatory properties of both these drinks make them ideal drinks for weight loss. Yet, research shows that green coffee beans/powder/instant coffee is better at aiding weight loss. Why? Due to the presence of chlorogenic acid in green coffee, which speeds up your weight loss goals without worrying about following fad diets. (Though, you do need to work out along with a balanced meal). </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><strong>Our verdict:</strong> If you want to speed up your weight loss journey, start drinking green coffee in the morning. Green coffee beans' benefits are more than just weight loss.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">That doesn’t mean that you cannot consume green tea. You can take green tea during the day or at night. Or even switch it up because it too helps the weight loss journey.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Wrapping up, start your day with a hot cup of coffee brewed using instant green coffee or green beans. You don’t need to add any milk to this drink, and it works perfectly to increase your metabolic rate. Thus, drinking it before working out gives you the energy to complete your workout better. Green coffee for PCOS or cholesterol control is also perfect as it helps you get rid of inflammation and toxins, which leads to these diseases. Along with consuming green coffee beans, lead a healthy lifestyle. Proper rest, diet, and sleep routine are essential for a healthy life and to keep the weight off forever.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
